<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118188916MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-29T11:29:03Z">
<doi>10.2118/188916-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/188916-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The Jasmine Field is commonly used to represent the Jasmine and Ban Yen Field. These are located within Block B5/27 in the Gulf of Thailand, approximately 300 km southeast of Bangkok, on the northwestern flank of the Tertiary Pattani Basin in water depths of is 190 to 200ft (Figure 1). The Jasmine field was discovered in 1974 by AMOCO and Idemitsu, and is currently 100% owned, and operated, by Mubadala Petroleum (Thailand) Ltd. The Jasmine Field complex consists of a large number of extensional and strike-slip fault blocks containing multiple sandstone reservoirs, largely having individual oil and gas water contacts.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>The Jasmine field is located in the Gulf of Thailand, approximately 300 km southeast of Bangkok city.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>The Jasmine field is located in the Gulf of Thailand, approximately 300 km southeast of Bangkok city.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The five platforms of the Jasmine field have produced a cumulative 65 million barrels oil at the end of 2016. Oil production comes from over 160 pools across 30 fault blocks and 30 separate reservoirs as shown in Figure 2; hydrocarbon columns are relatively short. Historically, most wells were clustered near the crest of the structural highs, but more recently unswept oil has been developed by wells targeting further downdip areas. A detailed history of the field is discussed by Oglesby et al. (2014).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>3D image illustrates oil and gas pools in the Jasmine Field. There are over 160 individual hydrocarbon pools.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>3D image illustrates oil and gas pools in the Jasmine Field. There are over 160 individual hydrocarbon pools.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Above this reservoir the Jasmine reservoirs are typically 20-80 ft thick and comprise a series of medium- to coarse-grained sandstones interbedded with mudstones. The reservoirs are interpreted to be fluvial dominated sands, with possible subsidiary lacustrine and deltaic (mouthbar/shoreface) influence. Seismic images particularly from the upper portion of the reservoir succession, record meandering channel patterns. Net to gross is generally high at 30-40 percent, and reservoirs are mostly high porosity 22-28 percent, and high permeability. Figure. 3 shows a type log from the Jasmine field.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Type log from the Jasmine field. Lower reservoirs of Middle Miocene age are separated from upper reservoirs of Late Miocene age by the Hot Shale</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Type log from the Jasmine field. Lower reservoirs of Middle Miocene age are separated from upper reservoirs of Late Miocene age by the Hot Shale</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">The BY31 horizontal well was proposed to develop the oil-bearing Y250 sandstone reservoir. The block has multiple oil-bearing reservoirs and was originally developed by only two deviated wells. Recent integrated evaluation suggested that at least two additional wells are required to further develop the oil reserves in the block. One of them is a horizontal well targeting the undeveloped oil in the Y250 reservoir as shown in Figure 4. Another proposed well is BY30, a deviated well targeting attic oil in the deeper Y245 reservoir that was not produced by the existing producers.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Top Y250 structure overlaid on Hydrocarbon Pore Volume (HCPV) thickness map in the fault block with existing and proposed wells. The BY31 horizontal well is proposed at the crest of Y250 structure. The BY30 proposed well targeting deeper Y245 reservoir sand is considered as a pilot hole for the proposed horizontal well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Top Y250 structure overlaid on Hydrocarbon Pore Volume (HCPV) thickness map in the fault block with existing and proposed wells. The BY31 horizontal well is proposed at the crest of Y250 structure. The BY30 proposed well targeting deeper Y245 reservoir sand is considered as a pilot hole for the proposed horizontal well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">The BY31 schematic well plan prior to drilling the BY30 pilot/producer well is shown in Figure 5a. The horizontal well path aimed to follow the top of the Y250 reservoir, not a true horizontal path. Adjustment to the well plan was then made based on the BY30 well data. The landing point was 25 ft deeper than the initial plan prior to BY30 pilot/producer well. Figure 5b illustrates the revised well plan after drilling BY30 well.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Cross section along proposed BY31 horizontal well path. The horizon and well plan prior to the BY30 pilot/producer well (5.a) and adjusted well plan post drilling BY30 well (5.b)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Cross section along proposed BY31 horizontal well path. The horizon and well plan prior to the BY30 pilot/producer well (5.a) and adjusted well plan post drilling BY30 well (5.b)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-5a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_5a.tif" id="ImgLink-5a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>The horizon and well plan prior to the BY30 pilot/producer well</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-5b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_5b.tif" id="ImgLink-5b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>adjusted well plan post drilling BY30 well</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The CE391 pilot well was proposed as an appraisal pilot to investigate the extent of an oil accumulation in the Y391 sandstone reservoir in this fault block. The Y391 oil accumulation was previously interpreted and has been produced only in the up dip part of the block. There is a strong stratigraphic control on the reservoir distribution as demonstrated by seismic attribute extraction and existing well data. Seismic mapping identified potential barriers between updip and the proposed downdip appraisal location as show in Figure 6.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188916MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188916MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Y391 seismic attribute map with depth contour. The proven accumulation is in the up dip part. The pressure derived oil water contact fall beyond structural spill point. The larger reservoir down dip is apparently isolated from the up dip oil accumulation. The CE391 pilot appraisal well was intended to test the down dip area.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Y391 seismic attribute map with depth contour. The proven accumulation is in the up dip part. The pressure derived oil water contact fall beyond structural spill point. The larger reservoir down dip is apparently isolated from the up dip oil accumulation. The CE391 pilot appraisal well was intended to test the down dip area.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>