<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118192039MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-30T15:04:51Z">
<doi>10.2118/192039-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/192039-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docTableList>
<docTable pdf-page="16" table-order="1" data-type-order="20">
<table-wrap id="102118192039MS-tblwrp-1" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">As a jetting fluid, acid can be used for limestone formation (Cinelli et al. 2013). Extensive study of the RD hydraulics has been done to establish optimum RD design (Wang et al. 2016). It is advised that petrophysical studies, rock mechanics test, fluid compatibility test prior to the intervention is required (Bruni et al. 2007). From a desktop research, technology maturity and applicability to the Kita-Akita field is summarized in Table 1.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 1</label>
<caption>Rd Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Rd Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118192039MS-Tbl_SPi-1" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center"><u>MATURITY</u></th>
<th valign="top" align="center">
<u>APPLICABILITY</u>
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•More than 1,800 case performed in world wide</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Service unit can be shipped in low cost to Japan.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Many paper publication found.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Fast and cost effective method. Ability to drill up to 8 lateral in two days.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Multi-lateral placement possible.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Accessible to thin sand reservoir in efficient manner.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•No track record in horizontal lateral placement.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Jetting capability in heterogeneous sand/ shale contrast.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•No angular lateral (45 deg) deployment is not tried in a field before.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Fluid sensitivity issue in clay rich formation.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Hose burst could be happened in tight reservoir.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Lateral bore stability during drilling and production.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•No liner installation and surveillance option in the lateral.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
<docTable pdf-page="20" table-order="2" data-type-order="27">
<table-wrap id="102118192039MS-tblwrp-2" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">A few successful installation and performance were reported in the literature (Torvund, 2016) yet, entire track record is not enough therefore it is still recognized as a relatively new technology. Table 2 summarize a desktop research summary from maturity and applicability perspectives.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 2</label>
<caption>Fishbone Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fishbone Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118192039MS-Tbl_SPi-2" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center">
<u>MATURITY</u>
</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">
<u>APPLICABILITY</u>
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Case of fishbone acid jetting in limestone formation is increasing.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Service unit can be shipped in low cost to Japan. <br /> •This sand reservoir in sheet type may work. <br /> •Fast and cost effective method. Ability to drill a needle for a short time.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Fishbone drilling case in sandstone reservoir is not many <br /> •Track record of sand stone case is not enough.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Lateral bore stability during drilling and production is necessary. <br /> •Needle length (35.4 ft. or 10 m) may not be enough to stimulate entire thickness in Kita-Akita reservoir <br /> •Formation damage and potential skin increase.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
<docTable pdf-page="23" table-order="3" data-type-order="33">
<table-wrap id="102118192039MS-tblwrp-3" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">In the literature, conventional hydraulic fracture treatments have had a marginal effect in mature lenticular reservoir (Precupanu et al., 2017). Predicting fracture height growth and the associated pay coverage by securing high conductive proppant placement is essential. From a desktop research, technology maturity and applicability to the Kita-Akita field for hydraulic fracturing is summarized in Table 3.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 3</label>
<caption>Fracturing Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fracturing Technology Maturity And Applicability On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118192039MS-Tbl_SPi-3" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center">
<u>MATURITY</u>
</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">
<u>APPLICABILITY</u>
</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Pros</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Fracturing is widely used for tight reservoir development. <br /> •Many paper publication found in the literature. <br /> •Feedback from unconventional play is applied and open subcommercial zone in conventional play.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•The past producers were completed in fracturing treatment.<br /> •In this layered sandstone reservoir, fracturing offers brute way to access the heterogeneously distributed matrix..</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">
<b>
<u>Cons</u>
</b>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Conventional fracturing may not work in heterogeneous lenticular reservoir <br /> •Diagnostic methodology is still not well established. <br /> •High surface pressure is generally required thus surface foot-print required. <br /> •Some envirionmental and regulation issue exists.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">•Frac related cost is high in Japan due to less activity and importing frac fleets from overseas. <br /> •Height control issue in less barrier environment.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
<docTable pdf-page="24" table-order="4" data-type-order="35">
<table-wrap id="102118192039MS-tblwrp-4" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Using that information, we firstly looked back the past treated hydraulic fracturing job in created 1D MEM based on goemchanical properties taken by the pilot-hole program. Fig. 31 illustrates fracture propagation result after closure. Since the job size in 1960s were much smaller proppant volume than today (Table 4), dimensionless conductivity was calculated almost zero. It is expected that a larger volume fracturing jobs would enhance well performance under the current sitation.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 4</label>
<caption>Fracturing Job Design</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fracturing Job Design</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118192039MS-Tbl_SPi-4" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center">Item</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">1957-1959</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">SCREENTNG</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">UNIT</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Pad volume</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">5.1</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">20.0</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">m3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Main fluid volume</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">26.9</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">156.9</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">m3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Flush volume</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">4.7 (vertical)</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">19.5 (horizontal)</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">m3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Pump rate</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">10.2</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">15.0</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">bpm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Proppant volume</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">3.5</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">68</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">ton</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
<docTable pdf-page="29" table-order="5" data-type-order="44">
<table-wrap id="102118192039MS-tblwrp-5" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Final screening summary is summarized in Fig. 39 and Table 5. Each maturity, applicability, productivity, and economics are normalized based on cased and perforated vertical well performance. In the study, multistage hydraulic fracturing treatment is still the most brute way to maximize a contact area and improve recovery, however, fracturing treatment cost worsen the economics.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 5</label>
<caption>Summary Of Screening Results On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Summary Of Screening Results On The Basis Of Score Matrix</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118192039MS-Tbl_SPi-5" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center">CHANNEL RESERVOIR</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">SHEET RESERVOIR</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="center">Maturity of the technology (color)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• Track record of fishbone drilling is not many.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• CT drilling is area specific. Need more learning curve.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• Deviated well drilling, perforation and hydraulic fracturing is mature technologies. Still room of imporivement.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• Radial drilling track records is sufficient for an operation.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="center">Applicabiilty into Kita-Akita field (babble size)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• Deviated well works in thin sand reservoir to mixmize reservoir contact. Perforating method should be optimized.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• The past record of hydraulic fracturing in vertical well shows fracturing is favorable.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• Multi-stage fracturing job cost is highest. Need to improve a design.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• CT drilling unit availability in acceptable price is difficult. For successful job, one infill drilling plan is not enough.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="left">• MST type completion (radial drilling and fishbone) may work but core testing, fluid compatibility test, well stability analysis during drilling and production is required.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2" valign="top" align="center">Productivity (x-axis) &amp; Economics (y-axis)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Fracturing, MST type completion, deviated well performance is better than cased and perforated vertical well.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Large variation found in sheet reservoir (The plog more scattaced).</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Production performance in Fishbone and 5 stage fractured horizontal well competes but fishbone is attractive in cost wise.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Horizontal well along with a specific zone underperform in cased hole condition, while deviated well works with penetrating all layers. However, the performance was vice versa in open hole condtion</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td rowspan="3" valign="top" align="left">• Dual RD system gives decent productivity and economics in vertical well type.</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">• 5 stage fracturing in horizontal well outperform but not cost-effective.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Dual RD system gives decent productivity and economics.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="left">• Fishbone in deviated well may be good options.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
</docTableList>
</docTables>