<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190341MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T18:58:02Z">
<doi>10.2118/190341-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190341-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The A West field is located on the Eastern Flank of the South Oman Salt Basin, 30 km south-south-west of the Nimr fields Figure 1. The field was discovered in 1972 with an initial reservoir pressure of 12,100 kPa and an initial reservoir temperature of 57°C. The heavy 180 – 2000cP oil is contained in a dome shaped unconformity trap with STOIIP ranging from 72 mln m3 to 130 mln m3. The oil column from 800 m tvdss to 1005m tvdss with a maximum thickness of 205m is present in the "main area" of the A West field with a common OOWC at 1004 mtvdss in the Haradh formation and the overlying, northerly dipping Amin and Mahwis formations. The net average porosity is 25%, and horizontal permeability varies from 10 – 4500 md, average 845 md.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Map view and geological cross section of "A" West and "A" East</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Map view and geological cross section of "A" West and "A" East</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">The Vertical Steam Drive (VSD) thermal EOR concept selected for the A West Field assumes an initial Vertical Steam Drive (VSD) process that will evolve over time into a Steam-oil Gravity Drainage process Figure 2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>The main development concept is Vertical Steam Drive (left) followed by Steam Oil Gravity Drainage (right).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>The main development concept is Vertical Steam Drive (left) followed by Steam Oil Gravity Drainage (right).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-2a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_2a.tif" id="ImgLink-2a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>left</caption-order>
<caption-text>Vertical Steam Drive</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-2b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_2b.tif" id="ImgLink-2b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>right</caption-order>
<caption-text>followed by Steam Oil Gravity Drainage</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">The execution of the trial involved drilling two new steam injectors in two locations within the 3.3 acre development. Each steam injector is positioned 42 m from 3 existing producers (from 3.3 acre development) to configure 1.1 acre inverted 4-spots patterns in two different locations with no additional facilities Figure 3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Steam Flood pattern configuration. 3.3 acre vs 1.1 acre.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Steam Flood pattern configuration. 3.3 acre vs 1.1 acre.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="4" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Interpretation of the tracer concentrations over time Figure 4 allows for identification of the "time of flight" of the tracer from injector to producer (simulation model calibration data), as well as indications of the dispersion of the tracer within the reservoir (from the "tail" of the concentration over time) which relates to the connectivity/sweep through the reservoir. The profile of the tracer concentration can also be used to estimate:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Tracer concentration changes over time, sampled at single well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Tracer concentration changes over time, sampled at single well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The completion strategy for the 1.1 acre trial wells has been aligned with the completion strategy applied in the 3.3 acre development to minimize changes and maximize the value of information. The producers have been perforated 15 m below the reservoir top and extended to 50 m above the oil water contact. The steam injectors perforation interval has been aligned with the producers with the steam injectors relatively 5-10 m deeper to avoid immediate steam breakthrough Figure 5. The oil producers are completed with 3.5″tubing insert pump and set at mid perforation with a tail pipe extended to the bottom perforation. DTS fiber optic cable is attached to the tubing to allow for continuous temperature surveillance for Haradh formation during production and injection. The injection wells are completed with 4.5″ VIT tubing and permanent thermal packer with two expansion joints.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Well perforation strategy</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well perforation strategy</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Down hole Venturi nozzle yields a minimum pressure drop in order to achieve the critical flow Figure 6. It is expected to provide 90% pressure recovery to achieve the critical flow compared to the standard straight-bore nozzle with 50-60% pressure recovery. Under critical flow conditions, mass and heat injection are independent to the downstream (reservoir) pressure.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Critical flow &amp; Pressure Requirement</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Critical flow &amp; Pressure Requirement</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="7" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">In this paper, the wellbore schematic is presented in Figure 7, where the Venturi nozzles are modeled and engineered by the tool supplier. Nozzle sizes depend on the reservoir pressure across the zone, steam injection pressure, steam injection quality and steam injection rate target for each zone. In this case, a total 400 te/d steam injection was modeled for 50-50% split across the upper and lower interval at the design injection pressure and reservoir pressure.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well Schematic with Venturi Nozzle Completion</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well Schematic with Venturi Nozzle Completion</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="8" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">The permanent real-time DTS profiles in the producers also show temperature anomalies during injection and production. Similar to the initial static temperature surveys the observed subsurface temperature response during injection and production shows that temperature is mainly concentrated at the top part of the reservoir. During the production, temperature profile is observed to expand downwards to the bottom of the well. However during the period of pump downtime, the temperature profile shows that the main heat source is mainly the top perforation interval Figure 8. The results from the krypton survey conducted in one of the steam injectors shows that the majority of steam is injected in the top 20 m of the perforated zone with minimum injection towards the bottom parts.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190341MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190341MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Real time DTS surveillance</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Real time DTS surveillance</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>