<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190419MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-27T12:51:31Z">
<doi>10.2118/190419-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190419-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The "A" West and East Fields are located in the south of the Sultanate of Oman (Figure 1). Thick, high net-to-gross sandstones belonging to the Haima Group form the main reservoir unit. "A" West Field and East are separated by a deeply incised paleo-valley infilled with lithologically heterogeneous glacial sediments belonging to the Al Khlata Formation. The targeted Haima oil is heavy, with viscosities increasing with depth, and reaching up to 400,000 cP close to the Oil Water Contact at "A" East Field.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>"A" Field Location Map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>"A" Field Location Map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">In order to monitor and manage the thermal injection and production processes a significant number of surveillance techniques and metering applications are employed, at well, reservoir and field level. On an annual basis the Asset's decision-based surveillance plan is reviewed, challenged and updated as required (see Figure 2). The execution of this plan, together with the Field's ongoing reservoir performance data translates to a very significant amount of diverse information being acquired on a daily basis. A combination of highly visual tools and innovative processes are employed within the cross-discipline work environment to facilitate effective management and analysis of this data. The Asset recognises this as an area key to success.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Decision Based Approach for Surveillance Planning</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Decision Based Approach for Surveillance Planning</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">The wells were set up with solar-powered wireless data transmission from the wellhead to a server/data storage bank at the Field Control Centre. From here the data is transferred to the team's geophysical contractor in Canada for signal processing. Daily reports are transmitted back to key staff in PDO for review/action, and automated alarms are triggered when signal characteristics exceed pre-defined operating envelopes. As with the daily reports, these are communicated by auto-generated emails. The acquisition system can be accessed at any time from office to check the network integrity and data streaming. This system has now been operational since Q1 2017, with excellent system uptime achieved to date. A summary of the project execution, from Risk Assessment through to Operation and Analysis, is shown in Figure 3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>"A" Field Micro Seismic, from Risk Assessment to Operation and Analysis</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>"A" Field Micro Seismic, from Risk Assessment to Operation and Analysis</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">NIBRAS is a powerful corporate production surveillance platform, developed in-house by PDO (see Figure 4). Some 98% of the company's well stock are monitored and analysed by this system (its success is reflected by recent backing from the PDO Board to commercialise it, adding value for PDO and the Sultanate of Oman). Some strengths of NIBRAS are the following:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Petroleum Development Oman's NIBRAS Tool</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Petroleum Development Oman's NIBRAS Tool</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">In addition to NIBRAS, the Asset utilizes a commercially available visualization platform to improve efficiency of field, pattern and well reviews, which play a crucial role in effective WRFM. Preparation for these events can be very time consuming. In "A" Field the platform has therefore been set up with diagnostic plots/map templates, populated with the latest data (see Figure 5). In addition to the time-saving aspect, this also creates consistency, and anomalous production behavior can be readily identified. One strength is the platform's ability to handle large amounts of data. It calls upon PDO's corporate databases, such that the input has been quality controlled, and is current. The flexible mapping and bubble plotting provide rapid insights into key aspects of current and historical production. The platform's forecasting capabilities are being used at "A" Field to reduce cycle time in business planning, short-term production forecasting, and reserves estimates.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Use of commercially available software to facilitate Well and Reservoir reviews</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Use of commercially available software to facilitate Well and Reservoir reviews</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Another tool vital for data integration and visualization is the full field, full stratigraphy live subsurface model built within the asset (see Figure 6). This was developed from 2015 onwards, following interpretation of a regional Wide Azimuth 3D seismic data volume, together with insights from a thorough analysis of a diverse range of supporting data. Corporate reference projects, linked to the PDO databases allow rapid updating of the project to reflect the latest data, which is integrated with the current seismic interpretation, plus geological and production insights. Automated workflows facilitate quick and easy model updates, highlighting opportunities and continuously reducing uncertainty. Business Impact is being realized across many areas, for example:-</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>"A" Field's Full Stratigraphy, Full Field Model</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>"A" Field's Full Stratigraphy, Full Field Model</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Data gathering can be costly; the Asset therefore attaches high importance to ensuring that acquisition is on a "need to have" basis, and it must be demonstrated that the data will add (or safeguard) sufficient value to justify the expense. Moreover, once the data is acquired, value erosion can still occur if the data is poorly managed and/or under-utilised. In this respect, the automation, data integration, manipulation and visualization tools described in earlier sections offer excellent return on investment. BLADE for example involved a low capital outlay, but has been estimated to save 20% man-power (see Figure 7). In "A" West Field BLADE implementation resulted in a 35% increase in oil rate. In terms of value it is clear that the payback time for such an initiative is very short.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190419MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190419MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Bottom Line Impact of BLADE Implementation (after Alwazeer et al. 2017)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Bottom Line Impact of BLADE Implementation (after <link href="BIB1">Alwazeer et al. 2017</link>)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="bib">
<bib id="BIB1">
<label>Alwazeer et al., 2017</label>
<author>
<first-name>A.</first-name>
<last-name>Alwazeer</last-name>
</author>, <author>
<first-name>L.</first-name>
<last-name>Vargas Rojas</last-name>
</author>, <author>
<first-name>A.</first-name>
<last-name>Andrade Marin</last-name>
</author> et al. <pubDate>2017</pubDate>. <article-title>Self Optimizing Thermal Field Using Beam Pumps with Variable Speed Drive. SPE-KSA Annual Technical Symposium &amp; Exhibition (ATS&amp;E), Dammam, Saudi Arabia, 25-27 April </article-title>. SPE-KSA-9008.</bib>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>