<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118189283STU.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T16:50:36Z">
<doi>10.2118/189283-STU</doi>
<pii>10.2118/189283-STU</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The team planned to implement a pilot waterflood program consisting of nine producers and four injectors arranged in an inverted 5-spot, 40-acre pattern (Figure 1). Seven of the nine producers were already producing from the Clearfork. As for the other two, one would be recompleted from the Fusselman formation, and the other would be re-drilled. The four injectors would be new drills. The main reason for not converting existing wells to injectors was because many of the existing producers had perforations in the Tubb, Clearfork, and Glorieta. This caused concern regarding efficiency.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Pilot Pattern (a): Drill four injectors followed by one central producer at a later time Expansion (b): Eventually cover entire structural high with 40-acre waterflood pattern, drilling injectors</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pilot Pattern (a): Drill four injectors followed by one central producer at a later time Expansion (b): Eventually cover entire structural high with 40-acre waterflood pattern, drilling injectors</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-1a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_1a.tif" id="ImgLink-1a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Drill four injectors followed by one central producer at a later time Expansion</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-1b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_1b.tif" id="ImgLink-1b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Eventually cover entire structural high with 40-acre waterflood pattern, drilling injectors</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">First, a static model of the Winkler County area was created by the team geologist. It modeled every horizon between the Glorieta and Tubb formations. Figure 2 displays the structure of the Clearfork, which lies between the aforementioned horizons. Outlined in black is the Winkler County Lease which encompasses a North-South oriented anticline composed of dolomitized carbonates that were deposited in a shallow water environment. The porosity and permeability are approximately 5% and 5 md, respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Clearfork structure map of the Winkler County Lease area</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Clearfork structure map of the Winkler County Lease area</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">The greatest challenge in history matching was the vast amount of uncertainty that surrounded almost every aspect of the model. This uncertainty was grouped into two categories: geologic, as in pertaining to the static model, and reservoir, or pertaining to the dynamic model. A selection of the key uncertainties and assumptions made can be found in Figure 3. The root of uncertainty was lack of data.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Key uncertainties and assumptions made in initial history matching; yellow represents the uncertainties associated with the static model while the light brown represents those associated with the dynamic model</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Key uncertainties and assumptions made in initial history matching; yellow represents the uncertainties associated with the static model while the light brown represents those associated with the dynamic model</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">One of the history matching parameters was relative permeability. Figure 4 shows cumulative oil production as a function of time for several different cases of relative permeability. It demonstrates that one small tweak can have a significant impact on the final result.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Sensitivity of oil production to relative permeability</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sensitivity of oil production to relative permeability</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">This caused the wells to not be able to produce the total liquid rate; the wells simply were not connected to enough of the reservoir to match historical production. Some team members visited the core warehouse with a geologist to look at core from a well within the lease (Figure 5). It was obvious to everyone that there was significantly less than 30 percent anhydrite; in addition, the anhydrite did not form laminations that would prevent vertical movement of reservoir fluids.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Clearfork core from a well within the Winkler County lease</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Clearfork core from a well within the Winkler County lease</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">With these changes to the static model, the history matching process improved drastically. A final history match was obtained shortly thereafter and is shown in Figure 6. This verified the model under the assumption that once the model behaves in a way consistent with history, it will behave like the actual wells in the future. With an acceptable history match, the last step of the simulation workflow involved estimating the reservoir response to the pilot waterflood.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>History match of the current pilot waterflood program Clearfork producers</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>History match of the current pilot waterflood program Clearfork producers</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">A dimensionless plot of hydrocarbon pore volume and secondary incremental recovery (Figure 7) was used to generate a production forecast based on the analog. Using the refined OOIP and expected water injection, one can predict reservoir response based on the analog field’s response to the same proportion of injection. As in the simulation model, a total water injection rate of 2,000 BWPD was assumed (500 BWPD/well).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Curve fit to the dimensionless analog field data</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Curve fit to the dimensionless analog field data</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">This value was established based on the guaranteed water supply. The pressure of each producing well was examined at the end of the historical case, and a unique bottomhole pressure constraint was established that aimed to smooth the transition between the historical and predictive cases. With the constraints established, the Clearfork’s response to water injection was estimated. The results are displayed in Figure 8. Future work may involve varying the water injection rate and improving conformance within the model.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Oil production forecast over time for the Winkler County Lease</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil production forecast over time for the Winkler County Lease</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">When these cases were run together in an economics software, the project was found to have a $51 breakeven oil price at a 10% discount rate. Like most oil and gas projects, the economic viability is highly sensitive to oil price (Figure 9). At $60 oil, the project has a present value of $1.3 MM.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189283STU-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189283STU_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Rate of return as a function of oil price</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Rate of return as a function of oil price</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>