<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118192047MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-30T12:29:14Z">
<doi>10.2118/192047-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/192047-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">From all formations of Phisanulok basin stratigraphy (Figure 1), two formations are defined as tight reservoirs. The first is deltaic-lacustrine reservoirs of the Lan Krabu (LKU) formation. This formation is thin-bedded reservoirs with high heterogeneity and structural compartmentalization. The tight targets are found in all sub-reservoir members depending on depth and location. The second is the alluvio-lacustrine reservoirs of the Sarabop formation, which is the alluvio-lacustrine reservoirs. This formation is the interbedded silty-sandstone with poorly sorted and high heterogeneity. This formation is the early sedimentation event of Phitsanulok basin that has lower degree of structural compartmentalization when compared with the LKU formation. In general, both targets are the focused areas of hydraulic fracturing campaigns.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Phisanulok basin schematic Tertiary chronostratigraphy</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Phisanulok basin schematic Tertiary chronostratigraphy</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Hydraulic fracturing was implimented for the first time in Sirikit oilfield more than a decade ago. Additional pilot wells have been continually performed ever since. The stimulated wells are mostly deviated which were typically completed with 2 7/8" tubing in 7" casing to put on production. The latest pilot HFA campaign was executed at two wells which are deviated and horizontal wells drilled through the LKU formations. There are seven stages of hydraulic fracturing: two stages in LZ-1 deviated well and five stages in LX-1 horizontal well (Figure 2). Six stages were successfully accomplished, while the first stage of LZ-1 had encountered premature screen-out due to equipment malfunction.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Well and hydraulic fracturing schematic at LZ-1 and LX-1</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well and hydraulic fracturing schematic at LZ-1 and LX-1</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-2a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_2a.tif" id="ImgLink-2a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LZ-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-2b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_2b.tif" id="ImgLink-2b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Field-scale implementation of hydraulic fracturing will be continued in the areas where production gain was proven to deliver positive economic value. These areas (Figure 3) usually equip with strong subsurface model. More infill development wells are continuously being drilled and dedicated for hydraulic fracturing in tight reservoirs. The information gathered from actual pumping operation and production analysis from former pilot campaigns is used to improve the understanding of subsurface quality and expected hydraulic fracture geometry.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Structural map (left) and reservoir thickness map (right) in the proven area with several drilled wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Structural map (left) and reservoir thickness map (right) in the proven area with several drilled wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order> (left)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Structural map</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(right)</caption-order>
<caption-text>reservoir thickness map</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Tight reservoir targets exist throughout the Sirikit oilfield, thus the feasibility of hydraulic fracturing technique and its suitability with area-specific subsurface conditions need to be proven. The work scope generally follows Figure 4.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>General hydraulic fracturing work scope in the unproven areas (Pilot project)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>General hydraulic fracturing work scope in the unproven areas (Pilot project)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">Following the workflow in Figure 5, existing well selection starts with basic criteria. For instance, existing well completion shoud ease the workover and well integrity should withstand hydraulic fracturing operation. In terms of subsurface structure, the accepted wells should not be near water-bearing layer and should have sufficient net thickness in tight reservoir targets, otherwise they may be dropped.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Existing well review for hydraulic fracturing candidates</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Existing well review for hydraulic fracturing candidates</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">In the proven areas, the experienced hydraulic-fractured formations are the attentive targets where the reservoir depths are averagely 2,200 meters below the mean sea level, see Figure 6. Additionally, the HFB campaign aimed to also perform hydraulic fracturing in the unproven areas and formations. For LB-1, the Sarabop formation was focused in this campaign and it has the relatively shallower hydraulic fracturing target depth than in the proven area. In addition, TE-1 well was targeted to perform hydraulic fracturing in the untested sublayers of LKU formations, which are the deepest targets in this campaign.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Campaign B hydraulic fracturing target depths and formations</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Campaign B hydraulic fracturing target depths and formations</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="7" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">The detailed study revealed that when considered in relative to those connected with other concepts, utilization of "plug-and-perforation technique on the cemented production casing (7") with retrievable fracturing string and packer as depicted in Figure 7, tends to concern lower associated costs; less special tools and contractor service packages required; shorter time spent on well drilling; no major modification to the conventional well design in the field; and less tendency to long non-productive-time (NPT) caused by operational difficulties. Thus, it was selected as a primary configuration for the campaign. In this configuration, once a bridge plug has been set and the target has been perforated by wireline runs, pumping job is conducted through four-inch-diameter drill pipe, as a frac string, during the treatment.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well Configuration based on the multistage hydraulic fracturing technique employed campaign HFB.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well Configuration based on the multistage hydraulic fracturing technique employed campaign HFB.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="8" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">In this configuration, once a bridge plug has been set and the target has been perforated by wireline runs, pumping job is conducted through four-inch-diameter drill pipe, as a frac string, during the treatment. When completing all stages, all plugs are drilled out and completed with production string. Depending on its plan, the supporting rig either skid to the next well, or rig down and move to the next location (Figure 8), to perform the hydraulic fracturing on the next candidate until completion of the campaign.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Conceptual operation sequence cycle on candidate wells for hydraulic fracturing in campaign HFB</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Conceptual operation sequence cycle on candidate wells for hydraulic fracturing in campaign HFB</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="9" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">The process adopted in the implementation of hydraulic fracturing in the campaign HFB is presented in four major phases depicted in Figure 9. The dataset of critical information connected with geomechanics, subsurface characteristics and reservoir flow and rock property data acquired from various sources along with the well information summarized in Table 3. They were the primary set used for the design phase as well as other subsequent technical and engineering considerations along the process. These data, after being processed or additionally collected when needed, fracture stimulation treatment were engineered in different aspects (Table 4).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Hydraulic Fracturing Work Process Implemented in the Campaign</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Hydraulic Fracturing Work Process Implemented in the Campaign</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="10" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">For each fracturing candidate well, a geomechanics profile was constructed by extracting subsurface attributes corresponding to the targets from the 3D Mechanical Earth Model (3D MEM). Fracture propagation and geometry prediction were simulated based on the Pseudo-3D fracture growth model and the performance prediction for each design scenario was evaluated in pursuing the optimum options. This has been described in Figure 10.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Approach in treatment design and optimization process, and the subsequent calibration illustrated for the hydraulic fracturing campaign in the case study.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Approach in treatment design and optimization process, and the subsequent calibration illustrated for the hydraulic fracturing campaign in the case study.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="11" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">In addition to the subsurface constraint, the factors potentially detrimental to the operation on the well itself such as poor integrity, and in case of existing well candidates, the presences of existing perforation. The temperature logs which were applied after the first stage pumping job on LZ-2 to verify the zonal isolation capability on the doubtful cement quality prior to proceed with the second stage (Figure 11) is one of the examples. Extended minifrac were exercised on the well concerning fault proximity. Additional features which may enhance the detectability of the issues being suspected were added to the program</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Fracture measurement utilizing the technique based on temperature distribution which was applied to evaluate possible integrity issue due to the doubtful cement in between the stages shown after the pumping job of the first stage prior to making judgement on the plan for the 2nd stage. This was done as part of the risk assessment and management protocol</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fracture measurement utilizing the technique based on temperature distribution which was applied to evaluate possible integrity issue due to the doubtful cement in between the stages shown after the pumping job of the first stage prior to making judgement on the plan for the 2nd stage. This was done as part of the risk assessment and management protocol</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="12" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">In preparation for the campign, some of other key aspects to be considered include transportation, water sources and supply, equipment layout, site and road survey, safety regulation, waste management, and potential concerns to the environment and community. Baseline assessments were conducted before the the oprearion. Operating time window was set to avoid the impact on local community. Sound barriers were installed at the site and noise level wemeasured regularly in the site and the surrounding areas (Figure 12).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Sound Measurement at the wellsite and in the surrounding areas during normal operation and during pumping the fracture treatment.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sound Measurement at the wellsite and in the surrounding areas during normal operation and during pumping the fracture treatment.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="16" pdf-page="14" figure-order="13" data-type-order="17">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">The fluid injections were regulated at 20 bpm where the pump time varied from 50 to 110 minutes per stage depending upon the size of the job. The maximum proppant concentration was up to seven ppa. Hydraulic fracturing jobs on all eleven stages on nine wells in the proven areas have been executed with no screenout, all the new wells achieved 100% pumping volume as planned. In unproven area, one experienced premature screenout. The other was terminated earlier than planned due to the indication of potential screenout risk when around 90% of proppant had been placed. Data recorded for the fracture treatment jobs are given in Figure 13.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>The example of hydraulic fracture treatment on each stagem that is, LZ-2-1, LZ-3-1, LZ-3-2, LZ-4-1, LY-1-1, LX-2-1, LX-3-1, LX-3-2, LX-4-1, LX-4-2, LT-1-1, LT-2-1, LT-2-2, LB-1-1, TE-1-1, and TE-1-2 is indicated in the curves, from (a), (b), (c), and (p), in a consecutive order.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>The example of hydraulic fracture treatment on each stagem that is, LZ-2-1, LZ-3-1, LZ-3-2, LZ-4-1, LY-1-1, LX-2-1, LX-3-1, LX-3-2, LX-4-1, LX-4-2, LT-1-1, LT-2-1, LT-2-2, LB-1-1, TE-1-1, and TE-1-2 is indicated in the curves, from (a), (b), (c), and (p), in a consecutive order.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13a.tif" id="ImgLink-13a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LZ-2-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13b.tif" id="ImgLink-13b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LZ-3-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13c.tif" id="ImgLink-13c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LZ-3-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13d">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13d.tif" id="ImgLink-13d" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LZ-4-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13e">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13e.tif" id="ImgLink-13e" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LY-1-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13f">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13f.tif" id="ImgLink-13f" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-2-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13g">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13g.tif" id="ImgLink-13g" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-3-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13h">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13h.tif" id="ImgLink-13h" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-3-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13i">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13i.tif" id="ImgLink-13i" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-4-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13j">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13j.tif" id="ImgLink-13j" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LX-4-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13k">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13k.tif" id="ImgLink-13k" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LT-1-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13l">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13l.tif" id="ImgLink-13l" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LT-2-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13m">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13m.tif" id="ImgLink-13m" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LT-2-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13n">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13n.tif" id="ImgLink-13n" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>LB-1-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13o">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13o.tif" id="ImgLink-13o" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>TE-1-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-13p">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_13p.tif" id="ImgLink-13p" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>TE-1-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="16" figure-order="14" data-type-order="18">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">The proppant amount and slurry volume injected into the formations are plotted as shown in Figure 14 and Figure 15 respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Total Proppant Placement on each frac stage</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Total Proppant Placement on each frac stage</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="16" figure-order="15" data-type-order="19">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr21">The proppant amount and slurry volume injected into the formations are plotted as shown in Figure 14 and Figure 15 respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Total Mainfrac fluid injection on each frac stage.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Total Mainfrac fluid injection on each frac stage.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="18" figure-order="16" data-type-order="22">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr22">The combination of pressure matching and pressure transient analysis was used as a primary method in determining the fracture results. Other fracture measurement applications including anisotropy analysis of and the analysis of temperature distribution between pre- and post-job were also applied on selected wells for vertical containment approximation. The fracture dimension - fracture half-length, fracture height, and fracture width - determined for each stage is given in Table 6. According to the results (Figure 16), the created half-length of every job in the proven area appeared to be in-line with that of its pre-job design. The only exception to this was that of the stage on LX-4 as the containment showed to be poorer than expected.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Fracture Half-length determined after each stage fracturing job basd on pressure matching and well test data analysis, comparing with the design.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fracture Half-length determined after each stage fracturing job basd on pressure matching and well test data analysis, comparing with the design.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="19" figure-order="17" data-type-order="23">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr23">On a per-stage basis, the jobs in this campaign HFB were approximately 24% quicker, while spending 31% less in cost, than those of the HFA (pilot) campaign as shown in Figure 17 where the comparision to those of their predecessors can aslo be qualitatively implied. Our analysis on time and cost model developed by grouping tasks sharing the same core elements of activities of frac operation on a well (similar to the development of the project time and cost model used for strategy determination prio to the campaign) allowed more accurate evaluation of time and cost effectiveness associated with each frac stage.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Actual (a) time and (b) cost utilization anong the campaigns considered on a per-stage basis.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Actual (a) time and (b) cost utilization anong the campaigns considered on a per-stage basis.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-17a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_17a.tif" id="ImgLink-17a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text> Actual time </caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-17b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_17b.tif" id="ImgLink-17b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>cost utilization</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="20" figure-order="18" data-type-order="24">
<link href="link-18" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-18" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr24">The production performances were closely monitored which revealed different productivity among fracturing stages. Two hydraulic fracturing stages within the same producer, but at different sublayers in same formation, can apparently yield diverse production rates. Figure 18 shows that the rates can be significantly varied, for example, the second stage of LZ-3 well, which has the best performance in the campaign, gives oil production rate above 25 times higher than some poor stages in some wells. This variation can be observed from the hydraulic fractured wells both in the proven and unproven areas. For instance, the TE-1 well, located in the unproven area and formations, show substantial difference of almost 16 times of oil production rate between two stages which are only about 80 meters apart.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118192047MS-Img_SPi-18">
<label>Figure 18 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118192047MS_i_18.tif" id="ImgLink-18" />
<caption>The variation of liquid and oil rates after clean up of all fracturing stages in Campaign B</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>18</caption-order>
<caption-text>The variation of liquid and oil rates after clean up of all fracturing stages in Campaign B</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>