<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118182869MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-22T13:58:52Z">
<doi>10.2118/182869-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/182869-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">Greater Burgan, which is located in the southeastern part of Kuwait, covers a surface area of about 450 square miles and has been ranked as one of the largest clastic oil fields in the world. The field is a four-closure and has a common OOWC of 4472 ft TVDSS. The field subdivided into three sub-domes Burgan, Ahmadi and Magwa separated by main graben (figure 1). The Burgan field is an ovate dome with a high ellipticity of 0.7 and a slight elongation striking north and it is uniformly dipping about 1° in all directions. The structure is cut by nearly 30 faults mapped as straight, part radial and commonly 3-4 km in length. Throws are generally less than 15 m.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182869MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182869MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>The Greater Burgan Field, Kuwait</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>The Greater Burgan Field, Kuwait</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">WELL AA1: Horizontal well in Wara drilled in the 90s but log data were not included purposely in the seismic inversion. The drilling history of the well and gamma ray log showed the lateral section drilled initially in good, clean sand then penetrated a shale layer then again encountered sand unit toward the toe of the lateral section. We compared this to the seismic volume taking different depth slices. The inversion volume indicated there are heterogeneity in the area and wara section having alternations between sand and shales, which is matching with the log data as well (Figure 2).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182869MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182869MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>different depth layers within Wara shows the lithological changes at the well path. Yellow are the good clean sand where red are shales</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>different depth layers within Wara shows the lithological changes at the well path. Yellow are the good clean sand where red are shales</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>