<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118178111MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-19T15:42:24Z">
<doi>10.2118/178111-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/178111-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The Raageshwari Deep Gas Field (RDG) was discovered in 2003 (Figure-1). Subsequent to the discovery, three additional appraisal wells produced gas during a period of extended well testing. The initial RDG field development plan (FDP) was submitted in 2005 and approved in 2006 as a supplement to the development plans for oilfields located in the northern part of RJ-ON-90/1. The initial 2005 FDP was based on RDG gas production as the fuel source for the processing of the waxy crudes in the northern part of the basin and for their transportation to the west coast of India through a ~600km heated crude oil pipeline.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Raageshwari Deep Gas Field Location and Structure Base Map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Raageshwari Deep Gas Field Location and Structure Base Map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The paced and phased RDG development provided additional time for data acquisition, and accordingly helped reduce subsurface uncertainties related to the potential for additional gas production for commercial gas sales. The re-evaluation showed a much higher RDG potential in terms of both deliverability and the expected ultimate recovery (EUR). Thus a revised FDP to maximize RDG economic potential including commercial gas sales as well as internal fuel usage was submitted to and approved by the management committee in 2015. The rejuvenation journey from internal usage to commercial gas is displayed in Figure-2. The key drivers of the revised 2015 FDP are as follows:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Raageshwari Deep Gas Historical Milestones</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Raageshwari Deep Gas Historical Milestones</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Prior to oilfield production startup, a few of the RDG wells were hydraulically fractured to improve their productivity. RDG has been on production since March 2010, but was only produced from the few wells necessary to cater to the oilfield fuel gas demands. In April 2013, commercial gas sales started on a test basis, so a few additional already stimulated wells were brought online. Extended well testing of several hydraulically fractured wells has now been carried out. The RDG production performance is shown in Figure-3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Raageshwari Deep Gas Field Production Performance</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Raageshwari Deep Gas Field Production Performance</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Characterization of volcanic reservoirs in terms of both rock and fluid properties is more difficult in comparison to conventional sandstone and carbonate reservoirs. Rapid changes in lithofacies, thickness and distribution of pores/vugs/fractures combined with significant vertical and horizontal heterogeneities are expected in such a depositional environment. Fluid and rock characterization based on conventional resistivity, density and porosity logs is difficult because these log responses are very dependent upon the mineralogy, volcanic rock types and inter-trappeans. A typical log from RDG showing the thick, low-NTG reservoir is shown in Figure-4.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Raageshwari Deep Gas Generic Log</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Raageshwari Deep Gas Generic Log</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">A seismic section showing the three major reservoir intervals mapped from north to south in the reservoir is given in Figure-5. Seismic velocities derived from processing of seismic data were calibrated with well velocities to facilitate use of the seismic over the entire extent of the field. The average of the shallowest P10 depth maps and the deepest P90 maps were considered as P50 depth maps and taken forward to static modeling.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Seismic Section Showing three Major Horizons Mapped from North to South</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Seismic Section Showing three Major Horizons Mapped from North to South</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The process of development of porosity, permeability and storage of hydrocarbons helps us to define and design appropriate petrophysical workflows. Porosity development is due to de-gassing from lava, weathering of minerals, alteration due to interaction with hydro-thermal fluids, natural fracturing, and other geological processes. Permeability development is due to development of fractures and inter-pore connectivity due to hydro-thermal fluid flows. A fit-for-purpose workflow and methodology was developed to capture the heterogeneity of the RDG reservoirs (Chowdhary, et. al, 2014). The step-by-step process is summarized in Figure-6.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>A Fit for Purpose Petrophysical Workflow used in Raageshwari Deep Gas Reservoir</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>A Fit for Purpose Petrophysical Workflow used in Raageshwari Deep Gas Reservoir</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">All geophysical, geological and petrophysical analyses were integrated within RDG static geocellular models for prediction and population of reservoir properties between wells. The static reservoir model was used for reservoir simulation purposes and future field development planning. The workflow used in building the static reservoir model is shown in Figure-7.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Static Reservoir Modeling Workflow</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Static Reservoir Modeling Workflow</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">In such situations it is better to use local grid refinement (LGR) near the wellbore (Gupta, et. al, 2014). As the name implies, LGR decreases the grid size locally and allows larger grid sizes throughout the reservoir volume. Thus LGR provides fine grid resolution without significantly increasing the number of total grid cells in a finite difference simulation. The commercial simulator used for the RDG work employed a fixed LGR size of 2ft near the wellbore and enhanced its matrix permeability accordingly to capture the measured fracture conductivity efficiency (Figure-8).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Hydraulic Fracture Representation in Finite Difference Numerical Simulation using Local Grid Refinements</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Hydraulic Fracture Representation in Finite Difference Numerical Simulation using Local Grid Refinements</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Well head pressure Well head pressure data was available for all wells and was a key performance parameter for history matching. A single vertical lift curve generated from actual flowing gradient survey results was used to convert the simulated bottomhole pressures to well head pressure for each well. A sample history match plot showing calculated vs measured tubing head pressure is given in Figure-9a.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9(a)</label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Well Head Pressure History Matching Plot for One Well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well Head Pressure History Matching Plot for One Well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Individual perforation contribution The production contributions of individual perforations measured from production logs were also used to calibrate the simulation model. A comparison of measured individual perforation contributions with the model results is given in Figure-9b.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 9(b)</label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Individual Fracture Stage PLT Contribution Comparison Plot for One Well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9 (b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Individual Fracture Stage PLT Contribution Comparison Plot for One Well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">The history matched simulation model was used to generate several future production scenarios. To capture uncertainties in the various input parameters, several sensitivities were performed to check the impact of individual parameters on production performance. The tornado plot on Figure-10 compares the impact of key parameters on RDG production performance. This has helped illustrate the upside and downside of the production forecasts for RDG commercial gas sales.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Tornado plot showing relative parametric impact on EUR from the field</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Tornado plot showing relative parametric impact on EUR from the field</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="12" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">The revised FDP has an average well spacing of 400-500m (40-60 acres per well), in line with analogue low permeability gas fields around the world (Kneller, et. al, 2006, Dubois et. al, 2006, Quint et. al, 2006). Wells will produce at lower tubing head pressures using a plant inlet booster compressor. A plateau period of ~5 years is envisaged as the optimum production scenario, during which ~50% of the total gas production will be realized. Mobile pad drilling is being used to minimize rig movement time; this is crucial to help contain project costs. Additional well pads will be required to drill wells in the less proven southern area of the field. A base map with existing and proposed well locations is shown in Figure-11.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118178111MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118178111MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Raageshwari Deep Gas Well Locations</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Raageshwari Deep Gas Well Locations</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>