<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118183006MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-22T17:20:01Z">
<doi>10.2118/183006-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/183006-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The subject reservoir is a sandstone deposited mainly in eolian dune complexes and sand sheets, as well as in playas and ephemeral streams in interdune areas. The dune and sand sheets of the eolian facies show the best reservoir quality, while the paleosol and playa show low porosity and permeability (&#x003C;1 mD). The rock is cemented with variable minerals including quartz, carbonates, anhydrite, kaolinite, and illite. Figure 1 shows Image log and core sections that depict the four facies dune, sandsheet, paleosol, and playa.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Image log that depict the four facies dune, sandsheet, paleosol, and playa with core description for each facies.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Image log that depict the four facies dune, sandsheet, paleosol, and playa with core description for each facies.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">Presence of clay minerals in the rock is adding another complexity as the conductivity contribution of the clay typically dominates the overall conductivity response, at the expense of the hydrocarbon phase. Figure 2 depicts a set of open hole logs (gamma ray, neutron density, and deep and shallow resistivity). Two sand bodies separated by thick shale layer are observed: the upper sand is located between X100 ft and X190 ft while the lower sand body is located between X300 ft and X380 ft. It appears from resistivity logs that the upper sand starting at X120 ft contains hydrocarbon and at about X-150 ft looks wet and therefore the oil-water contact (OWC) is located at ± X140.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Wireline triple combo logs and RFT pressure gradients for oil and water.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Wireline triple combo logs and RFT pressure gradients for oil and water.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Resistivity interpretations uncertainty aggravates as field matures and other external source of water is introduced in the reservoir to be mixed with the formation water. Figure 3 depicts LWD triple-combo for an infill sidetrack Well X-G2 that was drilled horizontally across the main reservoir compared to the original logs before production startup. High resistivity readings were observed across the intersected sand indicating hydrocarbon saturation presence, which is also observed in the initial log. As a result, the well was completed as an oil producer with sand screen completion. Surprisingly, the well performance was sub optimal with high water production.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Initial resistivity interpretation of X-G2 vs. sidetracked well LWD resistivity interpretations.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Initial resistivity interpretation of X-G2 vs. sidetracked well LWD resistivity interpretations.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">This well was originally drilled as a vertical producer on the western flank of the field. Figure 4 shows the formation analysis interpretations, which shows resistivity drop across the pay zone, yet the well produced dry oil. After years of production, the well has observed low oil rate and high water cut (&#x003E; 95 percentage) indicating that water has fully contacted the main producing zone. The team decided to sidetrack the well to an upswept area to improve oil productivity and reduce water cut.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Orignal wireline triple combo logs for Well XH1.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Orignal wireline triple combo logs for Well XH1.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">This well was originally drilled as a vertical producer on the western flank of the field. Figure 4 shows the formation analysis interpretations, which shows resistivity drop across the pay zone, yet the well produced dry oil. After years of production, the well has observed low oil rate and high water cut (&#x003E; 95 percentage) indicating that water has fully contacted the main producing zone. The team decided to sidetrack the well to an upswept area to improve oil productivity and reduce water cut. To reduce the saturation interpretation uncertainty around this area, the team had first drilled a pilot hole with coring and a suite of logs, including NMR and formation tester pressure and sampling tools in addition to advanced mud logging, Fig. 5.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Suite of fluid identification logging tools used in Well XH1.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Suite of fluid identification logging tools used in Well XH1.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">This well was originally drilled as a vertical producer on the western flank of the field. Figure 4 shows the formation analysis interpretations, which shows resistivity drop across the pay zone, yet the well produced dry oil. After years of production, the well has observed low oil rate and high water cut (&#x003E; 95 percentage) indicating that water has fully contacted the main producing zone. The team decided to sidetrack the well to an upswept area to improve oil productivity and reduce water cut. To reduce the saturation interpretation uncertainty around this area, the team had first drilled a pilot hole with coring and a suite of logs, including NMR and formation tester pressure and sampling tools in addition to advanced mud logging, Fig. 5. As shown in Fig. 6, the resistivity showed more or less similar trend to the original resistivity signature, Fig. 4, which added more to the challengs of the saturation analysis. Both NMR and formation tester tools results confirmed the presence of movable water across the target ambiguous zone's saturation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Weil X-H_1 pilot hole and horizontal sidetracked Well X-H1_2.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Weil X-H_1 pilot hole and horizontal sidetracked Well X-H1_2.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Well X-H2 was drilled initially as a vertical development well and perforated across 150 ft of oil-bearing sandstone reservoir as described in Fig. 7a, producing dry oil. After about 10 years of production, the well had observed high water cut, therefore, the well was sidetracked south as a single lateral oil producer. LWD indicated high resistivity across the drilled section as shown in Fig. 7b, therefore it was decided to complete the section with sand screens only. Unfortunately, the post-sidetrack performance of X-H2 experienced high water production rate indicating excessive water encroachment that was not detected by LWD resistivity readings.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well X-H2 VT well and sidetrack #1 logs interpretations.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well X-H2 VT well and sidetrack #1 logs interpretations.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">As a result, the team realized that utilizing the conventional resistivity LWD this low resistivity contrast clastic reservoir is inconclusive. After 6 years, the team decided to revitalize the well and recomplete it as dual lateral oil producer, but this time with comprehensive and integrated petrophysical methodology to reduce uncertainty and mitigate risk. Prior to drilling the two laterals, a pilot hole was drilled (X-H2_2) with coring and a suite of logs, including NMR and formation tester pressure and fluid sampling tools, Fig. 8.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Well X-H2 VT well resistivity vs. sidetrack #2 (pilot hole suite of logs).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well X-H2 VT well resistivity vs. sidetrack #2 (pilot hole suite of logs).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Comparing the pilot hole formation log analysis (FAL) of the pilot hole to the original FAL, indicate that water has already displaced the oil around this area. Results has driven the team to target the upper oil-bearing zone and avoid the underlying wet zones while drilling the first lateral toward the south. Figure 9 shows that the first lateral was drilled to intersect about 200 ft across the upper good quality lobe due to encountered reservoir and structural complexity.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Lateral #3 and #4 LWD logs interpretations.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Lateral #3 and #4 LWD logs interpretations.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Well Y-G01 was drilled on the western flank to delineate the reservoir boundary and confirm fluid contacts. The well observed wet reservoir as the top came just below the predicted OWC. Figure 10 shows an agreement of resistivity readings with NMR, and formation tester fluid samples in confirming the presence of the water-bearing zone. It is worth noting that the resistivity readings are low across high porosity zones and a little bit high across moderate to low porosity zones, which exhibits the effect of shaliness on getting a reliable resistivity interpretation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Well Y-G01 logs of the vertical downdip well and the sidetracked updip horizontal well.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well Y-G01 logs of the vertical downdip well and the sidetracked updip horizontal well.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">The estimated C/O OWC is close to the original OWC contact as shown on the left log in Fig. 11. The water reinvasion affect across perforations during shut in has been clearly identified, which has been removed during flowing. Although the C/O curve below the perforation zone is outside the envelop due to unknown fluid composition in the sump, the response of C/O curve clearly indicates the transition from oil. The C/O methodology has been applied in other observation wells in this field.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183006MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183006MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>The initial formation analysis log during the field development on the left along with the CO shut in and flowing passes results.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>The initial formation analysis log during the field development on the left along with the CO shut in and flowing passes results.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>