<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118189067MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-29T11:00:08Z">
<doi>10.2118/189067-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/189067-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The principle of using hydrocarbon ratio as a natural tracer has already been described in the literature (Pixler, B. O., 1969; Zhou, L., &amp; Blue, D. D, 2009). The plots used in this article represent the ratio C2 /C1+C2+C3 (C2/C123) versus the ratio C1 / C1+C2+C3 (C1/C123). In this article, the gas will be described as "leaner" if its signature on the C2/C123 vs. C1/C123 chart is close to the one of the R4 reservoir at initial condition. It will be described as "richer" if its signature is similar to the initial R10-R11 signature (see Figure 1).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Composition of the gas produced from PVT sampling campaigns (2011-2014), compared with initial composition from R10-R11 and R4 reservoirs (2002-2004).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Composition of the gas produced from PVT sampling campaigns (2011-2014), compared with initial composition from R10-R11 and R4 reservoirs (2002-2004).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Figure 1 highlights also that the initial gas composition is more homogenous for the R10 and R11 reservoirs than for the R4 reservoir. This can be explained by the correlation between the composition and the depth of the fluid sampled. Indeed, the deeper the fluid, the richer in heavier components. This is also demonstrated in Figure 2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Composition of the gas sampled initially vs. depth (m, TVDSS) of sampling from DSTs</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Composition of the gas sampled initially vs. depth (m, TVDSS) of sampling from DSTs</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">In order to estimate the percentage of gas produced from R4 and from R10, an uncertainly range was assumed regarding the composition of R10 at Well A, based on the measurements carried out on Well B and Well C when producing R10. Similarly, an uncertainty range was estimated for R4 reservoir based on Well D and Well E that were also producing from R4, in the same flow unit that was punched in Well A (see Figure 3).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Composition of produced gas from Well B, Well C (R10) and Well D, Well E (R4FU2) with Well A</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Composition of produced gas from Well B, Well C (R10) and Well D, Well E (R4FU2) with Well A</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Only one well is currently producing from R4b, namely Well F, as Well G was closed in 2015 due to integrity issue. Seismic data enabled the identification of a fault splitting R4b sands and that may isolate Well F (see Figure 4).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Net sand map of R4b sands. The true vertical depth of the top of the reservoir is indicated by contour lines.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Net sand map of R4b sands. The true vertical depth of the top of the reservoir is indicated by contour lines.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Based on pressure measurements, Well F seems dynamically disconnected from Well G. Furthermore, the gas composition analysis shows that in 2012 Well F and Well G present two different signatures (see Figure 5), Well F producing clearly leaner gas. This observation confirms the compartmentalization, which explains the rapid increase in GOR associated with the decrease in pressure. The change in signature between Well G and the initial DSTs captured in other wells of R4b is likely due to the depressurization of R4b.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Comparison of the gas composition from the initial DSTs acquired in R4b and Well F, Well G (producing recently from R4b)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of the gas composition from the initial DSTs acquired in R4b and Well F, Well G (producing recently from R4b)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">As evidenced previously there is a strong correlation between the initial gas composition and the depth of the producing layer (see Figure 2). A comparison was drawn between the initial gas composition from DSTs and the current gas composition as seen on Figure 6. It is clear that all the perforations are producing from similar depths, as all oil producers target the same oil ring. Additionally it is striking to observe that for some wells (Well I, Well J) the gas composition has deviated a lot from the original trend. A qualitative interpretation could be provided when the gas composition is richer than the initial gas composition.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Comparison of the produced gas composition from R4FU4 wells with initial gas composition from DSTs</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of the produced gas composition from R4FU4 wells with initial gas composition from DSTs</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="7" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">It is the case for Well I (central panel) and Well J (western panel) when sampled in 2013. This gas composition evolution is likely due to the enrichment of the gas by the injected stream. These two wells are situated on two different sides of the main fault, as shown in Figure 7, which suggests that the fault is open (at least in the gas bearing region). This interpretation is consistent with previous observations from tracer injection campaign (2005) and with other monitoring information (pressure trends, GOR evolution).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189067MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189067MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Top of R4FU4b, oil producers in green, water injector in blue and gas injectors in red. The initial WOC is outlined in blue and the initial GOC in red.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Top of R4FU4b, oil producers in green, water injector in blue and gas injectors in red. The initial WOC is outlined in blue and the initial GOC in red.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>