<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190174MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-30T19:49:23Z">
<doi>10.2118/190174-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190174-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">North Slope Alaska is estimated to contain 12 billion barrels of original oil in place of viscous oil in the shallow, late Cretaceous, Schrader Bluff Formation. This resource generally overlies deeper producing fields including two of the biggest fields in North America, Prudhoe Bay and Kuparuk (Figure 1). Alaska North Slope (ANS) viscous oil resource (VO) is one of the largest under-developed accumulations in North America. If even modest recoveries can be achieved (compared to light oil), potential reserves are substantial.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Alaska North Slope startigraphy showing major fields.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Alaska North Slope startigraphy showing major fields.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Detailed reviews of ANS VO resources are available (Paskvan 2016, Targac 2005). Of the estimated 12 billion barrels in place, 2.5 billion are being developed with water flooding (Figure 2). Over 150 million barrels oil have been produced to date with estimated ultimate recovery factor (RF) averaging 17% at 0.75 HCPVI at 35 years. This relatively low RF makes Alaska viscous a huge target for improving waterflood and applying enhanced oil recovery methods. Paskvan et. al. (2016) delves into the viscous resource and development history, evolution of well design, key waterflooding challenges, and geomechanical understanding that may meet these challenges.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Viscous oil resources in Alaska. Red outlined part is the already developed area.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscous oil resources in Alaska. Red outlined part is the already developed area.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Play to the engineering and operational strength of BP in managing and improving waterfloods. There exists a continuum of viscosity in VO (Figure 3) ranging from less than 150 cP to more than 2000 cP. Waterflooding is the current development strategy for the lower viscosity barrels, i. e. up to 600 cP, yet WF performance to date has underperformed expectations largely due to soft sand rock failures. The first goal of the RAS is to progress undeveloped high quality viscous oil projects to execute stage. From a technical standpoint, this objective necessitated establishing reliable recovery from waterfloodable viscous oil.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff viscosity continuum that influences the choice of IOR/EOR extraction techniques.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff viscosity continuum that influences the choice of IOR/EOR extraction techniques.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">The second RAS objective is to screen VO EOR options over a broad range of viscosities to improve RF by 10%. Alaska fluids range over a continuum of viscosities from light through viscous to heavy. Associated with this are continuums of technical, organizational, scientific and commercial challenges which increase as resource development progresses to heavier, more viscous oils (Figure 4). The optimal extraction technique is not only a function of viscosity, but also original oil in place (OOIP) and rock type. A description of an emerging “Quilt” of different recovery methods applied to different resource tranches is provided in Paskvan 2016.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Viscosity, technical and commercial challenges continuum across ANS VOHO Resources.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity, technical and commercial challenges continuum across ANS VOHO Resources.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">The third RAS objective is to assess heavy oil (HO) reservoir deliverability and cold extraction techniques through heavy oil pilot operation and artificial lift studies. These topics are beyond the scope of this paper. Heavy oil occurs in the Ugnu Formation at depths from 2000 to 5000 feet (Figures 1 and 5). At-scale development of VO and HO share clear synergies: geography, technologies, facilities, and ownership.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Most heavy oil resides in Ugnu overlying Schrader Bluff with high permeability and high net to gross.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Most heavy oil resides in Ugnu overlying Schrader Bluff with high permeability and high net to gross.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">Develop a list of potential extraction techniques (Figure 6).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Technologies identified that could be applied to viscous oil development.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Technologies identified that could be applied to viscous oil development.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">Characterize and high-grade the extraction techniques by materiality, readiness, and potential to cost-effectively develop VO resource tranches (Figure 7).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>VO high-graded technology options-technologies identified to cost effectively deliver VO RAS objectives.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>VO high-graded technology options-technologies identified to cost effectively deliver VO RAS objectives.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">Key challenges to waterflooding Schrader Bluff are well spacing and operational practices that limit HCPVI (Paskvan 2016, Bidinger 1995). Increased flood rate is needed to realize improved oil recovery (IOR), but risks of rock failure through Matrix Bypass Events (MBEs) with increased injection and interwell gradients require improved completions using sand control. Performance of individual areas vary, but SB waterfloods (Figure 8) have an average expected recovery of 17% with 0.75 HCPVI after 35 years of injection (Paskvan 2016). The average waterflood performance of SB is very consistent with global analogs.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Waterflood recovery vs. HCPV injected, global analogs and Alaska Schrader Bluff fields.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Waterflood recovery vs. HCPV injected, global analogs and Alaska Schrader Bluff fields.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Results from a history matched West Sak Type Pattern Model (TPM) (5 spot, 40 acres pattern with vertical wells) provides an estimate of RF by sands (BP and Conoco Phillips internal report). The West Sak area is operated by Conoco Phillips. The West Sak WF area has seen water breakthrough and thus provides more data to match. Figure 9 shows that total waterflood recovery in the 1D area for all the sands is 23% of OOIP at 0.8 HCPVI. The recovery trend is consistent with the original waterflood pilot results and associated pilot forecast.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>History matched West Sak sector model (VIP) showing potential recovery (BP internal report).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>History matched West Sak sector model (VIP) showing potential recovery (BP internal report).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="9" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">Figure 10 show recovery by sand. The D sand is well below total recovery with only 14% recovery in 30 years. The B sand appears to be well swept with nearly 35% recovery. B sand with 35% recovery is nearly at 100% water cut by the end 30 years. However, the A and D sands have had very little throughput in that time. This indicates that these zones are poorly swept and would benefit from greater throughput.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>History matched West Sak TPM recovery by sand (BP and Conoco Phillips internal report).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>History matched West Sak TPM recovery by sand (BP and Conoco Phillips internal report).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-10a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_10a.tif" id="ImgLink-10a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-10b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_10b.tif" id="ImgLink-10b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">According to Beliveau (2009), an analysis of waterflooded reservoirs in Western Canada (Figure11,Figure 12) shows that most viscous oil fields can yield good waterflood recoveries if a few basic tenets are followed including development on reasonably close well spacing when continuity is an issue, appropriate facility design, sufficient throughput of injected water, production to very high watercuts, a VRR close to unity, proper reservoir surveillance, and flexibility in adjusting the waterflood patterns employed are all keys to successful and economic projects.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Hydrocarbon pore volumes water injected versus oil RF (Western Canada analogs).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Hydrocarbon pore volumes water injected versus oil RF (Western Canada analogs).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="12" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">According to Beliveau (2009), an analysis of waterflooded reservoirs in Western Canada (Figure11,Figure 12) shows that most viscous oil fields can yield good waterflood recoveries if a few basic tenets are followed including development on reasonably close well spacing when continuity is an issue, appropriate facility design, sufficient throughput of injected water, production to very high watercuts, a VRR close to unity, proper reservoir surveillance, and flexibility in adjusting the waterflood patterns employed are all keys to successful and economic projects.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Waterflood recovery as a function of oil viscosity (Western Canada analogs).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Waterflood recovery as a function of oil viscosity (Western Canada analogs).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="13" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">Average oil recovery for a waterflood case was 41% OOIP. An additional average of 7 to 11% OOIP was recovered by using low salinity brine. Table 1 summarizes LoSal™ oil recovery as a function of brine salinity. Oil recovery improves from 41% for the highest salinity case (23000 ppm TDS) to 48% OOIP for salinity corresponding to 5000 ppm. Figure 13 shows cumulative oil recovery as a function of brine composition.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Oil recovery as a function of injection brine salinity-low temperature, low salinitystudies conducted at the University of Alaska Fairbanks.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil recovery as a function of injection brine salinity-low temperature, low salinitystudies conducted at the University of Alaska Fairbanks.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="14" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">Slim tube tests were conducted to determine the resistance factors at Schrader Bluff sand thief permeabilities (1 – 1.8 Darcy). A 40’ sandpack is coiled inside an oven with pressure taps every 5’ to measure the pressure at those points (9 pressure tap readings) and differential pressure (dP) over the whole 40’ pack (Figure 14). This slim tube test was conducted for a sandpack with ~2 Darcy permeability using a 5000 ppm BRIGHTWATER™. At the start of the test, TAP is injected into the 40’ sandpack at reservoir temperatures.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Slim tube tests results for a high permeability sand pack.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Slim tube tests results for a high permeability sand pack.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="15" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr21">Figure 15 shows another slim tube test for a ~1 Darcy sandpack with TAP concentration of 2000 ppm. No increase in pressure was observed even after 100 days indicating the TAP did not pop. For the high permeability 2 Darcy test, slim tube pressure increases were observed though far smaller than expected.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Slim tube tests results for a low permeability sand pack.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Slim tube tests results for a low permeability sand pack.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="16" figure-order="16" data-type-order="17">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr22">Understanding fluid chemistry variations would help define reserves as anticipated in a full commercial development. Our purpose was also to ascertain if, and what, different cocktails of ASP formulations may be required across the Schrader viscosity spectrum. This would help plan the laboratory studies and other studies required to understand full potential of ASP floods in SB. Figure 16 is a viscosity map of Milne Point Field and shows where the samples were collected. The samples are collected for a defined range of viscosities.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Viscosity map of Milne Point field showing fluids sample collection locations.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity map of Milne Point field showing fluids sample collection locations.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="17" figure-order="17" data-type-order="19">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr23">BP Alaska provided dead oil samples to AITF. Oils were made live by adding Milne gas manufactured in the laboratory to ensure samples generated were representative of the Milne SB crude. SB oils from Milne Point are similar to many viscous crudes, consisting of lighter components and an appreciable percentage of heavier components including waxes, napthenic acids, resins and asphaltenes. Oil sample analysis included viscosity and density measurements at both the room temperature and at reservoir temperature, Total Acid Number (TAN), Total Base Number (TBN) (Figure 17) and SARA analysis (Figure 18).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Total Acid Number (TAN) and Total Base Number (TBN) of Schrader oil samples.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Total Acid Number (TAN) and Total Base Number (TBN) of Schrader oil samples.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="18" figure-order="18" data-type-order="20">
<link href="link-18" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-18" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr24">BP Alaska provided dead oil samples to AITF. Oils were made live by adding Milne gas manufactured in the laboratory to ensure samples generated were representative of the Milne SB crude. SB oils from Milne Point are similar to many viscous crudes, consisting of lighter components and an appreciable percentage of heavier components including waxes, napthenic acids, resins and asphaltenes. Oil sample analysis included viscosity and density measurements at both the room temperature and at reservoir temperature, Total Acid Number (TAN), Total Base Number (TBN) (Figure 17) and SARA analysis (Figure 18).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-18">
<label>Figure 18 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_18.tif" id="ImgLink-18" />
<caption>Schrader oil samples SARA analysis.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>18</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader oil samples SARA analysis.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="18" figure-order="19" data-type-order="21">
<link href="link-19" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-19" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr25">Figure 19 is a plot of sample oil densities and Figure 20 is a viscosity plot of oil samples. Both oil density and oil viscosity decrease with increasing temperature as would be expected. Figure 19 showed that SB oil samples were close to the target viscosity of 100 cp and less (dead oil) and exhibited a similar trend in viscosity variation with temperature except for well MPJ-01. This sample has the lowest density, highest API, but exhibits a high viscosity of almost 200 cP.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-19">
<label>Figure 19 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_19.tif" id="ImgLink-19" />
<caption>Schrader oil from different wells showing similar trends in density and viscosity changes.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>19</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader oil from different wells showing similar trends in density and viscosity changes.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="19" figure-order="20" data-type-order="22">
<link href="link-20" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-20" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr26">Figure 19 is a plot of sample oil densities and Figure 20 is a viscosity plot of oil samples. Both oil density and oil viscosity decrease with increasing temperature as would be expected. Figure 19 showed that SB oil samples were close to the target viscosity of 100 cp and less (dead oil) and exhibited a similar trend in viscosity variation with temperature except for well MPJ-01. This sample has the lowest density, highest API, but exhibits a high viscosity of almost 200 cP.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-20">
<label>Figure 20 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_20.tif" id="ImgLink-20" />
<caption>Schrader oil samples oil viscosity as a function of temperature.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>20</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader oil samples oil viscosity as a function of temperature.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="21" figure-order="21" data-type-order="25">
<link href="link-21" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-21" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr27">The polymer viscosities of these polymers ranging in concentration from 500 to 2500 ppm are shown in (Figure 21) for a shear rate of 7s-1 and for a shear rate of 10s-1. A brine concentration of 7000 ppm was used for the study. The bulk viscosity of Superpusher C319 outperforms other polymers at higher concentrations. Polymers EOR 360 and Flopaam 3630 seem to generate similar bulk viscosities as a function of polymer concentration.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-21">
<label>Figure 21 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_21.tif" id="ImgLink-21" />
<caption>Polymer viscosity as function of concentration (Prudhoe Sea water + Prince Creek water). Flopaam 3630 viscosity in Prince Creek Water and Prudhoe Bay Water at shear rate of 10 s-1.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>21</caption-order>
<caption-text>Polymer viscosity as function of concentration (Prudhoe Sea water + Prince Creek water). Flopaam 3630 viscosity in Prince Creek Water and Prudhoe Bay Water at shear rate of 10 s-1.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-21a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_21a.tif" id="ImgLink-21a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-21b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_21b.tif" id="ImgLink-21b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="22" figure-order="22" data-type-order="26">
<link href="link-22" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-22" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr28">For the ASP systems, several surfactant samples generated positive phase behavior evaluations to indicate potential in incremental oil recovery. Figure 22 shows phase behavior of one of the shortlisted optimum formulation. Formulation that provided favorable results is marked by the red box in Figure 22.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-22">
<label>Figure 22 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_22.tif" id="ImgLink-22" />
<caption>Schrader oil phase behavior studies (SasolS23-13S surfactant).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>22</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader oil phase behavior studies (SasolS23-13S surfactant).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="23" figure-order="23" data-type-order="27">
<link href="link-23" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-23" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr29">The bulk adsorption was measured for all the surfactants. The overall surfactant adsorption is shown in (Figure 23). Adsorption values below 100 mg of surfactant per 100 g of rock would be ideal. Adsorption values above 200 mg of surfactant per 100 g of rock are economically challenging. The surfactants that had low adsorption values included Sasol S23-13S, Sasol L123, Sasol K4-13S, and OCT ORS74. In most cases, the presence of alkali dropped the surfactant adsorption level.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-23">
<label>Figure 23 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_23.tif" id="ImgLink-23" />
<caption>Adsorption (mg/100 g) rock for surfactants used in the AITF study.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>23</caption-order>
<caption-text>Adsorption (mg/100 g) rock for surfactants used in the AITF study.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="24" figure-order="24" data-type-order="28">
<link href="link-24" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-24" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr30">The first sandpack was loaded with the total bulk sand sample. Two pore volumes of PC +PB brine was followed with a (3.5 pore volume) polymer slug. The polymer formulations consisted of 1300 ppm polymer Floopaam 3630 mixed in PC +PB brine. The waterflood recovered 33% of the original oil in place after 2.0 pore volumes injected. The subsequent polymer flood recovered another 34% OOIP after 3.5 pore volumes of polymer injected. The oil production profile and watercut for the waterflood followed by polymer flood are shown in Figure 24 as a function of pore volumes injected.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-24">
<label>Figure 24 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_24.tif" id="ImgLink-24" />
<caption>Incremental polymer flood and ASP flood recovery from AITF sand pack cores.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>24</caption-order>
<caption-text>Incremental polymer flood and ASP flood recovery from AITF sand pack cores.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-24a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_24a.tif" id="ImgLink-24a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-24b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_24b.tif" id="ImgLink-24b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="26" figure-order="25" data-type-order="31">
<link href="link-25" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-25" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr31">Figure 25 shows oil recovery, oil cut and pressure drop for the first core flood. Oil cut rose to ~65%during ASP flood and water cut accordingly went down to ~35%. Waterflood reduces oil saturation from 84% to 40.3%. The first ASP coreflood reduced the oil saturation to 14.4%. Residual saturation to ASP of 14.4% is regarded as high in a sandpack coreflood and a residual of below 5% would be optimum.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-25">
<label>Figure 25 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_25.tif" id="ImgLink-25" />
<caption>Oil recovery vs. pore volume injected for UT first core flood</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>25</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil recovery vs. pore volume injected for UT first core flood</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="26" figure-order="26" data-type-order="32">
<link href="link-26" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-26" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr32">(Figure 26) shows the oil recovery, oil cut, pressure drop versus PV injected for the second coreflood. Oil cut in the second coreflood is 75%. Coreflood 2 exhibited higher recovery than coreflood 1 mainly due to a more optimized formulation and better mobility control.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-26">
<label>Figure 26 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_26.tif" id="ImgLink-26" />
<caption>Oil recovery vs. pore volume injected for UT second core flood.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>26</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil recovery vs. pore volume injected for UT second core flood.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="27" figure-order="27" data-type-order="33">
<link href="link-27" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-27" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr33">Schrader Bluff stratigraphy of the pilot area is shown in Figure 27. The key producing sands are the NB, OA and OB sands. While designing the field test, a well selection criteria was that no N sands be present. This would eliminate any concerns of cross flow between different sands. Figure 28 shows the reservoir heterogeneity typical of the pilot area. Schrader Bluff has two distinct rock types based on the depositional environment. About 1/3 OOIP is in the higher permeability (~600 mD) rock and 2/3 of OOIP is in the low permeability rock (&#x003C;100 mD).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-27">
<label>Figure 27 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_27.tif" id="ImgLink-27" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff stratigraphy of the pilot area.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>27</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff stratigraphy of the pilot area.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="28" figure-order="28" data-type-order="34">
<link href="link-28" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-28" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr34">Schrader Bluff stratigraphy of the pilot area is shown in Figure 27. The key producing sands are the NB, OA and OB sands. While designing the field test, a well selection criteria was that no N sands be present. This would eliminate any concerns of cross flow between different sands. Figure 28 shows the reservoir heterogeneity typical of the pilot area. Schrader Bluff has two distinct rock types based on the depositional environment. About 1/3 OOIP is in the higher permeability (~600 mD) rock and 2/3 of OOIP is in the low permeability rock (&#x003C;100 mD).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-28">
<label>Figure 28 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_28.tif" id="ImgLink-28" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff reservoir rock heterogenity.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>28</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff reservoir rock heterogenity.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="29" figure-order="29" data-type-order="35">
<link href="link-29" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-29" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr35">Polymer selection procedure is summarized in Figure 29. For this project, TIORCO polymers including EOR 380, EOR 360 and EOR 80 were screened. As should be expected, for similar concentration, higher molecular weight polymers EOR 380 and EOR 360 give the maximum viscosification compared to lower molecular weight polymer EOR80. However, the molecular weight versus permeability plot (Figure 29) clearly shows that only EOR 80 can effectively propagate through both the high permeability and low permeability sands. Higher molecular weight EOR 380 can effectively propagate through sands with permeabilities greater than 100 mD.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-29">
<label>Figure 29 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_29.tif" id="ImgLink-29" />
<caption>Polymer selection criteria for Schrader field trial.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>29</caption-order>
<caption-text>Polymer selection criteria for Schrader field trial.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="30" figure-order="30" data-type-order="36">
<link href="link-30" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-30" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr36">Polymer injection test design is shown in Figure 30. The planned field test could not be conducted due to failure of the vendor’s supplied mixing head (designed to hydrate the dry polymer powder into a uniform aqueous mixture). As mentioned before we could not find a well with only OA/OB completions in a healthy pattern with no MBE history. Well MPI-08 is completed in all the three sands OA, OB and N sands. Our test design included dummying off N sands and pulling out WFRV in both the N sands and the OA sands. Our plan was to set a pressure and rate gauge in the OA sands.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-30">
<label>Figure 30 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_30.tif" id="ImgLink-30" />
<caption>Schrader polymer injection test design schematic.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>30</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader polymer injection test design schematic.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="31" figure-order="31" data-type-order="37">
<link href="link-31" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-31" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr37">Cell dimensions are 10 feet by 10 feet in x and y directions within the refined area. Figure 31 shows the extent of polymer ring at the end of the test. We wanted to know how far the design polymer has been able to migrate and the polymer adsorption and RRF within this region. This was to ascertain if the design polymer could be injected economically and without a substantial reduction in formation permeability. Figure 31 also shows the expected adsorption, viscosity and RRF for the test design, all important parameters to understand the sensibility of injecting design polymer in average to low permeability Schrader Bluff rock.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-31">
<label>Figure 31 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_31.tif" id="ImgLink-31" />
<caption>Simulation results for Schrader field trial.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>31</caption-order>
<caption-text>Simulation results for Schrader field trial.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="31" figure-order="32" data-type-order="38">
<link href="link-32" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-32" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr38">Learnings from the simulation studies are shown on Figure 32 and summarized as:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-32">
<label>Figure 32 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_32.tif" id="ImgLink-32" />
<caption>Simulation results for Schrader field trial.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>32</caption-order>
<caption-text>Simulation results for Schrader field trial.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="33" figure-order="33" data-type-order="39">
<link href="link-33" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-33" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr39">Field results thus far indicate additional recovery of 2% to 4% of OOIP above WF recovery from VRWAG. VRWAG also helps lifting well hydraulics, and builds-up reservoir pressure faster than water injection. Figure 33 shows viscosity and oil density reduction for a West Sak oil in a multicomponent laboratory study (Conoco Phillips internal report). Viscosity reduces from an original 60 cP to ~5 cP after 3 contacts of injectant gas (Kuparuk MI-76%C1, 6% C2 and 7+% C3+ hydrocarbons) and West Sak oil (18 API). VRWAG should be considered where a source of VRI is economically available.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-33">
<label>Figure 33 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_33.tif" id="ImgLink-33" />
<caption>Multi-contact lab studies showing viscosity and density reduction as a function of number of gas contacts for West Sak oil.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>33</caption-order>
<caption-text>Multi-contact lab studies showing viscosity and density reduction as a function of number of gas contacts for West Sak oil.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-33a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_33a.tif" id="ImgLink-33a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-33b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_33b.tif" id="ImgLink-33b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="35" figure-order="34" data-type-order="40">
<link href="link-34" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-34" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr40">Laboratory studies indicate Schrader oil displays classical burning characteristics. Work done at the University of Calgary further showed that SB oil can successfully burn in dry mode, wet mode (co-inject water with air) and post water flood conditions. Figure 34 summarizes the preliminary results for the Schrader oil. The zero time (0.00 hours) is the time that air injection was started.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-34">
<label>Figure 34 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_34.tif" id="ImgLink-34" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff oil combustion test results. Oil and Water Production (Cumulative Masses) U of C Test 411, BP Alaska No. 1, Schrader Bluff No. 1 Center Line Temperature Profiles U of C Test 411, BP Alaska Schrader Bluff No. 1</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>34</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff oil combustion test results. Oil and Water Production (Cumulative Masses) U of C Test 411, BP Alaska No. 1, Schrader Bluff No. 1 Center Line Temperature Profiles U of C Test 411, BP Alaska Schrader Bluff No. 1</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-34a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_34a.tif" id="ImgLink-34a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil and Water Production (Cumulative Masses) U of C Test 411, BP Alaska No. 1, Schrader Bluff No. 1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-34b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_34b.tif" id="ImgLink-34b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Center Line Temperature Profiles U of C Test 411, BP Alaska Schrader Bluff No. 1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="3" pdf-page="36" figure-order="35" data-type-order="41">
<link href="link-35" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-35" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr41">Sensitivity studies conducted using ISC SB model show that the process is highly sensitive to reservoir thickness and oil viscosity and insensitive to formation permeability (Figure 35).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-35">
<label>Figure 35 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_35.tif" id="ImgLink-35" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff ISC benchmarking studies. Oil RF Sensitivity to Viscosity WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD Thickness versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD, 1000 CP Viscosity versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>35</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff ISC benchmarking studies. Oil RF Sensitivity to Viscosity WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD Thickness versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD, 1000 CP Viscosity versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-35a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_35a.tif" id="ImgLink-35a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Oil RF Sensitivity to Viscosity WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-35b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_35b.tif" id="ImgLink-35b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Thickness versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD, 1000 CP</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-35c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_35c.tif" id="ImgLink-35c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>c</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity versus Oil Rate WWSAK, 60 Acre Spacing, 200mD</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="37" figure-order="36" data-type-order="42">
<link href="link-36" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-36" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr42">Benchmarking studies (Figure 36) show for SB ISC development critical parameters for project economics, RF and air/oil ratio, fall in the range with other ISC projects and pilots worldwide.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190174MS-Img_SPi-36">
<label>Figure 36 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190174MS_i_36.tif" id="ImgLink-36" />
<caption>Schrader Bluff ISC benchmarking studies-commercial factors.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>36</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schrader Bluff ISC benchmarking studies-commercial factors.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>