<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118176345MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-15T15:05:55Z">
<doi>10.2118/176345-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/176345-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The study areas are located at the perimeter of Sundaland continental margin that is referred as deepwater Sundaland continental margin (abbreviated as DSCM) and indicated in Fig. 1 as the shaded areas. Geopressure characteristics of DSCM conform to the general concept of deepwater geopressure found anywhere else. However, their unique geological setting has impacted geopressure mechanisms and prediction strategy. One of the most notable differences is that the geophysical log-based empirical prediction method, which is strongly influenced by effective stress method, might be inapplicable in the area. This is due to the compressional tectonic regime of deepwater Borneo continental margin that some authors such as Swarbrick (2012) and Yassir and Addis (2002) has indicated to be one of the conditions where the effective stress approach fails to predict accurately. Several drilling experiences in the study area have observed the tendency of such method to under-predict the pore pressure, resulting in many unpleasant drilling surprises (Couzens-Schultz and Azbel, 2014; Kirschner, 2005)</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Sundaland continent in SE Asia; dotted areas are basins at the continental margin. A-B and C-D are cross-section lines that will be addressed in Fig.2</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sundaland continent in SE Asia; dotted areas are basins at the continental margin. A-B and C-D are cross-section lines that will be addressed in <link href="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-2">Fig.2</link>
</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">Despite their active compressional state, Borneo deepwater fold-thrust belts are still undergoing rapid deltaic deposition. This active deposition provides vertical loading superimposed on the tectonic com- pression, resulting in a complex sediment compaction mechanism (Hauser et al. 2014). Figs. 2a and b show the cross section of the Sundaland continental margin in NW Borneo and East Borneo, respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Regional cross sections of basins in Sundaland continental margin running perpendicular to the basin axis from shallow to deepwater regions (Fig. 1 shows section locations): a) NW Borneo (modified from Hesse et al. 2009) and b) East Borneo (modified from Guritno et al. 2003) show fold-thrust belt in deepwater environments. A and B in Fig. 2a are individual thrust-related fold structures, where A is a structure with drape sediments, indicating more intensive vertical loading or extensional stress conditions above the fold, and B is a structure without a drape sediment, indicating more intensive local compressional stress without significant vertical sediment loading. The red line in (b) shows the top of overpressure; note that the top of overpressure in shallow water region (c) is commonly found at great depths because of the course-grained sediments domination that supports high permeability system, where the deepwater region (d) normally has a shallow top of overpressure caused by fine-grained domination that promotes a low permeability system</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Regional cross sections of basins in Sundaland continental margin running perpendicular to the basin axis from shallow to deepwater regions (<link href="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-1">Fig. 1</link> shows section locations): a) NW Borneo (modified from Hesse et al. 2009) and b) East Borneo (modified from Guritno et al. 2003) show fold-thrust belt in deepwater environments. A and B in <link href="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-2">Fig. 2a</link> are individual thrust-related fold structures, where A is a structure with drape sediments, indicating more intensive vertical loading or extensional stress conditions above the fold, and B is a structure without a drape sediment, indicating more intensive local compressional stress without significant vertical sediment loading. The red line in (b) shows the top of overpressure; note that the top of overpressure in shallow water region (c) is commonly found at great depths because of the course-grained sediments domination that supports high permeability system, where the deepwater region (d) normally has a shallow top of overpressure caused by fine-grained domination that promotes a low permeability system</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">However, the top of overpressure is very shallow and often very close to the mudline. From a drilling perspective, the rate of pressure increase along the transition zone (i.e., from normal pressure to overpressure) is considered gradual with less probability of drilling surprises. However, the thick water column in the deepwater area reduces overburden stress and fracture gradient, leading to a narrow drilling window. As a result, the combination of the thick water column and early top of overpressure leads to a consistently narrow drilling window throughout the well section, requiring more frequent casing strings to maintain borehole integrity (Saleh and Shaker 2001; Fig. 3).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Impact of water column thickness on the number of casing strings; thicker water column causes a greater number of casing strings (right). Modified after Swarbrick (2012)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Impact of water column thickness on the number of casing strings; thicker water column causes a greater number of casing strings (right). Modified after Swarbrick (2012)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">When measuring NCT from velocity or transit time data, the authors do not hold to the idea that NCT physically follows semi-log trend (direct exponential method) as proposed by several workers in the early days (Hottman and Johnson 1965; Magara 1968). A great number of compaction trends have been analyzed both in the shallow water and shallow part of deepwater of the study areas to prove the approach of matrix velocity-controlled exponential trends (Chapman 1983; Bell 2002; Miller 2002; Zhang 2011) following the assumption that compaction is mechanical, the sediments are young, and an overpressure mechanism is disequilibrium compaction (Swarbrick 2001). Fig. 4 presents some representatives of sonic velocity-based NCTs in Sundaland continental margin basins; this data supports the matrix velocity-controlled exponential trend.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Collection of shallow water Normal Compaction Trends from Northwest Borneo and East Borneo basins using matrix velocity-controlled exponential trend method</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Collection of shallow water Normal Compaction Trends from Northwest Borneo and East Borneo basins using matrix velocity-controlled exponential trend method</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Unfortunately, in some cases, this assumption fails (Swarbrick 2001) and is much more pertinent in deepwater contractional areas, such as in DSCM (Kaeng et al. 2014). Figs. 5 and 6 illustrate how such an approach can create confusion. Pressure plots from three offset wells in a deepwater anticlinal structure are presented. An exploration well (DW-1) penetrates the crest of the structure, while appraisal wells DW-2 and DW-3 are on the flanks. The three wells penetrate a big deepwater toe thrusting-related anticlinal structure with similar stratigraphic sequence top to bottom. The distance between one well and the closest neighbor is approximately 3 km. In this case, it can be observed that an attempt to match the predicted PP (shale) to measured pressure (sands) will result in uncertainty of as much as a 2-Eaton exponent unit difference (Fig 5). In common practice, a 2-Eaton exponent unit difference represents a significant variation in pressure regime, which is obviously not the case here. From a drilling perspective, the impact to well planning is that the mud weight used to drill DW-1 (highest structure) is 1.3 lbm/gal higher than DW-3 (lowest structure), resulting in a two-casing string difference between DW-1 (five casings) and DW-3 (three casings) for a similar depth interval.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Three wells (DW-1, DW-2, and DW-3) in DW field, an example of deepwater field in SE Asia. The field is a large four-way structure formed by a deepwater thrusting system. DW-1 penetrates the crest of the anticline while DW-2 and DW-3 on the flanks. The distance between one well and the closest neighbor is approximately 3 km; (a) is the structure contour of top SS3 sand; (b) is a cartoon of seismic section showing the structural cross section of the top SS3 sand layer</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Three wells (DW-1, DW-2, and DW-3) in DW field, an example of deepwater field in SE Asia. The field is a large four-way structure formed by a deepwater thrusting system. DW-1 penetrates the crest of the anticline while DW-2 and DW-3 on the flanks. The distance between one well and the closest neighbor is approximately 3 km; (a) is the structure contour of top SS3 sand; (b) is a cartoon of seismic section showing the structural cross section of the top SS3 sand layer</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Unfortunately, in some cases, this assumption fails (Swarbrick 2001) and is much more pertinent in deepwater contractional areas, such as in DSCM (Kaeng et al. 2014). Figs. 5 and 6 illustrate how such an approach can create confusion. Pressure plots from three offset wells in a deepwater anticlinal structure are presented. An exploration well (DW-1) penetrates the crest of the structure, while appraisal wells DW-2 and DW-3 are on the flanks. The three wells penetrate a big deepwater toe thrusting-related anticlinal structure with similar stratigraphic sequence top to bottom. The distance between one well and the closest neighbor is approximately 3 km. In this case, it can be observed that an attempt to match the predicted PP (shale) to measured pressure (sands) will result in uncertainty of as much as a 2-Eaton exponent unit difference (Fig 5). In common practice, a 2-Eaton exponent unit difference represents a significant variation in pressure regime, which is obviously not the case here. From a drilling perspective, the impact to well planning is that the mud weight used to drill DW-1 (highest structure) is 1.3 lbm/gal higher than DW-3 (lowest structure), resulting in a two-casing string difference between DW-1 (five casings) and DW-3 (three casings) for a similar depth interval.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Predicted field shale PP using an empirical Eaton formula (Eaton 1975) from the three offset wells (DW-1, DW-2, and DW-3). The shaded area is the uncertainty window of predicted PPs as calibrated to measured pressures. The uncertainty window is underlain by the low case predicted PP with Eaton exponent (e) = 2 as calibrated to the lowest measured pressure points, and overlain by the high case predicted PP with Eaton exponent (e) = 4 as calibrated to the highest measured pressure points. In common practice, an Eaton exponent unit difference as much as 2 represents a significant variation in pressure regimes, which is not likely in this case. This is an example of how pressures in shale (predicted) and sands (measured) can be significantly different; thus, an attempt to calibrate shale pressure to measured pressures in sands or predicting sands pressure from shale pressure could be misleading</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Predicted field shale PP using an empirical Eaton formula (Eaton 1975) from the three offset wells (DW-1, DW-2, and DW-3). The shaded area is the uncertainty window of predicted PPs as calibrated to measured pressures. The uncertainty window is underlain by the low case predicted PP with Eaton exponent (e) = 2 as calibrated to the lowest measured pressure points, and overlain by the high case predicted PP with Eaton exponent (e) = 4 as calibrated to the highest measured pressure points. In common practice, an Eaton exponent unit difference as much as 2 represents a significant variation in pressure regimes, which is not likely in this case. This is an example of how pressures in shale (predicted) and sands (measured) can be significantly different; thus, an attempt to calibrate shale pressure to measured pressures in sands or predicting sands pressure from shale pressure could be misleading</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">As previously described, one common challenge that occurs in deepwater wells is that the top of overpressure is commonly shallow (Fig. 7) and close to the mud-line because of typical high sedimen- tation rates coupled with the dominance of very fine-grained, low-permeability lithology. When the shallow section shows some decline in porosity, it can be mistaken for a normally pressured section; in this case, conventional porosity-based techniques will underestimate the PP.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Overburden-derived NCT from Eq. 5</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Overburden-derived NCT from Eq. 5</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Fig. 8 shows how the velocity-effective stress method as described fails to match the measured pressure. The Eaton (1975) PP prediction method combined with Miller NCT shows significant underprediction at greater depths. At this well, sonic velocity data and the interpreted NCT are presented. The sonic velocity data shows the trend of constant decrease, indicating that compaction (porosity loss) has happened even though at a rate slower than the normal trend. To adhere to the theory of porosity-effective stress mechanical compaction, the resulting PP should follow the PP curve in Fig. 9. Pressure mismatch between interpreted and measured pressures must have happened because the overpressure mechanism does not follow the rule of mechanical compaction.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>PP from velocity-effective stress method fails to match with the measured pressures and exhibit huge discrepancy (FG= fracture pressure gradient, OB= overburden stress)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>PP from velocity-effective stress method fails to match with the measured pressures and exhibit huge discrepancy (FG= fracture pressure gradient, OB= overburden stress)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Fig. 8 shows how the velocity-effective stress method as described fails to match the measured pressure. The Eaton (1975) PP prediction method combined with Miller NCT shows significant underprediction at greater depths. At this well, sonic velocity data and the interpreted NCT are presented. The sonic velocity data shows the trend of constant decrease, indicating that compaction (porosity loss) has happened even though at a rate slower than the normal trend. To adhere to the theory of porosity-effective stress mechanical compaction, the resulting PP should follow the PP curve in Fig. 9. Pressure mismatch between interpreted and measured pressures must have happened because the overpressure mechanism does not follow the rule of mechanical compaction.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Final interpretation of the field-wide shale PP in the DW field. Note how the sonic velocity is anomalously decreasing while the PP keeps increasing. Miller NCT is used to calculate the PP above 3800 m where vertical loading is still taking place and semilog NCT is used below 3800 m. The shaded region is interpreted as the effect of undrained tectonic stress effect. It is interpreted as one of two major reasons (along with centroid effect) why many velocity-based predictions in DSCM underpredict PP</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Final interpretation of the field-wide shale PP in the DW field. Note how the sonic velocity is anomalously decreasing while the PP keeps increasing. Miller NCT is used to calculate the PP above 3800 m where vertical loading is still taking place and semilog NCT is used below 3800 m. The shaded region is interpreted as the effect of undrained tectonic stress effect. It is interpreted as one of two major reasons (along with centroid effect) why many velocity-based predictions in DSCM underpredict PP</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Fig. 10 shows the stress path resulted from tectonic shearing where velocity remains constant or increasing with the departure of the effective stress path left from the normal trend. The tectonic shearing stress path is bounded by the upper bound of unloading curve and the normal curve.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>(a) Velocity vs. vertical effective stress plot of DW field showing the stress path for undrained tectonic stress mechanism; (b) conceptual drawing of the stress path in a velocity vs. vertical effective stress plot</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>(a) Velocity vs. vertical effective stress plot of DW field showing the stress path for undrained tectonic stress mechanism; (b) conceptual drawing of the stress path in a velocity vs. vertical effective stress plot</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">It is believed that, in overpressured zones, a pressure difference in sand and shale is not uncommon in the presence of structural inclination (Traugott 1997; Heppard and Traugott 1998; Yardley and Swabrick 2000; Shaker 2005; Saleh and Shaker 2001). Disequilibrium compaction in shale-dominated basins tends to cause overpressure to increase with depth and the resultant pressure profile is often subparallel to the lithostatic gradient (Yardley and Swarbrick 2000). Therefore, deep isolated reservoirs tend to be more overpressured than shallower reservoirs (Fig. 11a). Where laterally extensive inclined reservoirs exist, deeper highly overpressured regions are connected to shallower, less overpressured regions by porous and permeable pathways. The redistribution of overpressure throughout the volume of such reservoir incline along a water gradient and can cause PP at the crest of a structure to increase (Fig. 11b). This phenomenon is larger if hydrocarbon is present because of buoyancy. The depth where the PP in a reservoir and the bounding shale are in equilibrium, as illustrated in Fig. 10, is termed centroid (Traugott 1997).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>a) Pressure-depth plot showing the centroid effect (after Heppard and Traugott 2002); b) the location of centroid in heterofluid-filled reservoir; note that the centroid is located at the midpoint of the water-filled part of the reservoir body</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>a) Pressure-depth plot showing the centroid effect (after Heppard and Traugott 2002); b) the location of centroid in heterofluid-filled reservoir; note that the centroid is located at the midpoint of the water-filled part of the reservoir body</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="16" figure-order="12" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">Fig. 12 shows the complete interpretation of sonic and velocity-based PP profiles in the DW field with noticeable centroid effect. It can be seen that the PP in the inclined reservoirs increases at fluid rate with increasing depth, whereas the shale pressure increases at an overburden rate.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Field shale PP interpretation from sonic velocity in Fig. 8</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Field shale PP interpretation from sonic velocity in <link href="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-8">Fig. 8</link>
</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="17" figure-order="13" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">At the crest of the structures, the PP of the sand is higher than the bounding shale, suggesting that the DW-1 Well penetrated above the centroid. Down at the structural flanks, as penetrated by the DW-3 Well, the PP of the sand is lower than the bounding shale. The DW-1 Well reached total depth (TD) at the base of SS3 sand and encountered 160 m apparent (vertical) thickness. The centroid model suggests that, if the well would penetrate a deeper reservoir with approximately similar thickness, the well would have no drilling window. Hence, the decision to set TD at the base of the SS3 sand was accurate. DW-2 is an appraisal well to test the lateral continuity of sands observed in DW-1 and target deeper seismic reflectors that were not penetrated by DW-1. Because of its position on the structure flank close to centroid, DW-2 had been a good choice for deeper drilling. Fig. 13 shows a definitive field shale PP and taking into account the centroid location at the midpoint of water column.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118176345MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118176345MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Definitive field shale PP interpretation taking into account centroid location at the water volumetric</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Definitive field shale PP interpretation taking into account centroid location at the water volumetric</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>