<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118189072MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-29T11:48:07Z">
<doi>10.2118/189072-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/189072-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The BANA001T penetrated the Z1000B and based on the petrophysical data acquired from the well (sidewall samples, Gamma Ray (GR) log, resistivity logs, etc), the reservoir was interpreted to be completely oil bearing (Figure 1). On the basis of this interpretation, an original in-place volume was determined for the reservoir and future developmental opportunities were established.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Z1000 Horizon map showing the initial interpretation of the reservoir based on BANA-001T and the proposed location for BANA-002T.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Z1000 Horizon map showing the initial interpretation of the reservoir based on BANA-001T and the proposed location for BANA-002T.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Scenario Generation: Post conceptualizing the data review/analysis in step 1, scenarios are created to enable the integration of wide range of possibilities. See Flowchart in Figure 2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Flowchart showing Different Scenarios Analysed for the Z1000B reservoir.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Flowchart showing Different Scenarios Analysed for the Z1000B reservoir.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Density log was also acquired from the well and based on the response observed on the density log, little or no confidence was vested on the ‘no show’ seen in the sidewall sample as indicative of the presence of gas, as it is believed that the density log response is affected by gas especially in a well-developed sand like Z1000B in BANA001T. However, in this case the density log suggests the presence of one-hydrocarbon fluid system, hence, the reservoir was interpreted as being fully oil bearing (Figure 3). Based on the analysis below, the contacts interpreted were an oil up-to (OUT) at 7761 ftss, oil down-to (ODT) at 7790 ftss and water up-to (WUT) at 7796 ftss.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>BANA001T Petrophysical data log showing the initial interpretation of Z1000B reservoir.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>BANA001T Petrophysical data log showing the initial interpretation of Z1000B reservoir.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Z1000B in BANA002T was identified as hydrocarbon bearing using the resistivity log. Fluid gradient from pressure-depth plot (Figure 4) was used for hydrocarbon differentiation and also for fluid contact analysis. Based on integration of petrophysical log and formation pressure data, the reservoir was interpreted as an oil reservoir with a gas cap. The contact interpreted for the well was a gas-oil contact (GOC) at 7763 ftss and an ODT at 7795 ftss.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>BANA002T Z1000B pressure-depth plot.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>BANA002T Z1000B pressure-depth plot.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">An analysis was carried out on the production performance from BANA001T. BANA001T has had a cumulative production of 30 years from the Z1000B reservoir which is sufficient to allow for a credible performance analysis. Figure 5 shows the performance profile of the well. The cumulative oil production from the well is 2.8 MMstb with a cumulative gas production of 1.9 Bscf. This gives a value of 686 scf/stb of cumulative gas-oil ratio, this value when compared with the initial solution gas-oil ratio (Rsi) of 830 scf/stb indicates that the gas production from the well is essentially from the solution gas in place.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>BANA001T Historical Production Performance Plot</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>BANA001T Historical Production Performance Plot</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">The historical pressure trend (Figure 6) indicates a pressure decline of less than two (2) percent from the initial giving suggestion of very good pressure support. This is believed to be as a result of the strong aquifer support associated with the Bana field which has been seen in many of the reservoirs in this field. With the strong pressure support in the reservoir, it is believed that the original gas-oil contact may not have expanded due to pressure depletion. This is supported by other reservoirs in this field with the same level of pressure depletion where we have seen no expansion in the gas cap as a result of production or pressure depletion.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>BANA001T Historical Pressure Trend (all pressures referenced to a datum depth of 7763 ftss)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>BANA001T Historical Pressure Trend (all pressures referenced to a datum depth of 7763 ftss)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">With an initial reservoir pressure defined as being equal to the bubble point pressure, gas came out of solution immediately production started. A secondary gas cap was created and as at the time of the drilling of BANA002T, the present gas-oil contact was at 7723 ftss and therefore unable to replicate the results from BANA002T pressure-depth analysis. This is the most unlikely of the scenarios, as the model could not achieve the evaluated depth. Albeit, the size of the gas cap could not have been created by the formation of a secondary gas cap which this scenario implies. This scenario was therefore discarded as a possibility. Its results are captured in Figure 7.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Scenario A Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7723 ftss)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Scenario A Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7723 ftss)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">With an original gas-oil contact at 7761 ftss, the result from this scenario gave a gas-oil contact of 7763 ftss which was in line with the results from BANA002T. This indicated a gas cap expansion of approximately 2 feet which was seen to be within the error margin for the measured data of BANA002T. It was considered as the possible original gas-oil contact. Its results are captured in Figure 8.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Scenario B Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7763 ftss)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Scenario B Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7763 ftss)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">The assumption that the OGOC had not expanded and therefore was at 7763 ftss as seen by BANA002T gave a result from the modelling which shows that the estimated gas-oil contact as at the time of drilling BANA002T is at 7765 ftss. This was also considered as a possible case for the original gas-oil contact. Its results are shown in Figure 9.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Scenario C Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7765 ftss)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Scenario C Material Balance Modelling Results (PGOC at 7765 ftss)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">This ‘no show’ is indicative of the presence of gas, however, the density log was used as a more compelling reason to displace the interpretation of gas. Integrating the results from the petrophysical evaluation (sidewall samples, well logs, formation pressure data) and the dynamic understanding and behaviour, the scenario C (original gas-oil contact at 7763 ftss) was selected as being more realistic as it supports all available data including BANA001T ‘no show’ result (Figure 10).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118189072MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118189072MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>BANA001T and BANA002T Petrophysical Data Log Showing Fluid distribution in Z1000B post review.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>BANA001T and BANA002T Petrophysical Data Log Showing Fluid distribution in Z1000B post review.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>