<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118182040MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-24T16:27:01Z">
<doi>10.2118/182040-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/182040-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">M reservoir is a giant marine sandstone reservoir, which has a nearly symmetric anticline structure with no faults inside. It has two stable shale compartment layers, therefore it can be divided into three sections (figure 1). The quantity of interlayers is gradually increased from south to north, and the reservoir properties in the north are poorer than that of the south. M reservoir is a massive sandstone reservoir with thin shale interlayers. The average thickness of reservoir is more than 100 meters. Sandstone are brown, fine-medium grained, sub-rounded, well-sorted, high porosity, with high net-gross ratio.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Well logs and zonation of a typical well in M reservoir</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well logs and zonation of a typical well in M reservoir</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">M reservoir has a unified original oil-water contact. For its AB zone, including A and B two layers, is lateral developed through the whole field with thickness of 4 ~ 7 m. Since the two layers are thin, they are generally analyzed as AB-layer. For its DJ zone, including 6 layers: D, E, F, G, H, J, whose layers have a large and stable thickness, and widely lateral distributed. For its LN zone, containing L, M, N three small layers, also shows a large and stable sand thickness. A west-east well section profile of M reservoir is shown in figure 2. As can be seen from the figure, two stable barriers are between the AB, DJ and LN zone, so the reservoir is divided into three oil-water systems. The heterogeneity of the three zones will inevitably lead to interference between layers during development.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>The west-east well section profile of M reservoir</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>The west-east well section profile of M reservoir</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">The left map of figure 3 shows the distribution of saturation logging wells in each year in a specific area of M reservoir. The test point distribution is similar in other regions. Therefore saturation logs have almost covered the full-field area and most of the wells of M reservoir, only the west and east flank area are not well-controlled and lack of saturation logging data. In general, through the analysis of current saturation logging data, it can quite accurately describe the remaining oil distribution of M reservoir.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>The location of saturation logs in a specific area of M reservoir (left map) and relationship between saturation logs and PLT of a typical well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>The location of saturation logs in a specific area of M reservoir (left map) and relationship between saturation logs and PLT of a typical well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="4" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The saturation logging started test in 2010 with a large amount. And the study firstly collected the surveillance data of M reservoir in 2012 and thereafter updated the results annually from 2012 to 2015. Based on surveillance data, the distribution maps of remaining oil saturation are generated year by year. The whole process of remaining oil characterization mainly utilizes saturation logs, PLT data, new well logs and dynamic production data. The specific workflow of the remaining oil characterization is shown in figure 4.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Workflow of remaining oil characterization through surveillance data analysis</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Workflow of remaining oil characterization through surveillance data analysis</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">The following illustrate a specific example to analyze the pure oil thickness mapping which are generated and constrained by saturation logs, PLT tests, and new well logs. Figure 5 shows the pure oil thickness distribution of a specific area in layer G from year 2012 to 2015. As can be seen from the figure, with continuing production of the reservoir, the edge of the pure oil thickness gradually becomes smaller and thinner, and the level of water flooded status grows. Overall, as the pure oil thickness only counts the area where the oil saturation is greater than 0.6, the changes of it in recent years are not that significant when the injection-production relationship has not changed during the time.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>the pure oil thickness maps of a specific area in layer G between 2012 and 2015</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>the pure oil thickness maps of a specific area in layer G between 2012 and 2015</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="4" pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Similarly, Figure 6 shows an example of remaining oil saturation distribution in a specific area of layer A from year 2012 to 2015. Comparing with the changes of pure oil thickness in Figure 5, the changes of oil saturation distribution are a little bit obvious from year to year. The oil saturation is clearly decreasing and the border of enrichment area is changing from year 2012 to 2014. Due to the low production from this aera in 2015, the oil saturation change in this year is insignificant.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>The oil saturation distribution of a specific area in layer A from 2012 to 2015</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>The oil saturation distribution of a specific area in layer A from 2012 to 2015</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-6a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_6a.tif" id="ImgLink-6a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2012</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-6b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_6b.tif" id="ImgLink-6b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2013</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-6c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_6c.tif" id="ImgLink-6c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2014</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-6d">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_6d.tif" id="ImgLink-6d" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2015</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="4" pdf-page="10" figure-order="7" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Following the proposed methodology of remaining oil characterization, the three-dimensional remaining oil distribution can also be characterized. Figure 7 shows a west-east profile of oil saturation in the north M reservoir from year 2012 to 2015. As M reservoir belongs to typical structured reservoir, and mainly relies on natural aquifer support and peripheral water injection, the edge water and injected water are gradually invading from the bottom to top, from edge to crest. The water flooded status in the bottom and the edge of M reservoir are significantly heavier than that of the higher positions and crest areas. Overall, the remaining oil are mostly concentrated in the high crest areas.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>The west-east profile of oil saturation in the north M reservoir</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>The west-east profile of oil saturation in the north M reservoir</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-7a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_7a.tif" id="ImgLink-7a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2012</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-7b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_7b.tif" id="ImgLink-7b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2013</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-7c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_7c.tif" id="ImgLink-7c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2014</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-7d">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_7d.tif" id="ImgLink-7d" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>2015</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="8" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Combined the understanding of static and dynamic characterization with comparing the migrations and changes of remaining oil from year to year, the impacts of different controlling factors on remaining oil distribution and its migration characteristics are determined. Besides, with a combination of well production data, the exploitation potential of different types' remaining oil located in different positions are determined and the development methods are proposed correspondingly (Figure 8). There are mainly 6 controlling factors: crest area, shale, barriers, injection-production contradictions, poor reservoir properties, and the area outside the peripheral injectors.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118182040MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118182040MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>The distribution characteristic, migration characteristic, and development strategy recommendation of remaining oil under different controlling factors</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>The distribution characteristic, migration characteristic, and development strategy recommendation of remaining oil under different controlling factors</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>