<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118185382MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-25T10:58:39Z">
<doi>10.2118/185382-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/185382-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="3" pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The fluvial sandstones of the Fatehgarh Formation of Paleocene age are the principle reservoirs and these facies are further sub-divided into five sub-units FB-1 to FB-5 downwards. Younger reservoir units were deposited by braided and meandering channels while the older units are dominated by multistorey braided channel facies. The upper two units of the Fatehgarh Formation contain more than 90% of the in-place hydrocarbons and dominate oil production. The upper unit, deposited in a meandering fluvial environment, displays the greatest heterogeneity. A type log, analogue environment of deposition (EOD) and cross section across Fatehgarh reservoir in Bhagyam Field is shown in Fig.1.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Bhagyam Type log, analogue EOD and cross section</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Bhagyam Type log, analogue EOD and cross section</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-1a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_1a.tif" id="ImgLink-1a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-1b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_1b.tif" id="ImgLink-1b" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-1c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_1c.tif" id="ImgLink-1c" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">During drilling of development wells, the net pay encountered by the FDP wells was, on average, better than prognosed, confirming the excellent development of reservoirs in the Upper and Lower Fatehgarh. The high oil saturations were further confirmed by Dean Stark measurements on multiple core analyses. However, when the wells were brought online, the well productivities were much lower than predicted. Initially heavy well bore damage, due to long exposure to kill fluid and sand screens, was suspected. However, after pressure build up data was gathered in the producers, it was apparent that reservoir transmissibility was much lower. Lower transmissibility was the main reason for the observed productivity deficit relative to the prediction. There is almost 2 order of magnitude difference between core and well test permeabilities in the oil zone as shown in Fig.2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Nearly two order of magnitude diference in core permeability</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Nearly two order of magnitude diference in core permeability</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Despite the new model, actual water production outstripped predictions. Most of the new wells (&#x003E;50%) coming online with moderate to high water cut. The high starting water cut in many of these wells was in spite of high resistivity, indicating high oil saturations, shown in open-hole logs. Repeat Formation Tester (RFT) data acquired in development wells and showed variable sweep and depletion across the sand intervals. The Upper Fatehgarh sands are composed of a number of sub-sands. These sub-sands are very difficult to correlate across the field or even in small sectors. However, as can be seen in RFT of B-Well A and B-Well B (Fig.3), the sub sands in FB-1 have variable levels of depletion, which is an indication of heterogeneity.and sweep.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>RFT data showing variable depletion across sand layers</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>RFT data showing variable depletion across sand layers</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>B-Well A RDT Survey</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>B-Well B RDT Survey</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">The fractional flow characteristics of the system (Fig.4) show that very high water cuts can develop at fairly low water saturation (Sw). This, coupled with the high oil sand resistivity and sand-shale alternations, makes assessment of the small increases in water saturation on induction-based resistivity logging tools difficult. The time lapse RST in Well C is another point in case where variable sweep is seen across FB-1 sub sands.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>RST logs indicate variable water break through across the sand intervals, fractional flow charcacteristics show that high water cuts can develop at very low oil saturations due to poor displacmnt mobility ratio</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>RST logs indicate variable water break through across the sand intervals, fractional flow charcacteristics show that high water cuts can develop at very low oil saturations due to poor displacmnt mobility ratio</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-4a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_4a.tif" id="ImgLink-4a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-4b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_4b.tif" id="ImgLink-4b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">The historical field permormance shows that after start of production in 2012 with an initial rate of 15,000 bopd; the field attained production of ~25,000 bopd. After the completion of development drilling activities, the field oil production rate strated declining. The field behavior with declining producing well count also deviated from the model expectations. Despite shutting the highest water cut wells, the field water oil ratio (WOR) continued to rise at much the same rate as before. It was obvious that water mobility of the system is very high and water is quickly finding its way to the nearest open producer. The field performance plot is shown in Fig 5.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Field performance plot</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Field performance plot</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Despite the efforts, maintaining field production under water flood has been a challenge. Chemical EOR schemes have been identified as suitable for the field. Medium oil viscosity, high reservoir permeability, high initial oil saturation, low reservoir temperature, low connate water salinity and shallow depths make it an ideal polymer flood candidate. This was recognized very early in the field life. Core floods supported this view and laboratory tests show polymer flood yields nearly 27% recovery over waterflood. Based on this, a polymer flood plan was proposed for the field. To derisk the full field polymer flood, a single well polymer injectivity test was planned in 2015. This was followed by a 4 well injectivity test in 2016, where 4 existing producers were converted to polymer injectors. Anaerobic sampling of polymer was done through special samplers (Fig.6) with chemical stabilizers and backed up with online viscometers and glove box measurements.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118185382MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118185382MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Special samples deployed for polymer</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Special samples deployed for polymer</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>