<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118183099MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T10:15:53Z">
<doi>10.2118/183099-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/183099-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The Nong Yao Field is in the Narathiwat Ridge, between the southern tip of the Pattani Basin and the northern tip of the North Malay Basin. The field is formed by a shallow, low relief structure and is comprised of amalgamated stacked channels of Late Miocene age. It was discovered by the Nong Yao-1 exploration well in 2009 (Figure 1) and production commenced in June 2015.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Nong Yao Field location map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Nong Yao Field location map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">An excellent example of well sequencing and innovative use of pressure measurements is observed in the drilling of well D13 from the southern platform (Figure 2). This well was one of the last wells drilled in this part of the field and its primary objective was as an injector into a deeper water bearing sand where aquifer support was known to be poor. However, well D13 was also designed so that it penetrated the shallower water bearing sand shown in Figure 2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Formation pressures were acquired in well D13 after 11 days of production from wells D11 and D12 to determine if the injection well to the south was required for aquifer support</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Formation pressures were acquired in well D13 after 11 days of production from wells D11 and D12 to determine if the injection well to the south was required for aquifer support</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">The subsurface and drilling teams were able to collaborate and design wells with complex trajectories which could not have been drilled with previous tools. The high build rate rotary steerable system had 100% success at drilling the planned well paths in the Nong Yao drilling campaign and allowed for maximum collection of appraisal data from shallower objectives. An example of a complex well plan and the actual drilled well path is shown in Figure 3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Planned (blue) and actual (red) well paths for a Nong Yao well. This well required high DLS (max DLS 7.05deg/100ft) to achieve the multiple appraisal objectives</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Planned (blue) and actual (red) well paths for a Nong Yao well. This well required high DLS (max DLS 7.05deg/100ft) to achieve the multiple appraisal objectives</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">The final drilling sequence for the northern platform is shown in Figure 4. The first well drilled from the platform (D1) was a pilot hole which would be converted to a water source well or a deviated producer depending on whether the water source was required for injection. D1 was a key appraisal well testing six prospective targets and discovering hydrocarbons in four of them, including the deep K reservoir, a sand in which hydrocarbons had not previously been encountered.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Nong Yao drilling sequence for the northern platform. Production wells were designed to test multiple shallow appraisal targets above the primary objectives</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Nong Yao drilling sequence for the northern platform. Production wells were designed to test multiple shallow appraisal targets above the primary objectives</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">An excellent example of how the appraisal while drilling affected the development of a key reservoir is demonstrated in Figure 5, which illustrates an AI extraction from the D interval within the Nong Yao Field. At Nong Yao, sands typically have low acoustic impedance (green/yellow/red colours) whilst shales have high impedance (blue/purple colours). Hydrocarbon bearing sands will have even lower impedances than wet sands. This key reservoir was originally penetrated by three exploration/appraisal wells in this area.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>After the exploration discovery E3, wells D1 (wet), D2 (gas), D4 (oil) and D5 (oil) appraised similar seismic amplitudes to the north leading to the successful drilling of the horizontal production well D8</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>After the exploration discovery E3, wells D1 (wet), D2 (gas), D4 (oil) and D5 (oil) appraised similar seismic amplitudes to the north leading to the successful drilling of the horizontal production well D8</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">An example of how the deep resistivity distance to boundary LWD tool was used at Nong Yao can be seen in the C reservoir. In an offset well penetrating this reservoir, the oil pay is thin (approximately 8-10ft TVT) and the upper part of the sand where the pay is found is fairly poor quality. This leads to a low resistivity contrast between the pay sand and the overlying shale. Figure 6 illustrates the resistivity and gamma ray profiles of the C reservoir in a nearby offset well.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Offset well showing well log properties and signature of C sand reservoir</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Offset well showing well log properties and signature of C sand reservoir</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">A real-time inversion provides valuable information on the boundary distance to the wellbore which can be used to geosteer the well confidently and precisely. The distance to boundary inversion was used for the entire horizontal interval of the Nong Yao development well shown in Figure 7. The well, which was drilled updip of the offset well, entered the sand at 5500m MD and was immediately steered down as the real time inversion indicated that the top sand was dipping down.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Entire horizontal section with Deep Resistivity Distance to Boundary LWD inversion</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Entire horizontal section with Deep Resistivity Distance to Boundary LWD inversion</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">This tool uses ultra-deep azimuthal electromagnetic propagation measurements and through a complex inversion can map resistivity contrasts and therefore formation boundaries at a distance of up to 120ft TVD (Figure 8). This deep mapping can help to detect boundaries well before the drill bit enters the formation, which enables the depth uncertainty of formation tops to be reduced in real-time to optimize the landing point.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Ultra deep azimuthal resistivity tool</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Ultra deep azimuthal resistivity tool</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">An example of the utilization of this technology is shown in Figure 9. Exploration well E1 encountered oil in a good quality 20ft sand and a similar looking target was identified on the eastern side of a large fault. This target was interpreted to be a younger sand that was downthrown by the fault to juxtapose against the oil discovery at E1. Unfortunately this easterly fault block contained no wells and so there was significant uncertainty on structure, fluids and contacts.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Well D1 was landed without first drilling a pilot hole, instead using the ultra-deep resistivity tool to look ahead of the bit. The ultra-deep azimuthal inversion identified that the formation was 20ft deeper than prognosed allowing the well to drop rather than following the original proposed well path in pink.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well D1 was landed without first drilling a pilot hole, instead using the ultra-deep resistivity tool to look ahead of the bit. The ultra-deep azimuthal inversion identified that the formation was 20ft deeper than prognosed allowing the well to drop rather than following the original proposed well path in pink.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">This careful pre-planning allowed the landing of development well D1 successfully without the need for a pilot hole as shown in Figure 10. The ultra-deep azimuthal resistivity inversion first mapped the top reservoir at 7161ft MD, at a depth of approximately 45ft TVD below the well path. The detection range was 5ft TVD greater than the pre-job modelling indicated.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118183099MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118183099MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>The ultra-deep azimuthal resistivity inversion accurately mapped the top of the sand 45ft above it.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>The ultra-deep azimuthal resistivity inversion accurately mapped the top of the sand 45ft above it.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>