<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190369MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T19:51:30Z">
<doi>10.2118/190369-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190369-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">In solubilisation efficiency tests, the surfactant solution and crude oil were shaken together at room temperature in special laboratory equipment (Fig. 1). After a certain rest time, and following separation of the phases the volumes of the formed phases were measured. After 24 hours storage at reservoir temperature, the volumes of phases were repeatedly determined. The amounts of aqueous phase, emulsion and oil are determined like comparing to the total liquid volume. The solubilisation efficiency could be analyzed concerning the different effect of the surfactant mixture on the type of emulsions usually formed in the natural reservoir by the native phases.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Special laboratory equipment used for measuring the solubilisation efficiency of surfactants</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Special laboratory equipment used for measuring the solubilisation efficiency of surfactants</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Usually, actual interfacial tension between efficient surfactant mixtures and oil was around 10-2 mN/m as it is shown with green line in Fig. 2. Thus, the characteristic IFT is 3,500 times lower than the original IFT between the brine and oil phases, viz. that value is quite comparable with data published in literature. That minimum value of IFT was obtained at 0.5 g/l surfactant concentration whereas the maximum IFT lowering value was often measured at 0.1 g/l.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Synergetic IFT effect observed in two-component surfactant mixture and surfactantpolymer mixtures in contrast to single-component surfactant solutions at brine/crude oil interfaces</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Synergetic IFT effect observed in two-component surfactant mixture and surfactantpolymer mixtures in contrast to single-component surfactant solutions at brine/crude oil interfaces</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">A positive, structure-strengthening effect could be observed not only in polymer solutions, but in surfactant/polymer solutions also. The presence of polymer plays a predominant effect of internal structure of systems and therefore, the viscoelastic character of displacing fluid may have beneficial effect on displacement efficiency too. The thermal stability of the selected surfactant/polymer solutions could also be checked by measuring the change of viscosity of solution in time. Probably some segments of polymer chains may degrade at high temperature resulting in decreased viscosity. Surprisingly, in contrast to this fundamental prediction, the fact is that the viscosity of tested surfactant/polymer solution significantly increased as shown in Fig. 3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Alteration in viscosity of surfactant/polymer solution in thermal stability test</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Alteration in viscosity of surfactant/polymer solution in thermal stability test</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The tests were performed in a long core displacement apparatus (see Fig. 4).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Long core displacement apparatus used for optimization of the injection technology</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Long core displacement apparatus used for optimization of the injection technology</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">The flow and displacement tests were carried out at constant injection rate, which corresponded to 20-60 cm/day linear front rate in the cores. This flow rate is modelling the flow of fluids moving from injection wells towards production wells in the reservoir. The effluent samples were collected in volume of 10-50 cm3 depending on the length of the cores. The oil content was determined in each sample breaking the emulsions if they existed. Special mathematical procedure was used to calculate the total incremental oil volume and the recovery efficiency during the core-flooding test. The results of a typical core-flooding test are shown in Fig. 5.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Changes in displacement efficiency (ΔE<sub>D</sub>) during core flooding test</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Changes in displacement efficiency (ΔE<sub>D</sub>) during core flooding test</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="6" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">This process was followed by modelling the pilot area for injectivity test (Figure 6) using the results of the 3D reservoir geologic model and production data of existing wells.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Full field geologic model of Algyo-2 reservoir and selected pilot area</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Full field geologic model of Algyo-2 reservoir and selected pilot area</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="7" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">The well was first tested with KCl injection as a pre-treatment to control clay swelling near the bore zone to improve the injectivity of the former production well. Then it was shut in until the injection of surfactant/polymer solution. The injection started with 100 m3/d water injection and then the chemical solution containing 15,000 ppm surfactant and 1,000 ppm polymer was continuously injected into the well from 30th September through 25th October, 2013. In this period 2,000 m3 surfactant/polymer solution with 12-15 mPa s viscosity was injected into the reservoir. In the final stage, the chemical solution was driven deeply into the reservoir injecting additional 100 m3 water. A sophisticated slicing and mixing unit was deployed and used for preparation and injection of surfactant/polymer solution at the well-site (Fig. 7).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Overview of the surfactant/polymer slicing, mixing and injection unit deployed at the well-site</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Overview of the surfactant/polymer slicing, mixing and injection unit deployed at the well-site</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="8" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">The injection lasted almost a month and the operation was precisely monitored by measuring the wellhead pressure, injection rate and viscosity of injected fluids. During the injection period, flow rate was practically stable and wellhead pressure gradually increased as expected indicating a normal trend and good injectivity of the surfactant/polymer solution (Fig. 8).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Build-up of well head pressure in the injection well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Build-up of well head pressure in the injection well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="9" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">MOL Executive Board recognizing the high technical knowledge and outstanding performance of the team approved an individual project proposal prepared by the Upstream Research and Development team. Right now, the approved project is already running and the surfactant/polymer solution is being injected by state of the art injection technology (Fig. 9) into two injection wells from April 2016 and as planned, it will end only in 2019 after 45 months injection period.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190369MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190369MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>The site of surfactant-polymer injection pilot</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>The site of surfactant-polymer injection pilot</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>