<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118188990MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-29T11:45:32Z">
<doi>10.2118/188990-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/188990-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The Azeri-Chirag-Gunashli (ACG) field is located offshore Azerbaijan in the South Caspian region (Figure 1), on the eastern end of a long regional anticlinal feature known as the Apsheron Trend. The trend can be mapped to onshore Azerbaijan and along its length are several giant oil fields whose production dates back to the late 19th and early 20th centuries. The fields were discovered between 1979 and 1987 with initial production occurring in 1980. The Azeri field constitutes the south-eastern culmination of the structure and is being developed by a consortium of oil companies with BP as operator.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>ACG Field Location</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>ACG Field Location</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The ACG PSA encompasses three development areas: Azeri, Chirag and Deepwater Gunashli (DWG) - see Figure 2. The Chirag Early Oil Project (EOP) came on stream in November 1997. ACG full field development (FFD) was subsequently planned as a three-phase development. Phase 1 represents a standalone scenario for the Central Azeri (CA) sector of the field. As FFD progressed, Phase 1 was integrated with Phase 2, covering West Azeri (WA) and East Azeri (EA), to optimize full Azeri oil recovery. Finally, Phase 3 focuses on development of the DWG area.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Schematic Diagram of ACG Field Lay-out &amp; Facilities</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schematic Diagram of ACG Field Lay-out &amp; Facilities</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Well A is an OHGP producer completed on March 2017. The pack consists of natural sand gravel. MDPN tool was run after completion for gravel pack quality evaluation. Permanent distributed fiber optic was installed in the well and DAS (distributed acoustic sensing) data gathered and processed for sand monitoring (Thiruvenkatanathan, 2016). MDPN logs and DAS derived sand attribute are shown in Figure 3. The tracks shown in Figure 3 from the left to the right are wellbore schematic, gamma ray, silicon activation, burst ratio, DAS sand attribute and oxygen activation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Well A MDPN and DAS sand events</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well A MDPN and DAS sand events</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Well B is located on the North Flank of the Central Azeri field. The well is OHGP producer with 7″ X 5″ tubing completion design. The well was completed on Feb 2017 with engineered proppant. MDPN silicon activation and spectroscopy log were run after completion for gravel pack quality evaluation. MDPN logs are presented in Figure 4. From he left to the right, the tracks are volume of shale, wellbore schematic, open hole gamma ray and cased hole gamma ray, MDPN gadolinium yield, corrected gadolinium yield, and silicon activation. Open hole gamma ray and cased hole gamma ray are normalized over the interval where no gravel is present in borehole.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Well B MDPN Nuclear Attributes used for GPE</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well B MDPN Nuclear Attributes used for GPE</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">A Production Log (PL) was run on Aug 2012. PL data indicates cross flow from lower reservoir Per D and C into Per B. Two bridge plugs were set in Per C on Aug 2012. On Jan 2013, scale was observed inside the tubing. Due to the uncertainty in the ion analysis of workflow, the damage mechanism could be due to calcite carbonate scale or mix of calcite carbonate and barium sulphate scale. MDPN tool was run on Feb 2017 to identify scale chemical composition and scale location. MDPN tool was run passive mode and energy spectroscopy mode. Logs of passive mode and energy spectroscopy mode are plotted in Figure 5.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Well C, MDPN used for scale identification</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well C, MDPN used for scale identification</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="4" pdf-page="8" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Nuclear models were carefully built up with very detailed logging conditions and formation properties. The responses of burst nuclear attribute and capture attribute are simulated and they are plotted in Figure 6. It is clear that capture nuclear attribute show much better sensitivity than burst nuclear attribute. The relative response of capture nuclear attribute is 5 times higher than the relative response of burst nuclear attribute. Capture nuclear attribute is the gamma ray ratio from late time window which are mainly from neutron capture interaction. Compared to burst nuclear attribute, the capture nuclear attribute has deeper volume of investigation but it is more sensitive to formation clay minerals.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Nuclear Models Response of burst NA Response of capture NA Relative response of burst NA Relative response of capture NA</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Nuclear Models Response of burst NA Response of capture NA Relative response of burst NA Relative response of capture NA</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-6a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_6a.tif" id="ImgLink-6a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Response of burst NA</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-6b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_6b.tif" id="ImgLink-6b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Response of capture NA</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-6c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_6c.tif" id="ImgLink-6c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>c</caption-order>
<caption-text>Relative response of burst NA</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-6d">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_6d.tif" id="ImgLink-6d" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>d</caption-order>
<caption-text>Relative response of capture NA</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">The measured burst nuclear attribute and capture nuclear attribute on Dec 05 over Bal X are illustrated in Figure 7. The repeatability of Both Dec 05 and Dec 12 logs are good. However, nuclear attributes of Dec 05 are systematically higher than nuclear attributes of Dec 12. Borehole fluid ID shows denser borehole fluid near TD indicating poor mud circulating. The abnormal increase of nuclear attributes of Dec 05 was caused by segregation of borehole fluids. It also proves that MDPN measurement can be affected by borehole fluid. Capture nuclear attribute of Dec 12 was used for Bal X interpretation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well D Measured Nuclear Attributes</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well D Measured Nuclear Attributes</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Figure 8 shows the interpreted gas saturation of using burst and capture nuclear attributes. With better gas sensitivity, the capture derived gas saturation matches better than burst the openhole saturation (SWT).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Well D MDPN Interpretation</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well D MDPN Interpretation</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="10" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">While burst nuclear attribute is more sensitivity to formation density the capture nuclear attribute is more sensitive to formation lithology and hydrogen index which is similar to open hole neutron porosity measurement. In well D, there is a good correlation between cased hole MDPN nuclear attributes and open hole LWD neutron porosity and density logs. Well E has similar completion as well D. There was no open hole neutron porosity and density data in well E. The analytical workflow developed on Well A is applied on the MDPN dataset from well E to predict open hole neutron porosity and density logs. The results are illustrated in Figure 9.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Generating Proxy Neutron Porosity and Bulk Density from MDPN using analytical approach Well D: MDPN proxy neutron porosity and density versus OH LWD logs. For neutron porosity, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 1.1 pu; for density log, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 0.011 g/cc Well E: proxy neutron porosity and pseudo density logs predicted from cased hole MDPN data. Note the correlation with OH LWD resistivity logs</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Generating Proxy Neutron Porosity and Bulk Density from MDPN using analytical approach Well D: MDPN proxy neutron porosity and density versus OH LWD logs. For neutron porosity, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 1.1 pu; for density log, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 0.011 g/cc Well E: proxy neutron porosity and pseudo density logs predicted from cased hole MDPN data. Note the correlation with OH LWD resistivity logs</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-9a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_9a.tif" id="ImgLink-9a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well D: MDPN proxy neutron porosity and density versus OH LWD logs. For neutron porosity, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 1.1 pu; for density log, the difference of mean value of predict log and OH LWD logs is 0.011 g/cc</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118188990MS-Img_SPi-9b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118188990MS_i_9b.tif" id="ImgLink-9b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well E: proxy neutron porosity and pseudo density logs predicted from cased hole MDPN data. Note the correlation with OH LWD resistivity logs</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>