<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118186187MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T13:43:55Z">
<doi>10.2118/186187-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/186187-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">A summary on increasing capillary number to reduce residual fluid saturation is presented in Figure 1. This summary is resumed from various phenomena of fluid flow in porous media, which covers oil, microemulsion and brine flow. Figure 1 portrays the attempt to recover more fluid either oil or brine is achievable by increasing trapping number NT. The contribution of trapping number can be approached either by capillary number side or Bond number side. Bond number covers the density difference Δγ, fluid bubble size d and both wettability θ and surface tension Ts. </anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Capillary desaturation curve (CDC) under stable displacement regime or piston-like displacement. Once buoyancy number <i>N<sub>B</sub>
</i>is ignored, trapping number <i>N<sub>T</sub>
</i>would equal to capillary number <i>N<sub>C</sub>
</i>. Bouyancy number at particular inclination <i>α </i>is only considered in Youssef (2015). All data are abstracted from laboratory results except Al Shalabi (2014) which is from numerical simulation. Normalised residual saturation is expressed as follow <i>S<sub>n</sub>
</i>=(<i>S<sub>or</sub>
</i>-<i>S<sub>or(min)</sub>
</i>)/(<i>S<sub>or(max)</sub>- S<sub>or(min)</sub>
</i>).</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Capillary desaturation curve (CDC) under stable displacement regime or piston-like displacement. Once buoyancy number N<sub>B</sub>is ignored, trapping number N<sub>T</sub>would equal to capillary number N<sub>C</sub>. Bouyancy number at particular inclination α is only considered in <link href="BIB1">Youssef (2015)</link>  . All data are abstracted from laboratory results except Al Shalabi (2014) which is from numerical simulation. Normalised residual saturation is expressed as follow S<sub>n</sub>=(S<sub>or</sub>-S<sub>or(min)</sub>)/(S<sub>or(max)</sub>- S<sub>or(min)</sub>).</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="bib">
<bib id="BIB1">
<label>Youssef et al., 2015</label>
<author>
<first-name>S.</first-name>
<last-name>Youssef</last-name>
</author>, <author>
<first-name>Y.</first-name>
<last-name>Peysson</last-name>
</author>, <author>
<first-name>D.</first-name>
<last-name>Bauer</last-name>
</author> &amp; <author>
<first-name>O.</first-name>
<last-name>Vizika</last-name>
</author>
<pubDate>2015</pubDate>. <article-title>Capillary desaturation curve prediction using 3d microtomography images. Presented at the International Symposium of the Society of Core Analysts held in St. John’s Newfoundland and Labrador, Canada , 16-21 August</article-title>.</bib>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">Figure 2a tells that Klamono Field is located in the East part of Salawati Basin. The reservoir consists of three formations, which are Kais, Sirga and Klasefet Formation under strong water drive force. The New Guinea Limestone Group encompassed of Oligocene to Miocene aged Faumai, Sirga, Kais and Klasafet formations are the key in tertiary strata (See Figure 2b). The major reservoir is Kais carbonates while the source of hydrocarbon is Klasafet shale (Satyana et al, 1999). General reservoir properties are displayed in Table 2. The reason of EDH application is due to its API at 18.5 and viscosity 68 cP (at 52 °C). A crude is categorised as a heavy oil if its API is between 10 to 22 (Pramana et al., 2012).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Part (a): Map showing Salawati Basin tectoning setting. Salawati Basin is bounded by Sorong Fault and there exists some faults within SW-NE and SSW-NNE trending, genetically formed as enechelon extension fractures to the Sorong Fault ( Satyana et al., 1999). An index map at upper left part indicates that Salawati Basin is in foreland position of Papua Island and nearby the Indo-Australia Plate. Part (b): Stratigraphy map of Salawati Basin (Satyana et al., 1999). Red box points where Klamono Field is, mainly from middle to late Miocene.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Part (a): Map showing Salawati Basin tectoning setting. Salawati Basin is bounded by Sorong Fault and there exists some faults within SW-NE and SSW-NNE trending, genetically formed as enechelon extension fractures to the Sorong Fault ( <link href="BIB2">Satyana et al., 1999</link> ). An index map at upper left part indicates that Salawati Basin is in foreland position of Papua Island and nearby the Indo-Australia Plate. Part (b): Stratigraphy map of Salawati Basin ( <link href="BIB2">Satyana et al., 1999</link> ). Red box points where Klamono Field is, mainly from middle to late Miocene.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-2a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_2a.tif" id="ImgLink-2a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Map showing Salawati Basin tectoning setting</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-2b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_2b.tif" id="ImgLink-2b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Stratigraphy map of Salawati Basin</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="bib">
<bib id="BIB2">
<label>Satyana et al., 1999</label>
<author>
<first-name>A. H.</first-name>
<last-name>Satyana</last-name>
</author>, <author>
<first-name>Y.</first-name>
<last-name>Salim</last-name>
</author> &amp; <author>
<first-name>J. M.</first-name>
<last-name>Demarest</last-name>
</author>
<pubDate>1999</pubDate>. <article-title>Significance of focused hydrocarbon migration in the salawati basin: Controls of faults and structural noses . Proceeding of the 27th Indonesian Petroleum Association Conference and Exhibition, Jakarta, October</article-title>.</bib>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="6" figure-order="3" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">The primary candidate for our trial of EDH is well KLO-X1 (See Figure 3). KLO-X1 was drilled on 6 Aug 2007 at 141 m TVD. It could be categorized as a shallow oil well. It is assisted by Sucker Rod Pump. Due to low influx, the well is suspended for a while. The well has been producing since 15 May 2009 at 289 blpd and 5.8 bopd (98% water cut) after respacing job (change of rod spacing at SRP). Current well oil cumulative is approximately 1085 STB (See Figure 3a). Reparation job has been done 4 times those are Feb 2008, Aug 2009, Sept 2011 and Nov 2013.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Part (a): Profile of production history for 7 years of well KLO-X1. Part (b): Profile of pressure and temperature of well KLO-X1. The data is obtained using pressure and temperature gauge (PT Log) at static condition (no flow). This measurement was conducted on 13 March 2015.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Part (a): Profile of production history for 7 years of well KLO-X1. Part (b): Profile of pressure and temperature of well KLO-X1. The data is obtained using pressure and temperature gauge (PT Log) at static condition (no flow). This measurement was conducted on 13 March 2015.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Profile of production history for 7 years of well KLO-X1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Profile of pressure and temperature of well KLO-X1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="4" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">As mentioned in the Introduction section, viscosity is critical to the fluid flow of oil. Experimental data is achieved from Fann VG measurement and a set of fitting equations is employed to see how dead oil behaves under a wider temperature range. Possible temperature range must follow what reservoir condition is like and the density is, in fact, pressure dependent (See Figure 3b). Dead oil equation is presented as Eq. 5 (McCain, 1990). Detailed parameters of equation set to compute oil density is presented in Appendices section. A macro tool has been provided to compute the equations set and density of dead oil properties (See Appendix 1 and Figure 4) (Guo, 2007). A rough trend of thermal gradient is projected from the top and bottom well temperature as follows 0.180833 °C/m.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Red curve: Viscosity profile of oil sample from Klamono Field. Prediction of viscosity is computed using Eq. 5 (See also Appendix 1) indicated by continuous line (-) and the experimental data is performed by Fann VG measurement indicated by (□). Green curve: Fractional flow for oil computed by modifying Eq. 8 (f<sub>o</sub>=1-f<sub>w</sub>). This chart is computed based on 6 selected temperature. The value of k<sub>ro</sub>/k<sub>rw</sub> is obtained from the history matching of production data, i.e. f<sub>o</sub>=2.5% (f<sub>w</sub>=97.5%) at 52 °C (from fluid sampling in conjunction of PT Log operation). Point f<sub>o</sub>=2.5% at 52 °C points out initial condition before EDH was installed.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Red curve: Viscosity profile of oil sample from Klamono Field. Prediction of viscosity is computed using Eq. 5 (See also Appendix 1) indicated by continuous line (-) and the experimental data is performed by Fann VG measurement indicated by (□). Green curve: Fractional flow for oil computed by modifying Eq. 8 (f<sub>o</sub>=1-f<sub>w</sub>). This chart is computed based on 6 selected temperature. The value of k<sub>ro</sub>/k<sub>rw</sub> is obtained from the history matching of production data, i.e. f<sub>o</sub>=2.5% (f<sub>w</sub>=97.5%) at 52 °C (from fluid sampling in conjunction of PT Log operation). Point f<sub>o</sub>=2.5% at 52 °C points out initial condition before EDH was installed.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="11" figure-order="5" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">Figure 5 displays the initial and final liquid rate are added to 14 blpd (field data). By zooming Figure 5a, the initial and final liquid rates are 251 blpd and 261 blpd, respectively for the prediction data through computation. This study assumes constant productivity index PI at 5 bbl/day/psi.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>KLO-X1 inflow and outflow performance. Part (a): Liquid phase inflow and outflow performance is constructed by Eq. 9 and 10, respectively. Outflow performance is conducted by matching pressure &amp; rate based on BHP survey and production test of well. “Before” refers to condition when EDH was just about to install at 18 March 2015 and “After” is showing the condition at 20 March 2015. Part (b): Oil phase inflow performance relationship.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>KLO-X1 inflow and outflow performance. Part (a): Liquid phase inflow and outflow performance is constructed by Eq. 9 and 10, respectively. Outflow performance is conducted by matching pressure &amp; rate based on BHP survey and production test of well. “Before” refers to condition when EDH was just about to install at 18 March 2015 and “After” is showing the condition at 20 March 2015. Part (b): Oil phase inflow performance relationship.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-5a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_5a.tif" id="ImgLink-5a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Liquid phase inflow and outflow performance is constructed by Eq. 9 and 10</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-5b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_5b.tif" id="ImgLink-5b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text> Oil phase inflow performance relationship</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="6" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">The analytical results have good agreement with the field data oil rate, with 0.8% and 2.3% relative error with respect to the field data, pre- and post-EDH installation respectively. It gains 10 blpd rises after EDH was installed on the 2nd day after installation (See Figure 6). The comparison of field and prediction data as revealed in Figure 6 shows that prediction has a pessimistic trend. It might be due to higher volume exhibiting heat exchange via convection than it should be. The computation of temperature is carried out at the static condition of heat transfer along the tubing (gross pipe length Lpipe=109 m). According to Eq. 6 (also See Appendix 2), the volume considered is the entire liquid along inside the tubing.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186187MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186187MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Well KLO-X1 production performance. Actual production are collected from well production test data. Prediction data are computed by inflow versus outflow performance relationship. The continuous line (-) represents field data and dashed line (--) refers to prediction data computed. The vertical red line indicates the date of EDH installation.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well KLO-X1 production performance. Actual production are collected from well production test data. Prediction data are computed by inflow versus outflow performance relationship. The continuous line (-) represents field data and dashed line (--) refers to prediction data computed. The vertical red line indicates the date of EDH installation.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>