<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118180732MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-23T10:37:26Z">
<doi>10.2118/180732-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/180732-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">Figure 1 shows a schematic diagram (adapted from Villarroel, 2013) of a well cluster drilled using pad drilling technique. For this study, the well spacing was 500m for PP.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>A schematic diagram of a well-pad used for exploitation of extra-heavy oil fields in Orinoco</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>A schematic diagram of a well-pad used for exploitation of extra-heavy oil fields in Orinoco</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">An integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast is schematically illustrated in Figure 2. The workflow comprises of three sequential segments to assess the full-field (FF) potential. The first segment of the workflow selects three realizations from a suite of full-field geostatistical realizations. The three selected realizations account for variations in reservoir geology and represent low, mid, and high scenarios of reservoir geology respectively. Additionally, well locations were selected separately for each realization based on surface constraints and well selection algorithm (described below).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The cumulative oil production (OPC) at 50 years from the simulation runs were used to compare the outcomes of various scenarios and rank them. Three perfor-mance curves representing low, mid &amp; high full-field primary production forecast are selected based on cumulative oil production after 50 years. The output from this step was the full-field rate profiles of different phases (oil, water and gas), estimated recovery values, number of producers and well-scheduling using Approach-1 development plan. Figure 3 shows the oil production profiles with the initial ramp up reaching to the target full-field plateau and then decline. Oil recoveries for three cases were 2.4%, 2.8%and 3.8% on the full-field basis OOIP.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Full-field primary production (PP) oil production rate profiles show ramp-up, plateau &amp; decline</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Full-field primary production (PP) oil production rate profiles show ramp-up, plateau &amp; decline</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Following the full-field primary DOE simulations, we developed the Pareto charts of OPC under primary at 25 years (Figure 4) and 50 years (Figure 5). It ranks the uncertain parameters in order of their impact. Rig availability came out to be the most important parameters affecting OPC in the time-frames of 25 and 50 years. Number of rigs (and hence number of wells drilled) has a very large impact on the field performance.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Pareto chart showing relative impact of uncertain parameters on OPC at 25 years under PP</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pareto chart showing relative impact of uncertain parameters on OPC at 25 years under PP</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Following the full-field primary DOE simulations, we developed the Pareto charts of OPC under primary at 25 years (Figure 4) and 50 years (Figure 5). It ranks the uncertain parameters in order of their impact. Rig availability came out to be the most important parameters affecting OPC in the time-frames of 25 and 50 years. Number of rigs (and hence number of wells drilled) has a very large impact on the field performance.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Pareto chart showing relative impact of uncertain parameters on OPC at 50 years under PP</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pareto chart showing relative impact of uncertain parameters on OPC at 50 years under PP</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">The next and most important step for primary production forecasting is to compare the simulation results with analog data. The analog field was an XHO field with similar geology, but at a greater depth (and therefore, with lower oil viscosity and higher reservoir pressure) and developed using horizontal wells of similar horizontal lengths. Figure 6 compares the cumulative distribution of initial production rates and estimated ultimate recovery at the individual well level in the low, mid &amp; high cases with the analog field data.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Benchmarking of PP forecasting with analog data</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Benchmarking of PP forecasting with analog data</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">First of all, the thermal development targets are identified. Cut-offs on minimum reservoir thickness and maximum thickness of barriers-to-steam were imposed to map thermal geobodies for each FFM. Figure 7 shows a plan-view of geobodies after imposition of cut-offs (thermal targets) along with the associated primary producers in one of the target reservoirs. The area shown in the figure is considered amenable for thermal recovery.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Thermal geobodies (targets) and selected well locations in Mid FFM</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Thermal geobodies (targets) and selected well locations in Mid FFM</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">After the simulation, we also created the Pareto chart of DNOPC under thermal production (Figure 8) to rank the uncertain parameters in order of their impact. Geology (a key factor controlling OOIP) came out as the most important parameter affecting the thermal performance.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Pareto chart of DNOPC under thermal (PP, CSS &amp; CSI)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pareto chart of DNOPC under thermal (PP, CSS &amp; CSI)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">Monte Carlo simulations were performed using the proxy. Several Monte Carlo runs were made by randomly picking values of uncertain parameters from their specified distribution and estimating DNOPC using the proxy. Thus, after Monte Carlo simulation, we obtain a distribution (cumulative distribution function, CDF) of DNOPC. Three different points on this CDF corresponding to cumulative probabilities of 10 –50 –90 respectively represent low, mid and high performance profiles and called thermal type wells. Figure 9 shows the oil-production rate profile, steam-injection rate profile and cumulative steam oil ratio (Cum SOR) for the three selected type wells.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Three thermal type-wells representing expected range of thermal recovery performance</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Three thermal type-wells representing expected range of thermal recovery performance</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="10" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">Figure 10 is a schematic diagram showing wells for thermal development. The well spacing for PP was 500 meter. For thermal development scenario, we used reduced well spacing by placing three equally spaced horizontal infills between existing PP producers. This reduces the interwell spacing to 125 meter. The additional producers at each end of AOI serve as guard wells. These wells protect the inner thermal wells from cold oil-influx from the buffer zone.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Schematic diagram of well placement for thermal; area of interest (AOI) for recovery and pressure caclculation inside red dashed box</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schematic diagram of well placement for thermal; area of interest (AOI) for recovery and pressure caclculation inside red dashed box</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="11" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">Figure 11 shows a plan view of the reservoir simulation grid used for the thermal performance study. The thermal sector includes the area of interest (AOI) and the surrounding buffer zone. The AOI is 2500ft. long and 2050ft. wide in the aerial direction. We used tartan grids in the x-y plain. Tartan grid has fine grid size (12.5m × 12.5m) in the AOI to accurately capture the impact of important phenomena occurring in that region.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Plan view of the reservoir model; tartan grid used in the current study</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Plan view of the reservoir model; tartan grid used in the current study</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="12" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Figure 12 shows the pressure depletion in the three geological sectors using primary production for five years. Pressure depletions in the three sectors are quite different. Primary production only can deplete the Sector-2 reservoirs to target pressure of 450 psi before five years. However, target pressure in Sector-1 is achieved only at five years, whereas Sector-3 (thickest) is not depleted to the target pressure during this period.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="3" pdf-page="14" figure-order="13" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">Figure 13 shows the geological sector cross sections for three sectors at the end of five years. These cross-sections show local pressure depletion at the end of each year for five years (i.e. at the end of 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 years). The shale baffles obstruct the flow of oil from the upper regions of the reservoir to the primary producers. Therefore, the presence of baffles reduces the rate of pressure depletion in the upper regions (Figure 13c); higher pressure depletion occurs in the regions below the baffles. The overall impact of shale baffles is to slow down average pressure depletion in the AOI.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Cross-sections across horizontal wells (pressure depletion after five years of primary production in different sectors. Presence of shale baffles obstructs oil flow from the upper regions of the reservoir (a) Sector-1 (b) Sector-2 (c) Sector-3</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Cross-sections across horizontal wells (pressure depletion after five years of primary production in different sectors. Presence of shale baffles obstructs oil flow from the upper regions of the reservoir (a) Sector-1 (b) Sector-2 (c) Sector-3</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-13a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_13a.tif" id="ImgLink-13a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sector-1</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-13b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_13b.tif" id="ImgLink-13b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sector-2</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-13c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_13c.tif" id="ImgLink-13c" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>c</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sector-3</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="14" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">Figure 14 shows the impact of CSS on pressure depletion for the three geological sectors. In Sector-1, CSS accelerates the pressure depletion to some extent. The difference in average pressures in the AOI is about 150 psi during initial cycles and it reduces to about 50 psi towards the end of five years (Fig. 14(a)). The difference in pressure depletions is even less pronounced for Sector-2 (Fig. 14(b)). In this case, comparable pressure depletion is achieved with primary production because of good reservoir connec-tivity and smaller thickness.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Comparison of pressure profiles using the two operating methods; PP only and PP followed by CSS. Sector-3 experiences the highest impact of CSS on pressure depletion in the AOI</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of pressure profiles using the two operating methods; PP only and PP followed by CSS. Sector-3 experiences the highest impact of CSS on pressure depletion in the AOI</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="15" data-type-order="17">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">Table 2 summarizes oil recovery after five years under two strategies. Figure 15(a) shows the oil recovery (calculated from oil in place) from AOI vs. time; Figure 15(b) and (c) show the gas in place and water in place vs. time. It is evident that for XHO reservoirs, horizontal well CSS provides significantly higher oil recovery than PP only. At the end of five years the recovery from PP is 7.5% – 9.1% whereas after using CSS, the recovery was increased to 18.2% – 27.2%.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Integrated workflow for primary and thermal probabilistic forecast</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="16" figure-order="16" data-type-order="18">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">We also investigated the impact of cross guard wells (wells perpendicular to the horizontal producers) on pressure depletion. These wells are intended to prevent cold oil-influx from near-toe and near-heel regions of the AOI wells. Figure 16 shows the pressure map without and with the cross-guard wells after 5-years of pressure-depletion using Strategy-2 in Sector-3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Pressure-map (a) without and (b) with the cross-guard wells after 5-years of pressure depletion using pressure depletion strategy-2 with Sector-3</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pressure-map (a) without and (b) with the cross-guard wells after 5-years of pressure depletion using pressure depletion strategy-2 with Sector-3</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-16a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_16a.tif" id="ImgLink-16a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>a</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pressure-map</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-16b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_16b.tif" id="ImgLink-16b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>b</caption-order>
<caption-text>without and</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="17" figure-order="17" data-type-order="19">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">Figure 17 illustrates the importance of maintaining an appropriate differential pressure. In the first case, the differential pressure is 4 psi. This is sufficient to produce all the heated liquid. As a result, there is only a small liquid level build-up above the producer. The steam chamber develops nicely and the reservoir is drained in an efficient manner (Fig. 17(a)). However, in the second case (Fig. 17(b)), the differential pressure is much smaller (~0 psi).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Improper development of steam chamber when differential pressure is small</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Improper development of steam chamber when differential pressure is small</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="17" figure-order="18" data-type-order="20">
<link href="link-18" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-18" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr21">A positive differential pressure is important for efficient drainage of the steam chamber. However, pressure drops in a CSI-HIHP well-pair (producer and injector) can cause a condition, when theoretically, pressure in portions of the injector may be lower than that in the producer. Figure 18 schematically illustrates impact of wellbore pressure drops in CSI-HIHP configuration.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-18">
<label>Figure 18 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_18.tif" id="ImgLink-18" />
<caption>Schematic illustration of impact of wellbore pressure drop; High frictional pressures losses may cause pressure in portions of the injector lower than producer</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>18</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schematic illustration of impact of wellbore pressure drop; High frictional pressures losses may cause pressure in portions of the injector lower than producer</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="18" figure-order="19" data-type-order="21">
<link href="link-19" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-19" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr22">Figure 19 shows the producer and injector pressure profiles along their lengths with no pressure drop in the injector. The injector pressure was kept constant along its length to explicitly study impact of pressure drop in producer only. However, producer pressure can drop from toe of the well towards its heel depending on the magnitude of pressure drop. For a typical 6.25” liner diameter, the pressure drop in the wellbore is only 1 psi.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-19">
<label>Figure 19 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_19.tif" id="ImgLink-19" />
<caption>Producer and injector pressure profiles along their length</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>19</caption-order>
<caption-text>Producer and injector pressure profiles along their length</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="19" figure-order="20" data-type-order="22">
<link href="link-20" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-20" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr23">Figure 20 shows a comparison of oil inflow profile, cumulative oil production and steam-oil-ratio for the three cases. As evident, because of small pressure drop in case of standard size liner diameter (6.25”) the impact of pressure drop in producer on thermal performance is minimal. It compares very closely with the no friction case. We also illustrate the case, when the liner diameter was reduced to 3.12”.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-20">
<label>Figure 20 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_20.tif" id="ImgLink-20" />
<caption>Comparison of oil inflow profile, cumulative oil production and steam-oil-ratio for the three cases</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>20</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of oil inflow profile, cumulative oil production and steam-oil-ratio for the three cases</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="19" figure-order="21" data-type-order="24">
<link href="link-21" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-21" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr24">We examine two cases with different steam injection configurations (Figure 21). In both cases, steam injection rate is fixed at 3000 bbls/d. The liner diameter is 8”.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-21">
<label>Figure 21 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_21.tif" id="ImgLink-21" />
<caption>Schematics of different injection schemes</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>21</caption-order>
<caption-text>Schematics of different injection schemes</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="20" figure-order="22" data-type-order="25">
<link href="link-22" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-22" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr25">Figure 22 shows the pressure along injectors and producers and its impact on the steam injection rate and development of steam chamber near the heel, toe and along the well-length for the two cases under consideration.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-22">
<label>Figure 22 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_22.tif" id="ImgLink-22" />
<caption>Pressure along injectors and producers, steam injection rate and development of steam chamber near the heel, toe and along the well-length</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>22</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pressure along injectors and producers, steam injection rate and development of steam chamber near the heel, toe and along the well-length</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="21" figure-order="23" data-type-order="26">
<link href="link-23" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-23" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr26">As described above, in the development lifecycle of many heavy-oil reservoirs, thermal enhanced oil recovery (EOR) method is preceded by primary production. Long producers (~ 5000 ft. or longer) is typically used during primary production of heavy oil reservoirs. The current art for thermal development would require shorter injectors and producers to be drilled after primary production, which could make thermal recovery commercially non-economic. The proposed well configuration of two shorter injectors per producer (Figure 23) would significantly improve economics of such projects.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118180732MS-Img_SPi-23">
<label>Figure 23 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118180732MS_i_23.tif" id="ImgLink-23" />
<caption>Proposed well configuration of two short injectors and a long producer in CSI-HIHP configuration</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>23</caption-order>
<caption-text>Proposed well configuration of two short injectors and a long producer in CSI-HIHP configuration</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>