<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118191917MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-29T20:06:39Z">
<doi>10.2118/191917-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/191917-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The Walloon Coal Measures (previously referred to as the Walloon Subgroup) are an unconventional CSG reservoir in the Jurassic sequence of the north-eastern Surat Basin, with production primarily from the coal prone Juandah and Taroom coal measures. Along with the underlying Bowen Basin that extends to the north, the Surat Basin is currently a key focus of appraisal and development for the CSG to LNG projects in Queensland. Where these two basins sit regionally is shown in Figure 1. Santos’ Surat Basin acreage discussed in this paper is highlighted blue around the towns of Roma and Wallumbilla.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Surat and Bowen Basin Regional Map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Surat and Bowen Basin Regional Map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">This fine-scale heterogeneity is illustrated in Figure 2 by the core sample with cleats, fractures, and maceral types highlighted. This sample shows that the aperture, length, and frequency of fractures and cleats that control flow behaviour varies greatly at a fine scale. The zoomed-in section highlights thin bands dominated by different maceral types that control gas generation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Coal Core Sample with Fractures, Cleating, and Macerals Highlighted</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Coal Core Sample with Fractures, Cleating, and Macerals Highlighted</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">The high degree of variability in the deposition of the Walloon Coal Measures is illustrated in Figure 3 by the contrast in reservoir intersected by an offset well drilled only 50m away from the original. Example zones of coal, clastic, and shale facies have been highlighted for reference, and the percentage change in net coal per formation is summarised on the right. Note how the distribution and character of coal seams differs significantly within each formation between the two wells. Most important is how the three main coal packages observed in the Lower Juandah formation in Well 1 are completely absent from Well 2. They are instead replaced by thick sections of shale and clastic facies, resulting in 90% less net coal in this formation at this well location.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Reservoir Heterogeneity Observed in Walloon Coal Measures between 50m Offset Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Reservoir Heterogeneity Observed in Walloon Coal Measures between 50m Offset Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">The quantity of reservoir sampling taken and the range of results seen from exploration wells across an example development area of the Walloon Coal Measures is summarised in Figure 4. This figure illustrates the large variability in static and dynamic properties between exploration wells. The intervals sampled by each drill-stem test and the interpreted permeability are highlighted in red boxes, and gas content results are shown in the right log-track for each well. These four exploration wells are the only reservoir sampling for an area that would ultimately contain approximately 100 development wells.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Example Reservoir Data Sampling Obtained from Exploration Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Example Reservoir Data Sampling Obtained from Exploration Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">The variability in permeability seen in these four wells is within the four log-cycle range of what has been observed locally and documented by other operators across the basin (Kabir et al. 2011, Mazumder et al. 2013). The variability over short lateral distances for reservoir properties such as permeability is clearly illustrated by the test results from closely spaced (500m) infill wells overlaid on the regional dataset. These wells are in a development area immediately adjacent to that discussed in Figure 4, with the results shown in Figure 5. Each unit on the vertical axis represents one log-cycle.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Highly Variable Infill Well Permeability Results Plotted Over Regional Trend</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Highly Variable Infill Well Permeability Results Plotted Over Regional Trend</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The regional gas content trend shown in Figure 6 also shows a high degree of variability. In this diagram, each unit on the horizontal axis represents 1 m3/ton. While there is a general trend of increasing gas content with depth, for a given depth there is large variability even within the same formation. Combined with changes in coal quality, the gas holding capacity associated with each of these samples will vary and lead to a wide range of gas saturations and production behaviour from individual coal seams.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Walloon Coal Measures Regional Gas Content Trend</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Walloon Coal Measures Regional Gas Content Trend</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="7" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">In Figure 7, note that for this Permian coal sequence of the Bowen Basin there is visually some variability in the distribution of coal vertically. Despite this, the vertical facies proportion curve on the right of the cross-section shows a clear signature of where coal tends to be deposited vertically within the gross reservoir sequence. Here it is a lesser issue modelling reservoir geometry as the individual coal packages correlate more readily between wells and facies modelling workflows can be applied successfully.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Bowen Basin and Surat Basin Comparison of Coal Geometry and Vertical Facies Distribution</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Bowen Basin and Surat Basin Comparison of Coal Geometry and Vertical Facies Distribution</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-7a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_7a.tif" id="ImgLink-7a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>Bowen Basin</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-7b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_7b.tif" id="ImgLink-7b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order></caption-order>
<caption-text>Surat Basin</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">This removes any bias on uncertain lithostratigraphic interpretations as well as avoiding the requirement of correlating each seam individually. This approach represents the current best method to predict total net coal volume away from well control in the Walloon Coal Measures and is supported by good reproduction of well data statistics at this scale during blind testing of individual wells in a recently drilled 30 well development. Figure 8 shows that while there is a more narrow range of uncertainty at broader scales (highlighted in red for the project, and green for the individual wells), it is evident that the individual reservoirs intersected by a given well (highlighted in blue) are unique and highly variable. Note how the distribution of coal across the three formations differs significantly between the three highlighted wells, despite a net coal total within 10% of each other.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Impact of Scale on Net Coal Deviation from Mean</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Impact of Scale on Net Coal Deviation from Mean</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">To illustrate the challenge of upscaling with highly variable permeability, an example of upscaling five separate seams with a four log-cycle variation in permeability representative of the Walloon Coal Measures can be considered. This is represented in Figure 9 below.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Upscaling Five Seams Separated by Impermeable Interburden</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Upscaling Five Seams Separated by Impermeable Interburden</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">For simplicity, all seams in this example are defined as the same thickness, as well as having equal gas content, desorption isotherms, and static conditions. Permeability was upscaled to match the permeability-thickness product for both cases. Figure 10 shows that although the resulting water production is broadly equivalent between both cases, the gas production behaviour differs significantly.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Production Results of Permeability Upscale Example</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Production Results of Permeability Upscale Example</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">The number of reservoir units modelled is increased to 30 to construct an example more representative of reality. All other parameters were kept constant between the reservoir units. This scenario is equivalent to upscaling all reservoir units within a well to a single gas content and isotherm. To honour the hydrocarbon volumetrics for both cases, the initial gas content and reservoir pressure will be a net coal weighted average from the reservoir units in the fine scale system. The upscaled isotherm is then defined such that the initial gas saturation and isotherm curvature yield a good match of the gas production history. The match achieved for gas and water production is illustrated in Figure 11.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Production Results of Saturation Upscale Example</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Production Results of Saturation Upscale Example</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="12" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">The resulting upscaled isotherm for this example is plotted in red in Figure 12. It also shows the mid-case isotherm for each of the formations in solid colours, as well as the high and low bounds defined by the +/-15% saturation variability as dotted lines.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Input Isotherm Range and Upscaled Isotherm for Saturation Upscale Example</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Input Isotherm Range and Upscaled Isotherm for Saturation Upscale Example</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="13" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">The inherent reservoir heterogeneity coupled with the low sampling density both laterally (widely spaced exploration wells) and vertically (not all reservoir units within a well were tested) leads to a high degree of variability and uncertainty when populating such a model for the Walloon Coal Measures. This means it will not have the ability to accurately characterise the properties of individual reservoir units at specific well locations. An example of this from during the history matching process of a coarse model for the Walloon Coal Measures is illustrated in Figure 13 and Figure 14.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Example of Improved Total Gas Production Match with Field-Level Property Manipulation</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Example of Improved Total Gas Production Match with Field-Level Property Manipulation</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="14" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">The inherent reservoir heterogeneity coupled with the low sampling density both laterally (widely spaced exploration wells) and vertically (not all reservoir units within a well were tested) leads to a high degree of variability and uncertainty when populating such a model for the Walloon Coal Measures. This means it will not have the ability to accurately characterise the properties of individual reservoir units at specific well locations. An example of this from during the history matching process of a coarse model for the Walloon Coal Measures is illustrated in Figure 13 and Figure 14.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Example of Well Match Not Honoured as Field Match Improves (Run 2)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Example of Well Match Not Honoured as Field Match Improves (Run 2)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="15" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Example outcomes of such a workflow are shown in Figure 15. For both, a single well production model has been developed using the reservoir data available for the geodomain which can then be refined to improve the match against the aggregated production history. High and low cases can be defined based on the range of production outcomes observed. Both examples are plotted on the same vertical scale. The relative simplicity of this workflow over a 3D simulation model is an advantage in terms of resource requirements and its ability to be updated rapidly.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Example Gas Production Curves for Single-Well Models Matched to Aggregated Geodomain Production</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Example Gas Production Curves for Single-Well Models Matched to Aggregated Geodomain Production</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="16" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">This then forms the basis for multi-realisation stochastic models of each sub-unit of the Walloon Coal Measures to establish a statistical range for the proportion of coal statically connected for different well spacing scenarios. The outcome of this for Santos’ Surat Basin acreage has been coal connectivity factors for individual areas that can then be used as inputs to the modelling of aggregated production areas discussed previously. An example of this highlighting three well spacing scenarios and the P50 static connectivity expected on aggregate and per formation is shown in Figure 16.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191917MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191917MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Static Connectivity as Function of Well Spacing for Example Area</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Static Connectivity as Function of Well Spacing for Example Area</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>