<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118191925MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-30T10:45:42Z">
<doi>10.2118/191925-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/191925-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">The distance between block-7E and Platform E and the depth of the target locations restrict drilling serviceable deviated and slanted wells crossing the primary targets while maintaining well to remain economic. An extended horizontal well was decided the most optimum option to develop reserves in block-7E (Figure 1). Well trajectory for PHW-2 is an extended reach well (i.e. information on how long the section towards landing point and how long its open-hole reservoir penetrated length) in a relatively shallow and thin reservoir to maximize net pay thickness while maintain operating serviceability. This required advance completion to reach out to total depth with some level of zonal control or self-regulating against water invasion to extend oil life.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Trajectory of extended reach horizontal well PHW-2</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Trajectory of extended reach horizontal well PHW-2</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">Fluid PVT in Sand I reservoir was defined as oil with API of 37 grades, bubble point pressure of 2675 psi, oil density of 52.4 lbm/ft3 with an initial Rs of 0.696 MSCF/STB. SCAL data is not available, instead analog data was used for similar reservoir type and depth from West and East flanks collectively. Sand package Sand I is subdivided into four sub-flow units: Sand I, Sand II, Sand III and Sand IV, all interpreted to be oil saturated and sharing the same OWC. In between these units a shale of 5 to 10 ft is interpreted from open hole logs in Exp-6 well (Figure 2). The lateral continuity of these thin shale section along the whole block is unknown and beyond the seismic resolution, but they could potentially act as barrier limiting vertical fluid flow.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Exp-6 LWD and petrophysical results</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Exp-6 LWD and petrophysical results</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3"> </anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Pre-drilling (left) and post-drilling model and proposed trajectory of PHW-2 well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pre-drilling (left) and post-drilling model and proposed trajectory of PHW-2 well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-3a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_3a.tif" id="ImgLink-3a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-3b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_3b.tif" id="ImgLink-3b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">With a long horizontal wellbore in this extended drilling condition, a major challenge is the delay of water coning and control of water cut once water breaks through into the wellbore. A field proven solution is to employ nozzle-type Inflow Control Devices (ICD) (See Figure 4) to purposely respond to high mobility fluid flows into the well (i.e water or gas) in terms of higher Bernoulli's induced back-pressure against the high-surge influx.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Sliding Sleeve with integral Inflow Control Device (ICD)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Sliding Sleeve with integral Inflow Control Device (ICD)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Due to no PSD data and also no core from this block, to select an optimal premium screen nominal opening, a 3-D (or thick-bed) filter medium was selected for the screen. This type of screen filter medium can efficiently control a wide range of formation particle sizes and not easily plugged. The Figure 5 illustrates how the flow area through a 2D type filter can be very quickly reduced by the natural sand pack bridging on screen slot opening. The 3D filter, however, allows a permeable medium to be formed by the combination of the filter itself and the medium range formation grains that get trapped inside the medium. This helps retain a wider range of grain sizes and maintains a large flow area for liquid and fines to pass through the packed medium.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Comparison of sand retention by 2D and 3D filter screens</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of sand retention by 2D and 3D filter screens</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Alpha-Beta-wave (See Figure 6) packing was chosen as the placement method for the gravel pack. This technique has proven suitable for wellbores drilled with water-based fluids and for formations (in this well) that have a large gap between formation pore pressure and frac pressure, allowing the circulating pressure during the beta-wave placement to never exceed the formation frac pressure. The risks of an incomplete gravel pack using this technique are significant based on past records, especially in the presence of reactive shales or when fracture pressure can easily be exceeded. Although a higher cost option using alternate path screens of beta-beta-wave packing could have mitigated these risks, the cost sensitive nature of the project drove the decision toward Alpha-Beta water packing and to rely on the 3D filter screens to provide the needed additional insurance against an incomplete pack.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Open Hole Gravel Pack – Alpha &amp; Beta Waves</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Open Hole Gravel Pack – Alpha &amp; Beta Waves</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Figure 7 summarizes the ICD design workflow for first horizontal well in S-field East Flank. This workflow is divided into three stages which is pre-drill feasibility modeling, real-time modeling and post-drilling evaluation. During the pre-drilling stage, the model is constructed based on offset well data in the East Flank such as reservoir properties, PVT data and etc. Then, 3D dynamic modeling was conducted to optimize the ICD-nozzles’ configuration and packer placement in order to simulate the oil production gain and water/gas reduction against the base case (open hole). In the real-time phase, the pre-drill model is updated and calibrated with the Logging-While-Drilling (LWD) real-time data while the data is retrieved batch-by-batch while drilling until total depth (TD).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>ICD Design Workflow for Well PHW-2 in S-field East Flank</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>ICD Design Workflow for Well PHW-2 in S-field East Flank</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">At the beginning of the study, a dynamic simulation was performed for single-well assessment with the model's grid properties such as PVT data, SCAL data, water saturation porosity, vertical permeability (Kv) and horizontal permeability (Kh). The properties were populated based on actual layer properties obtained from the only offset well, i.e. Exp-6 that is penetrating this far-reaching east flank (see Figure 8). The proposed horizontal well was planned to be completed approximately 2,100-ft in horizontal length. Furthermore, the Well PHW-2 was planned to penetrate through Sand I and Sand II reservoir layers.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Geological structure with horizontal well (well PHW-2) and offset well</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Geological structure with horizontal well (well PHW-2) and offset well</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">At the beginning of the study, a dynamic simulation was performed for single-well assessment with the model's grid properties such as PVT data, SCAL data, water saturation porosity, vertical permeability (Kv) and horizontal permeability (Kh). The properties were populated based on actual layer properties obtained from the only offset well, i.e. Exp-6 that is penetrating this far-reaching east flank (see Figure 8). The proposed horizontal well was planned to be completed approximately 2,100-ft in horizontal length. Furthermore, the Well PHW-2 was planned to penetrate through Sand I and Sand II reservoir layers.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Horizontal Well Permeability and Porosity log</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Horizontal Well Permeability and Porosity log</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Prior to ICD optimization, a base case (OH) was run in a dynamic simulation to validate the model with respect to the expected fluid in-place (oil, gas and water), FBHP and well productivity index (PI). This is followed by an ICD optimization simulation that was performed with different parameters conditions at each run such as constant nozzle size, varying nozzle sizes, different number of packers and their placements. Figure 10 demonstrated the ICD's contribution to suppress water influx from Sand II layer that had high permeability in order to re-distribute a more uniform influx across the entire length of the horizontal interval in this open hole multi-zone completion. This in return boost more oil from lower-water cut sections.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Heel to toe influx profile comparison between the base case (OH) and ICD case</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Heel to toe influx profile comparison between the base case (OH) and ICD case</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="11" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">Prior to ICD's design optimization, an updated geological model by the asset geologist was obtained after performing the geological correlations in East Flank block as per described in Figure 11.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Updated Geological Model</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Updated Geological Model</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="12" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">Concurrently, numbers of packers’ isolation were designed and optimized to compartmentalize the production between Sand I, Sand II and Sand III as well as within the same sand with the sand-shale varying permeabilities demonstrated (See Figure 12). Meanwhile, Figure 13 illustrated Well PHW-2 was separated into 9 different compartments with oil swellable packers along the final drilled 2300-ft lateral section. Each compartment was configured with only one ICD joint that had 2 to 4 nozzles to optimize the flow control to maximize and prolong oil production as long as water can be hold back and reduced later.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>LWD-derived permeability, completion and formation tops</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>LWD-derived permeability, completion and formation tops</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="13" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">Concurrently, numbers of packers’ isolation were designed and optimized to compartmentalize the production between Sand I, Sand II and Sand III as well as within the same sand with the sand-shale varying permeabilities demonstrated (See Figure 12). Meanwhile, Figure 13 illustrated Well PHW-2 was separated into 9 different compartments with oil swellable packers along the final drilled 2300-ft lateral section. Each compartment was configured with only one ICD joint that had 2 to 4 nozzles to optimize the flow control to maximize and prolong oil production as long as water can be hold back and reduced later.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Geological cross-section structure and horizontal well penetrating Sand I, Sand II and Sand III with 9 compartments</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Geological cross-section structure and horizontal well penetrating Sand I, Sand II and Sand III with 9 compartments</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="14" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">Strategically, the ICD fine tuning process of Well PHW-2 based on 9 compartments was proven to be significant in optimizing the nozzles’ configuration before running in hole. As observed in Figure 14, the LWD-derived permeability was significantly different from heel to toe section as compared to the pre-drilled reservoir model's profile. Hence, this verifies the real-time ICD modeling and finetuning is extremely important to optimize the ICD configuration based on actual LWD-derived data prior to RIH. If the ICD's pressure-drop design was based on the previous predrilled reservoir properties, the ultimate oil production benefits of ICD is not optimized.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Actual LWD-derived Permeability Profile against Pre-drilled Permeability Properties</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Actual LWD-derived Permeability Profile against Pre-drilled Permeability Properties</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="15" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Figure 15 demonstrated the flow behavior over the 5-year production with 1,000 blpd with liquid rate as the constraint. The 3D dynamic simulation was iterated according to the time-lapse changes of reservoir properties, fluid saturation and fluid distribution in Sand I, Sand II and Sand III for base case (OH). The cross-section demonstrated that the water first breakthorugh at toe section through Sand I and Sand II after 2 years (mid-production). Without ICD control, the strong water continued flowing through Sand II toward the wellbore at toe section after 5 years (late-production) due to aquifer charging phenomenon. Therefore, the effect of the ICD completion was evaluated from the early production to the point of water breakthrough at toe section in Sand II and Sand III.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Flow Behavior in 5 years period</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Flow Behavior in 5 years period</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="16" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">During post-installation evaluation, it showed that ICD had significantly hold back the high permeability section contribution. The subsequent Figure 16 clearly indiicated that ICD managed to suppress the influx at lateral mid section (of Sand II) and toe section (of Sand I and Sand II) for water breakthrough before evenly re-distributing the fluid flow along the lateral length. As a consequent, more oil influx from the low productivity zone (heel section) was allowed in comparison with open-hole no-control completion profile.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Heel to toe influx profile comparison between base case (OH) and optimal ICD case (Real-time modeling)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Heel to toe influx profile comparison between base case (OH) and optimal ICD case (Real-time modeling)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="17" data-type-order="17">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">Based on the dynamic modeling, the upside potential between the base case which is the open-hole completion and ICD case were about 36 MSTB (3%) additional oil gain and 36 MSTB (5.8%) water reduction. after 5 years (See Figure 17). During the fine-tuning process, several sensitivity analysis and multiple ICD nozzles’ configurations were simulated for the best oil incremental (optimal case) while achieving a minimum FBHP limit of 700 psi. The simulations showed that the well would be expected to have water breakthrough in the 1st month. The ICD case produced with a lower water cut over 5 years consistently.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Field Production Performance comparison between Optimized ICD and Open-hole</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Field Production Performance comparison between Optimized ICD and Open-hole</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="18" data-type-order="18">
<link href="link-18" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-18" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">In order to create separate segments to be controlled with ICDs, the horizontal section was isolated by a 3-1/2" inner string placed inside the 5-1/2" gravel pack screens (See Figure 18). Each section is delimited by oil swellable packers that straddle a Sliding Sleeve mounted ICD module. The length and location of each segment was finalized after drilling the 8-1/2" open hole section, and so was the number of ICD nozzles to be placed in each of the Sliding Sleeve mounted ICD modules. These integral sliding sleeves were installed with the side door in the ICD position.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-18">
<label>Figure 18 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_18.tif" id="ImgLink-18" />
<caption>Open Hole section segmented by swellable packers inside the 5-1/2" GP screens</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>18</caption-order>
<caption-text>Open Hole section segmented by swellable packers inside the 5-1/2" GP screens</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="17" figure-order="19" data-type-order="19">
<link href="link-19" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-19" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">The flow capacity of the surface choke valves was designed with a margin to allow potentially higher flow design. The surface choke flow opening was kept the same after unloading and only beaned up when flowrate has dropped in April 2018 (Figure 19). Downhole pressure and temperature as well as surface measurements of pressure, temperature and gas lift injection flowrate are measured by digital transmitters where the data is stored in a SCADA system and is transmitted online for real-time monitoring. This ensures the well flowing stable and any fluctuations or interruptions can be intervened quickly. Wellhead sampling and well tests are conducted daily and monthly respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118191925MS-Img_SPi-19">
<label>Figure 19 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118191925MS_i_19.tif" id="ImgLink-19" />
<caption>Well PHW-2 Production performance vs. FDP estimation</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>19</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well PHW-2 Production performance vs. FDP estimation</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>