<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118186060MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T20:04:14Z">
<doi>10.2118/186060-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/186060-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">N field is located at the the middle host of Betara Complex in Jabung block in south Sumatra basin (Fig.1). It is one of the oldest condensated gas fields developed LTAF reservoir since 1995 and supplying gas to LPG Plant to Singapore since 2005. The main targets, the LTAF drilled by 98 wells, are made up of fine-medium grained sandstones to coarse sandstones deposited in a fluvial-delta-marine setting. N field, as a complicated faulted anticline on a granite basement paleo-high confined by two NNW to SSE trending reverse-faults, contened variable CO2 within the nature gas. Because of this, N field has generally been divided into several compartments. The distributions of LTAF are very special, in which some strata were on lap on the old basement high and were locally derived in the early stage.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Location Map of N Field</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Location Map of N Field</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">Well logs divisions based on cores and depositional cycles and 3D seismic sections were tied together in order to describe 3D distribution of all boundaries. Sequence boundaries of four segments with 15 cycles (U1-U4, M1-M4) and 30 sub-divided sand-units (U1a-U1b, U2a-U2b etc.) onlap basement in LTAF have been identified and correlated in all wells by using the flooding surfaces and turnaround boundaries (Fig.2). Four segments named U, M, L and Simpang associated with marine flooding events, can be defined in seismic sections that were correspondent with segments in wells based on well-seismic ties (Fig.2), while the basement displayed conglomerated granite lithology. At the top of basement, it created an abrupt-changing surface that showed a strong reflector in most of seismic profiles, which can easily be corresponding and interpreted.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>LTAF Sequcnce Boundaries Identification and Well Seismogram</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>LTAF Sequcnce Boundaries Identification and Well Seismogram</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">All strata were onlap onto granite basement (Fig.3). It was not easy to predict the distribution, for the strata varied with different locations, especially for those of small sand units. These 30 sand units were in the resolution of single sand unit within LTAF and in thin thickness with the range of 9.8 ft to 30.7ft.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Well and Seismic Correlation Sections of LTAF</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well and Seismic Correlation Sections of LTAF</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="3" pdf-page="5" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">This kind of division can increasingly determine the extent and characteristics of the reservoir intervals. While 15 cycles and 30 sub-divided sand units can be correlated between wells under the control of segment divisions by using cycle identifications of sequence stratigraphy. Strata onalp can be observed and outlined in well sections with the help of same well seismic corss-well section (Fig.3). After the studies of segment division and detailed well-seismic tie of I well, three new interpretated segment horisons, M, L, Simpang, have been lowered to several reflectors in seismic sections resulting in new gas micro-structure findings and new gas trap for lower LTAF (Fig.4). Gas sand units in the lower part of LTAF have been found for the first time that is kind of rolling developing potential.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Five Segment Horizon Definition and New Changes</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Five Segment Horizon Definition and New Changes</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-4a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_4a.tif" id="ImgLink-4a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-4b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_4b.tif" id="ImgLink-4b" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-4c">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_4c.tif" id="ImgLink-4c" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">For the lithogy-structure controlled reservoir, structure and faults are the key factors for the geological components (Ouenes et al., 2010). N field is also this case. By the way mentioned above, all the structures of five segments have been checked, including basement and those of L segment thought as no hydrocarbon. Whole N field structure was a normal-fault controlled anticline confined by two reverse boundary faults (Fig.5). Structures of Simpang, L, M were similar in a succession pattern that were gradually onlap onto the granite basement with U covering at the top. Onlap boundaries were carefully studied according to well logs, core description and seismic reflector response. Basement area grew less from simpang to L and then to M. This shows the complex deposition process during reservoir formation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Fault Block Divion in U Structure Map and Structure Comtraston Maps of L</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fault Block Divion in U Structure Map and Structure Comtraston Maps of L</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Attributes were analysied including tuning frequency, sum of negative amplitude, sum of positive amplitude, min amplitude and peak amplitude etc. Then the best-fit attribute that was in highest correlation coefficient was choosen to represent the trend of reservoir property distribution of wells and in-between wells, including sandstone thickness and porosity. After testing, cumulative negative amplitude attribute constrained by CoKriging algorithm was adopted to predict net sand thickness. The property grid was computed by using Cokriging algorithm and sand thickness was predicted by spatial distribution of reservoir property and the best seismic attribute through the variation functions in each sand units. Finally, constraint by trend of the most sensitive seismic attributes, impedance inversion was run by using geostatics inversion to get the distribution of reservoir properties (Fig.6).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Impedance Inversion Section and Derived Sandstone Map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Impedance Inversion Section and Derived Sandstone Map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">These parameters in LTAF of N field were based on common methods assisted by the sidewall core analysis, DST and production data. In order to identify the fluid types of those layers lack of well test data, DST, log values, petrophysical parameters such as water saturation etc. can be combined together to identify oil, gas and water due to different log sigatures for the fluids in the reservoirs. Core/DST sample points with correspondent log values can be used to determine the fluid type. The porosity (Por) vs shale content (Vsh), resistivity/porosity vs water saturation (Sw), porosity vs density and porosity vs water saturation can be cross-plotted to get the fluid cutoffs according to actual measured data. Oil layer (green), gas layer (red) and water layer (blue) in non core wells can be recognised (Fig.7)</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Fluid Cutoff Crossplots and Fluid Identification</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fluid Cutoff Crossplots and Fluid Identification</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="8" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">In N field, the compartments showed more complicated in both areal direction and vertical directions. There were seven compartments in area direction named compartments of I, II, III, IV, V, VI, VII. Both compartment II and compartment Ⅳ were subdivided into two sub-compartments, which were more complicated system. Taking Vcompartment as an example (Fig.8). According to DST data, log interpretation result and production data in addition to pressure data, there was a lowest known gas contact (LKG) in N, P and Z well. There was a highest known oil contact (HKO) in X well, and there was a lowest known oil contact (LKO) in M and N well. The highest known water contact (HKW) was found in X, M and Z well. So the GOC and OWC can be deferred.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Fluid Section in Compartment V</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Fluid Section in Compartment V</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="9" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Beside these studies, in order to resolve productivity deficiency of new wells, more detailed study on existing producers and secondary log interpretations have been engaged to find more potential for development. Results have found that there were still 72 sand units with total thickness of 742 ft from 15 old wells of new proposed potential candidates that can be perforated to produce gas. They were with average thickness of 15ft and average porosity of 22.3%. Thereupon carefully quantitative log and geological analysis, the sandstone units that did not produce were identified as “the potential” (Fig.9). All the study built the basis to do volume calculation in stochastic model.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Potential Candidate Example</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Potential Candidate Example</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="10" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">The UTAF that contained mainly shales and clays interbedded with thin sandstones was a gas reservoir with poor to moderate porosity and moderate permeability (Fig.10). It developed underwater distributary channel, interchannel, mouth bar, mud flat microfacies. The mudstone added as upwards. Clay changing from light brown to gray or dark brown appeared little limy sedimentary. The UTAF was divided into seven layers from UTAF, UT1, UT2, UT3, UT4, UT5, UT6 and UT7 according flooding surfaces. The structures of UTAF were faulted anticlines with similar structure succession as LTAF. Gas potential was mainly concentrated in UT1, UT2, UT3, UT4 layers.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118186060MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118186060MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>UTAF Property and Gas-water System in Well Section</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>UTAF Property and Gas-water System in Well Section</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>