<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118186387MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-26T15:26:22Z">
<doi>10.2118/186387-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/186387-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docTableList>
<docTable pdf-page="4" table-order="1" data-type-order="3">
<table-wrap id="102118186387MS-tblwrp-1" content-type="structured">
<anchoringText id="Ancr1">Core samples were available for all of the aforementioned three plays for this study, as summarized in Table 1. It can be observed that the reservoir rocks were well consolidated, therefore justifying the use of Willson et al. (2002) approach. If the rocks had been weakly consolidated or unconsolidated, other analyses might have been required.</anchoringText>
<label>Table 1</label>
<caption>Description of available cores for geomechanics testing</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Table</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Description of available cores for geomechanics testing</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
<table id="102118186387MS-Tbl_SPi-1" frame="hsides">
<thead>
<tr>
<th valign="top" align="center">Reservoir</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Description</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Average Porosity (%)</th>
<th valign="top" align="center">Typical UCS (psi)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Upper Miocene post-rift turbidite 1</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sandstone, very fine grains, well sorted, moderate to very friable, sub angular, consolidated, predominantly lightly cemented with silicic cement, very good visual porosity</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">24</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">2500-3000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Upper Miocene post-rift turbidite 2</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sandstone, very fine to medium grains, predominantly fine grains, moderately to well sorted, moderately hard to hard, sub-angular to sub-round, moderately spherical, moderately grain contacted, consolidated with argillaceous and poor calcite cement, good to very good visual porosity</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">26</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">2500-3000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Middle Miocene syn-rift turbidite</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Sandstone, very fine to medium grains, commonly fine grains, poorly sorted, commonly moderately hard to hard, occasionally very hard, angular to sub-rounded, commonly poor spherical, consolidated with silicic cement, occasionally consolidated with argillaceous or calcite cement, poor to fair visual porosity, occasional mud clast</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">15</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">7000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td valign="top" align="center">Lower Miocene shallow marine / deltaic</td>
<td valign="top" align="left">Silty sandstone, very fine to fine grains, commonly very fine grains, well sorted, predominantly sub- angular to angular, occasionally sub-rounded, consolidated with calcareous cement, occasionally argillaceous cement, poor to fair visual porosity, thin mud lamination, clast, organic material, sand lens, discontinous thin sand beds</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">15</td>
<td valign="top" align="center">5000</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</table-wrap>
<appendix />
</docTable>
</docTableList>
</docTables>