<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118181721MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-20T16:28:19Z">
<doi>10.2118/181721-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/181721-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">Over 13,000 active oil and gas wells and more than 740 million bbl of oil have been produced from conventional vertical wells in Utah's Uinta Basin (Fig. 1). Located within the basin, the Monument Butte area is among the top 100 oil fields in the United States. Operators with a strong presence in the Monument Butte area are also pursuing ideal target zone(s) for horizontal wells by evaluating various sections of the reservoirs and utilizing the availability of technological advances made in recent years in horizontal drilling. Determining the reservoir water source zones to curb water disposal costs and ascertaining the productivity of different segments of a well to evaluate its profitability are more important than ever considering the current economic situation.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Uinta Basin, Utah</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Uinta Basin, Utah</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">The central basin is the intersection of two main plays: the Wasatch (Altamont-Bluebell field) and the Green River (Monument Butte) (Fig. 2). Recently released for development, the majority of the central basin is undeveloped. The Uinta Basin has grown from approximately 20,000 bbl/d in 2002 to more than 80,000 bbl/d by year-end 2015. The development of the central basin will continue this growth. Active oil and gas development in the Uinta Basin dates from the 1950s and during that time over 30,000 wells have been drilled in the basin. The released tribal lands give operators access to the central basin. Operators in the area believe that increased recovery potential is achievable through horizontal drilling and multi-stage fracture stimulation. The majority of new wells in the basin are vertical or slightly deviated wells, which encounter stacked pay within a 1,000 to 3,000 ft gross interval (Fig. 3). Vertical development of 160 acre spacing before 2012 has substantially decreased; however, there is still great potential for further down spacing through horizontal drilling targets in several zones such as the Black Shale, Uteland Butte and Upper Wasatch (Internal Presentation).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Uinta Basin's Oil and Gas Fields</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Uinta Basin's Oil and Gas Fields</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">The central basin is the intersection of two main plays: the Wasatch (Altamont-Bluebell field) and the Green River (Monument Butte) (Fig. 2). Recently released for development, the majority of the central basin is undeveloped. The Uinta Basin has grown from approximately 20,000 bbl/d in 2002 to more than 80,000 bbl/d by year-end 2015. The development of the central basin will continue this growth. Active oil and gas development in the Uinta Basin dates from the 1950s and during that time over 30,000 wells have been drilled in the basin. The released tribal lands give operators access to the central basin. Operators in the area believe that increased recovery potential is achievable through horizontal drilling and multi-stage fracture stimulation. The majority of new wells in the basin are vertical or slightly deviated wells, which encounter stacked pay within a 1,000 to 3,000 ft gross interval (Fig. 3). Vertical development of 160 acre spacing before 2012 has substantially decreased; however, there is still great potential for further down spacing through horizontal drilling targets in several zones such as the Black Shale, Uteland Butte and Upper Wasatch (Internal Presentation).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Typical Vertical Well Sketch in the Basin</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Typical Vertical Well Sketch in the Basin</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr21">In order to develop the northern-most section of the Monument Butte area, a set of new wells was drilled to infill the area surrounded by a few offsets. The main objective of pumping fluid tracers was to determine which zones were productive and which zones could be bypassed on the completion. The red square in Fig. 4 denotes the general area where this section is located within the field.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Study's Sections</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Study's Sections</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr22">The Uinta Basin is located in northeastern Utah approximately 200 miles east of Salt Lake City. It is bounded to the north by the Uinta Mountains, where the regional dip steepens, and to the south by the Wasatch Plateau, where dips remain very shallow for many miles. In addition, the Douglas Creek Arch separates Uinta Basin from the Piceance Basin (Fig. 5). Throughout the Uinta Basin, commercial oil and gas production occurs predominantly from the Wasatch and Green River formations. The Wasatch produces primarily from highly discontinuous sandstone reservoirs in the north, specifically the Central Basin that borders the Altamont-Bluebell field, whereas, the Green River produces mainly from discontinuous sandstones, shales and carbonates in the south, principally the Randlett and Monument Butte fields.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Uinta Basin Map</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Uinta Basin Map</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr23">The lithology and depositional environment of the Wasatch and Green River formations are extremely complicated and thus beyond the scope of this paper (Fig. 6). However, in general terms, the Uinta Basin was formed between the late Cretaceous Period and the Eocene Epoch creating three petroleum systems. First, the Green River oil system, characterized by a high paraffin content (15%) and a black wax crude with a 32-degree API gravity; second, the over-pressured Wasatch oil system, characterized by a high paraffin content as well and a yellow wax crude with a 42-degree API gravity; and finally the Mesa Verde gas system. The primary production for both oil-bearing formations involves highly oil-saturated sandstones with significant contributions from shales and carbonates. Varying water saturations and lithologies also contribute to the complexity of the Green River and Wasatch formations (Internal Presentation).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Uinta Basin Stratigraphic Complex</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Uinta Basin Stratigraphic Complex</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="19" figure-order="7" data-type-order="18">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr24">The only other substantial contributor was the Green 3 at 15.9%, but that is significantly less than the Wasatch intervals’ 53.3%. Fig. 7 illustrates the percent deviation from an equitable CFT contribution for each stage, while Table 12 shows the normalized concentrations for all of the water samples analyzed.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well F's Percent Deviation from an Equitable CFT Contribution</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well F's Percent Deviation from an Equitable CFT Contribution</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="26" figure-order="8" data-type-order="25">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr25">Concentrations of the water tracers recovered again point to the Wasatch intervals, stimulated in frac stages 1–3, contributing a higher than normal percentage of the total tracer ppb recovered from all stages during the sampling period. The only other substantial contributor was the Green 3 at 15.9%, but that is significantly less than the Wasatch intervals’ 53.3%. Fig. 7 illustrates the percent deviation from an equitable CFT contribution for each stage, while Table 12 shows the normalized concentrations for all of the water samples analyzed.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181721MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181721MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>WELL H's Percent Deviation from an Equitable OFT Contribution</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>WELL H's Percent Deviation from an Equitable OFT Contribution</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>