<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118181984MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-22T15:02:28Z">
<doi>10.2118/181984-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/181984-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="1" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">As mentioned above, three wells (Fig. 1) on Pad 1 were selected to demonstrate the integrated HPT-SNL toolstring capabilities in constructing an inflow profile in order to identify high gas production zones and locate water encroachment sources. The horizontal wellbore section was drilled in Unit PK1-3 oil rim. The gas-saturated part of the reservoir is screened with a cemented casing, while in the oil-saturated part is cased with an uncemented liner.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Locations of surveyed wells.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Locations of surveyed wells.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="2" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">As the wells had been shut-in for a long time before the survey, it was decided it would be logistically more convenient if the survey began with an SHPT measurement and then was continued with an FHPT measurement. The survey procedure was similar for all wells under study. The survey schematic is shown in Fig.2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>HPT-SNL survey schematic</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>HPT-SNL survey schematic</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="3" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Horizontal producer No. 1 was drilled in November 2012. The well trajectory is shown in Fig. 3. The horizontal section is cased with an uncemented liner. After completion, the well flowed at an average rate of 200 m3/day with an average water cut of 5-10%.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Well 1 trajectory</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well 1 trajectory</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="4" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">The measured integrated survey data are given in Fig. 4. The FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column contains the inflow profile based on temperature simulations. The input parameters are: well design and completion schematic (fluid type and annular fluid levels), initial reservoir pressure, porosity and permeability (absolute and relative) for each flow zone, saturation (gas, oil, water), hydrodynamic imperfections in the bottomhole zone for each flow zone (skin factor), drainage radius, reservoir pressure at the drainage radius boundary, PVT model including thermodynamic fluid properties, and flowing wellbore pressure dynamics.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>The integrated HPT-SNL- KarSar survey in Well No. 1. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>The integrated HPT-SNL- KarSar survey in Well No. 1. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="5" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">The gas-saturated part of the reservoir was exposed with a subhorizontal wellbore section and cased off with a cemented production casing. The first horizontal wellbore section dropping down in relation to TVDSS along the hole was drilled within PK1-3 oil rim (well trajectory is highlighted in grey in Fig. 5). However, due to the larger part of the wellbore passing through the low-production zones of a horizontally stratified reservoir, it was decided to sidetrack the well (well trajectory is highlighted in black in Fig. 5) without shutting off the old wellbore.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Well 2 trajectory</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well 2 trajectory</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="6" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">As the well had remained shut in for a long time, the static survey was carried out first. Similar to the previous case, a stable operating regime during the survey - under compression - was not achieved in this well and the maximum differential pressure was only 1.2 atm. Nevertheless, the SNL successfully identified the flow zones, and a combined SNL and HPT data analysis with subsequent temperature simulations and multi-phase data helped to estimate the inflow profile (FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column in Fig. 6).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>The integrated HPT-SNL-KarSar survey in Well 2. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>The integrated HPT-SNL-KarSar survey in Well 2. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="7" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Horizontal producer No. 3 was drilled in August 2014 for PK1-3 target. The well path is shown in Fig. 7. The formations in the gas cap were cased off with a cemented production casing. An uncemented slotted liner was run in the horizontal wellbore section passing through the oil rim of a highly heterogeneous formation. At the time of the survey the total flow rate was 148 m3/day and oil flow rate was 68 t/day at 51% water cut.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Well 3 trajectory</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well 3 trajectory</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="8" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Similar to the previous case, the coherent parasitic noise in the frequency range of 3.3 – 5.4 kHz detected in different regimes in the interval 1035.0 – 2093.0 m was generated due to the KarSar tool operation. This noise was filtered out using the wavelet thresholding processing (see SND SHUT-IN, FLOWING columns in Fig. 8), leaving only the useful noise associated with fluid flows along the reservoir.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>The integrated HPT-SNL-Cap recorded in Well 3. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>The integrated HPT-SNL-Cap recorded in Well 3. The inflow profile based on temperature simulations is shown in the FORMATION INFLOW PROFILE column.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="13" figure-order="9" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">All three wells discussed in this paper are spaced close to each other. It is therefore possible to trace some common features related to the wellbore inflow pattern. A cross-correlation section showing all three logged wells, complete with their inflow profiles, is shown in Fig. 9. It can be seen that gas inflow from the gas cap regularly occurred in all three wells.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118181984MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118181984MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Cross-correlation section with inflow profiles for the logged wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Cross-correlation section with inflow profiles for the logged wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>