<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190159MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-30T10:06:14Z">
<doi>10.2118/190159-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190159-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="3" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">Figure 1 (a) shows the rheological profiles of untriggered and triggered polymer and demonstrates that, in its untriggered form, the inverted polymer in SSW has water-like viscosity. In comparison, the triggered polymer solution has a viscosity commensurate with an HPAM polymer of equivalent molecular weight and concentration. It can also be seen that the untriggered polymer acts a Newtonian fluid – that is, it is unaffected by shear. Once triggered, the polymer backbone is extended and indistinguishable from HPAM and therefore demonstrates the same non-Newtonian shear-thinning behaviour.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>(a) Viscosity vs. shear rate for the untriggered and triggered 1,000 mg/l polymer solutions measured at 25°C (b) The viscosity–concentration relationship of polymer in synthetic sea water at 25°C and a shear-rate of 10 s<sup>-1</sup>
</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>(a) Viscosity vs. shear rate for the untriggered and triggered 1,000 mg/l polymer solutions measured at 25°C (b) The viscosity–concentration relationship of polymer in synthetic sea water at 25°C and a shear-rate of 10 s<sup>-1</sup>
</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-1a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_1a.tif" id="ImgLink-1a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity vs. shear rate for the untriggered and triggered 1,000 mg/l polymer solutions measured at 25°C</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-1b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_1b.tif" id="ImgLink-1b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>The viscosity–concentration relationship of polymer in synthetic sea water at 25°C and a shear-rate of 10 s<sup>-1</sup></caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="2" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">A map of the area of the field in which the trial was conducted is shown in Figure 2. The chosen area for the trial was near the crest of the field with few active wells in the vicinity. The nearest injector and producer were to the northwest of the field trial wells. There were no active wells to the south and the nearest active well to the east was more than 3,000 ft away. Production from the interval was steady over the period of the trial with minimal changes in injection volumes or average reservoir pressure.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Map of the field trial well locations showing the net reservoir thickness and the two nearest offset wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Map of the field trial well locations showing the net reservoir thickness and the two nearest offset wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="3" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">Step-rate tests were run regularly during the trial to provide an estimate of the fracture pressure of the formation and to calibrate injectivity in models. The injection rate, brine density and temperature were recorded continuously, while production rates were measured by regular well tests. The rate of oil production was estimated by visual inspection of the twice-daily wellhead samples. A timeline of the key surveillance activities is shown in Figure 3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Timeline of field trial surveillance activities</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Timeline of field trial surveillance activities</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="4" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">The pressure history from the downhole gauge in the injection well is shown alongside the injection rate in Figure 4. Periods of water injection are shown in blue and polymer injection in orange. Water was first injected for 43 days, in order to create a cooled zone around the well, as would occur in real field applications, and to provide baseline performance. Polymer was then injected for 43 days and was followed by 24 days of chase water injection. The final stage of the test was to examine the impact of shutting in the well for a significant period during polymer injection. For this purpose, polymer injection was restored for 3 days, followed by a shut-in period of 3 days, and then chase water.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Downhole injection gauge pressure (blue: periods of water injection; orange: periods of polymer injection); Injection and Production rates on upper graph (grey: surface measurements of injection rate; green line: allocated production rate; green dots: spot measurements of production rate)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Downhole injection gauge pressure (blue: periods of water injection; orange: periods of polymer injection); Injection and Production rates on upper graph (grey: surface measurements of injection rate; green line: allocated production rate; green dots: spot measurements of production rate)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="5" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">The bottom-hole pressure recorded during the PFO tests is shown in Figure 5. The increase of reservoir pressure around the well, from 1150 psi during waterflood to approximately 1800 psi by the end of polymer injection, is apparent.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Injection well bottom-hole pressure during PFO tests</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Injection well bottom-hole pressure during PFO tests</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="6" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">Information on the rising reservoir pressure from the PFOs has been combined with the injection pressure data to produce the Hall plot of injectivity shown in Figure 6. The rapid drop in injection pressure described above is clearly seen by the change in gradient at the start of polymer injection.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Hall plot of the injector during the field trial period</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Hall plot of the injector during the field trial period</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="7" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Most of the injection, including all the polymer injection, is believed to have occurred below fracture pressure, as was desired, in order to avoid complicating the interpretation. A step-rate test during waterflood showed that fracture pressure was 3070 psi with initial reservoir pressure of 1150 psi, and it rose during polymer injection in response to the significant increase in reservoir pressure (Figure 7). A repeat test performed during the polymer flood showed a fracture pressure of 3170 psi.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Step-rate test data during the trial</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Step-rate test data during the trial</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="8" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">Figure 8 shows the salinity and tracer concentration measurements of water samples collected from the production wellhead. Breakthrough time for the injected water was 4 days, and the rapid decrease in produced water salinity is a strong indication that a large proportion of the injected fluid was passing through a single layer in the reservoir. This is further supported by the quality of the match to salinity data from single-layer simulation models.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Produced water tracer concentration</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Produced water tracer concentration</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="9" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">The concentration of polymer in the effluent is shown in Figure 9. Polymer was detected in surface samples at the producer 9 days after polymer injected started. In comparison, Polymer Tracer 1, injected on the first day of polymer injection, reached the producer in 3 days. Polymer concentration increased steadily post-breakthrough before decreasing when the production rate was increased to approximately 500 bbl/d. A return of the production rate to 150 bbl/d led to an increase in polymer concentration to the maximum 1000 mg/l level expected based on the injection concentration. This was achieved approximately 24 days after the start of polymer injection.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Produced water polymer concentration shown with injection rate and allocated production rate</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Produced water polymer concentration shown with injection rate and allocated production rate</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="10" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">The formation and properties of the viscous polymer bank are shown most clearly from the evolution of the pressure derivative during the PFO sequence. Figure 10 shows the change in derivative from the end of the waterflood (PFO2b) to the end of the polymer flood (PFO3), the end of chase water injection (PFO4), and the end of the trial (PFO5). Note that additional PFOs 1 and 2a were performed during the waterflood. PFO1 indicated the presence of gas, due to reservoir depletion below bubble point. The system compressibility</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Pressure derivative curves for water, polymer and chase water injection</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pressure derivative curves for water, polymer and chase water injection</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="11" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr19">The likely presence of a small gas saturation resulting from reservoir depletion will reduce krw. The global skin factor of +25 will include an element due to near-well cooling, but implies a mechanical skin factor of about+15, which demonstrates a high level of damage from solids and/or fluids during drilling and completion. This is likely as the reservoir is under-pressured. The derivative obtained from reservoir simulation of the waterflood PFO2b, shown in Figure 11, is consistent with the observed data.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Type curves and reservoir simulator output of waterflood and polymer PFO tests</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Type curves and reservoir simulator output of waterflood and polymer PFO tests</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="18" figure-order="12" data-type-order="19">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr20">To derive the pre-exponential factor and activation energies we have used viscosity-trends with time and temperature from laboratory bottle-tests. The rate response appears to be different at different temperatures, which has required us to model the reaction with a temperature-dependent activation energy where each temperature range uses the Arrhenius dependence of the rate constant on temperature. The match to viscosity trends with time is shown in Figure 12 (a) and is acceptable in the range of temperatures present in the model. Note that at 50°C the kinetic model is slower than measured data, whilst at 70°C the viscosification is quicker. However, at the temperatures present in the model the match is acceptable.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>(a) Viscosity trends in time at 50°C and 70°C compared with those in bottle tests; (b) Viscosity against concentration model compared with laboratory data (shear rate 10 s<sup>-1</sup>)</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>(a) Viscosity trends in time at 50°C and 70°C compared with those in bottle tests; (b) Viscosity against concentration model compared with laboratory data (shear rate 10 s<sup>-1</sup>)</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-12a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_12a.tif" id="ImgLink-12a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(a)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity trends in time at 50°C and 70°C compared with those in bottle tests;</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-12b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_12b.tif" id="ImgLink-12b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(b)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Viscosity against concentration model compared with laboratory data (shear rate 10 s<sup>-1</sup>)</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="18" figure-order="13" data-type-order="20">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr21">Polymer retention has been represented in the model by a Langmuir-like irreversible adsorption isotherm. Whilst retention may be due to adsorption to solid surfaces or trapping within small pores, both mechanisms lead to a delay in propagation. The untriggered and triggered forms of the polymer are assigned two different adsorption levels, in recognition of the laboratory evidence suggesting the untriggered polymer has higher retention. The isotherms used are shown in Figure 13.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Langmuir-type adsorption isotherms used as inputs to the numerical simulation for the untriggered and triggered polymer</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Langmuir-type adsorption isotherms used as inputs to the numerical simulation for the untriggered and triggered polymer</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="19" figure-order="14" data-type-order="21">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr22">The basic rock properties and dispersivity in the model were tuned using the salinity of the effluent and concentrations of the waterflood tracer in wellhead samples during the waterflood phase of the trial. The match to the swept volume is accurate, and, as shown in Figure 14, the qualitative changes in salinity and tracer concentration in response to well control events are captured in the model. The skin of the injector and total compressibility were further guided by PTA. We found it was important to carefully tune the total compressibility in the model to provide an adequate match during periods when injection and/or production rates were changing. PFO2 at the end of the waterflood phase was also simulated using the reservoir model and a comparison with field data is shown in Figure 11.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Comparison between the reference model and measurements of salinity and tracer concentration in surface samples from the producer. The circles represent the field measured values. Concentration of injected tracer is measured as a fraction of the injected concentration.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison between the reference model and measurements of salinity and tracer concentration in surface samples from the producer. The circles represent the field measured values. Concentration of injected tracer is measured as a fraction of the injected concentration.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="20" figure-order="15" data-type-order="22">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr23">The match to polymer concentrations is shown in Figure 15. The breakthrough time is captured in the model; however, there is a poor match in the period between 67 and 71 days. An investigation of the model at these times shows that the cause of the low concentration is due to a coning-like effect described earlier in this paper, resulting in mixing in the production well and dilution of the produced concentrations.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>Comparison between reference model and measurements of salinity and polymer concentration in surface samples from the producer</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison between reference model and measurements of salinity and polymer concentration in surface samples from the producer</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="20" figure-order="16" data-type-order="23">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr24">Figure 16 shows concentration maps of triggered polymers during polymer production. This effect may be seen on the concentration map at day 75, when the produced concentration is only 700 mg/l, however, the bank of polymer has gone past the production well. The concentration of produced polymer at this time in the model (and in the field) was controlled by the physics of ‘coning’ rather than polymer propagation characteristics. This, in part, is the source of the discrepancy between the model and the field data. The extent of ‘coning’ is governed by the production rate.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>Measured concentrations of produced polymer during the trial and modelled concentrations of triggered polymer in the field showing a coning-like effect where low viscosity fluid is drawn towards the producer. The solid lines refer to the reference model, the dotted lines are model predictions where the production rate has been decreased to 50 bbl/d from 67-71 days. Saturation maps are from the reference model. The top left is the injection well.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>Measured concentrations of produced polymer during the trial and modelled concentrations of triggered polymer in the field showing a coning-like effect where low viscosity fluid is drawn towards the producer. The solid lines refer to the reference model, the dotted lines are model predictions where the production rate has been decreased to 50 bbl/d from 67-71 days. Saturation maps are from the reference model. The top left is the injection well.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="21" figure-order="17" data-type-order="24">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr25">The predicted and measured injection pressures and well rates are shown in Figure 17. During the waterflood phase injection pressure is modelled to within 10% of measured rates. The 3% gas saturation modelled as a high rock compressibility was required to match the decline in injection pressure seen from day 5 to 25. The mechanical skin required in the model was +15. Whilst this is lower than the global skin of +25 estimated from PTA, the contribution to skin from thermal cooling is modelled separately in these simulations.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Simulated gauge pressure (black) compared with measured pressure in the field, and the injection (grey) and production rates (green) used in the simulation model. Solid lines are simulation output, dots are field measurements.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Simulated gauge pressure (black) compared with measured pressure in the field, and the injection (grey) and production rates (green) used in the simulation model. Solid lines are simulation output, dots are field measurements.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="22" figure-order="18" data-type-order="25">
<link href="link-18" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-18" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr26">The modelled injection pressures were used to calculate derivatives to compare against the field data (Figure 11). To better understand the comparison Figure 18 the concentration of triggered polymer and the viscosity of water in the reservoir before PFO 3. This shows the size of the inner polymer bank is &#x003C; 50 ft, however the viscous bank is more complex, governed by the extent of cooling in the reservoir in addition to the presence of polymer. This suggests that to achieve a better match both the kinetics of triggering and the thermal properties of the reservoir and the over/under-burden need to be tuned carefully.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-18">
<label>Figure 18 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_18.tif" id="ImgLink-18" />
<caption>Triggered polymer concentration (left) and viscosity (right) maps from the reference model at 80.5 days (before PFO 3). This shows the limited extent of the bank of untriggered polymer and the coning of low viscosity water at the producer during the flood and as observed in the field.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>18</caption-order>
<caption-text>Triggered polymer concentration (left) and viscosity (right) maps from the reference model at 80.5 days (before PFO 3). This shows the limited extent of the bank of untriggered polymer and the coning of low viscosity water at the producer during the flood and as observed in the field.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-18a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_18a.tif" id="ImgLink-18a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(left)</caption-order>
<caption-text>Triggered polymer concentration</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-18b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_18b.tif" id="ImgLink-18b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>(right)</caption-order>
<caption-text>viscosity</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="23" figure-order="19" data-type-order="26">
<link href="link-19" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-19" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr27">The effect of polymer retention is shown in Figure 19 which shows models where the level of adsorption of untriggered polymer and triggered polymer were independently varied from 25 to 250 μg/g-rock. Two observations are clear:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-19">
<label>Figure 19 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_19.tif" id="ImgLink-19" />
<caption>The sensitivity of polymer concentration in the effluent to the modelled adsorption of untriggered and triggered polymers.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>19</caption-order>
<caption-text>The sensitivity of polymer concentration in the effluent to the modelled adsorption of untriggered and triggered polymers.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="25" figure-order="20" data-type-order="28">
<link href="link-20" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-20" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr28">The trial described in this paper was the shortest in duration and injected the smallest mass of polymer but it compares favourably with other trials given the thickness of the reservoir interval. The quantity of polymer injected, in mass per unit area, was greater than, or of the same order as, other trials. The number of pore volumes injected through a 10-m radius around the injector was similar to the Matzen trial and significantly greater than others (see Figure 20). Injectivity reduction is a particular concern during polymer trials. In other trials, there was evidence of declining injectivity over time, attributed to the shear-thickening behaviour of HPAM polymers in the high-shear near-wellbore region (Lotfollahi, et al. 2016). Despite the comparable injection quantity, no injectivity decline was seen with this polymer; and the polymer backbones were protected when passing through the high-shear region.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190159MS-Img_SPi-20">
<label>Figure 20 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190159MS_i_20.tif" id="ImgLink-20" />
<caption>Comparison of various published polymer field trials with respect to total mass of polymer injected and the pore volume at a radius of 10m from the injector</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>20</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of various published polymer field trials with respect to total mass of polymer injected and the pore volume at a radius of 10m from the injector</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>