<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118190437MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-27T13:06:22Z">
<doi>10.2118/190437-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/190437-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">The Lower Fars formation broadly consists of two sandstone units separated by a mid-shale unit. Intervening siltstone and shale units often divide the two sandstone units into four stratified reservoir units of Upper-A, Upper-B, Lower-A and Lower- B as shown in Figure 1. Each zone varies in pay thickness from about 10 to 30 feet. Upper-B Sand has been selected for testing in the pilot with the potential of development of Upper-A Sand at a later stage.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Generalized Reservoir Stratigraphy of Lower Fars Formation in South Ratqa Field</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Generalized Reservoir Stratigraphy of Lower Fars Formation in South Ratqa Field</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="3" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Some sort of neutron density crossovers (not very clear crossovers) could be identified in 4 wells in the pilot area that are attributed to presence of free gas. The wells showing the gas signature are CW1, CW3, CW4, and E34 as shown in Figure 2.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>Pilot Configuration</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pilot Configuration</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">In addition to varying perforation types, two wells (CW4 &amp; PI2) were also completed with a Stand Alone Screen (SAS) to evaluate the impact on sand production, well productivity, injectivity, and Artificial Lift pump performance under thermal condition. Figure 3 shows the well diagram for Well PI2 which has a SAS.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Well Diagram for Well PI2</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Well Diagram for Well PI2</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="6" figure-order="4" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">Due to small variation in initial reservoir pressure recorded in different wells (&#x003C;10 psi), presenting the interference results in terms of measured pressures would add another layer of complexity for interpretation of the results. The interference test results can be best presented by looking at pressure changes at each location as shown in Figure 4. Examining this Figure reveals a high degree of continuity and uniformity around CCW. The overall observations from this plot can be listed as follows:</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Differential Pressure in Nearby Wells Due to Injection in Well CCW</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Differential Pressure in Nearby Wells Due to Injection in Well CCW</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="5" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Figure 5 shows the average pressures of the two wells (UO1 &amp; UO2) in Upper-A Sand and that of the other two wells (LO1 &amp; LO2) in Upper-B Sand along with injection and production history of the pilot. Pressure measurements in Upper-A Sand and Upper-B sand in the 4 perforated observation wells, reveals that in Upper-A Sand pressure responds to the activities in the Upper-B Sand quite well. The consistency between the measurements in both wells during injection and production provide enough evidences for rapid pressure communication across the shale unit which is 3-4 ft thick in the area. Upper-B Sand pressure as expected responds to pilot in a faster manner as all the activities are in this layer.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Pressure Responses to Perforated Observation Wells to the Pilot Operations</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Pressure Responses to Perforated Observation Wells to the Pilot Operations</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="6" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Presenting the Hall analysis for all the wells on the same graph will provide valuable insight on reservoir performance. Figure 6 depicts the Hall plots for all wells (Excluding HWC) in the pilot. This Figure presents multiple curves with huge variation in their slopes. Generally, the wells with lowest injectivity fall above and those with highest injectivity fall below. From this plot one can identify the high injectivity wells (colored) and low injectivity wells (gray). The highest injectivity wells are either horizontal (HWF), having a gas demarcation on log (Well CW1) or amongst the wells with the highest reservoir thickness (CCW &amp; CW2). Similarly it is expected to locate the wells with thinnest pay thickness (E23, CW4 &amp; PI3) amongst the wells that fall above.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>SLSTP Hall Plots for Various Wells Highlighting the Best Injectors</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>SLSTP Hall Plots for Various Wells Highlighting the Best Injectors</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="9" figure-order="7" data-type-order="8">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Change in slope in Hall plot indicates either impairment (slope increase) or injectivity enhancement (slope decrease). In this example, most of the wells have a constant slope, indicative of no meaningful change in well injectivity. For some wells, however, there is a clear slope change. In some wells the injectivity enhances after early poor injectivity (Wells CW3 &amp; E23) while for others (Well CW4), clear injection impairment is seen midway through injection. Figure 7 shows what has been interpreted as steam quality impact on the injectivity of Well CW3 (&amp; PI2) and sandscreen effect on the injectivity of Well CW4.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>The Impact of Either Steam Quality or Sandscreen on Injectivity of Some Distinctive Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>The Impact of Either Steam Quality or Sandscreen on Injectivity of Some Distinctive Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="10" figure-order="8" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">PTA technique is then conducted for real CSS wells of the pilot. PI3 pressure fall off data presents the typical signature of a thermal under steam injection after steam injection has stopped. Figure 8 shows the semi log plot where pressure is dominated by the steam pressure in the swept zone. The early time flattening of pressure has a slope of 12 psi/cycle where swept zone pressure is around 305 psi. Swept zone temperature can be estimated from the steam table that would lead to proper calculation of steam viscosity in the swept zone.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Established Fall-Off Flow Regimes for Early and Late Time</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Established Fall-Off Flow Regimes for Early and Late Time</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-8a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_8a.tif" id="ImgLink-8a" />
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-8b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_8b.tif" id="ImgLink-8b" />
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="9" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">The estimated steam front from the fall off data interpretation is in agreement with what seismic suggests. Figure 9 shows the size of seismic anomaly at the time of baseline seismic and monitor for well CW1. The areal steam size measured by seismic is 742 meters which resulted in a radius of 15.3 m assuming a circular steam zone around the well. This is where the 4D seismic can add value in providing the actual measurement of the steam size. The detailed discussion of the seismic result is the subject of a publication elsewhere.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Observed Steam Size around Well CW1 from the AI Difference between Monitor and Base</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Observed Steam Size around Well CW1 from the AI Difference between Monitor and Base</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="10" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">Early oil production from the pilot has exceeded expectations despite the fact that the oil viscosity in the pilot area is substantially higher than other parts of the field. Figure 10 compares the relative oil production performance of various vertical wells and one of the horizontal wells under CSS. This well represents the first trial of CSS in horizontal wells in Kuwait. Due to some mechanical issues in the well bore of well HWC, no production data under CSS is available for this well so far.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Comparison of Oil Production from Vertical and Horizontal Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of Oil Production from Vertical and Horizontal Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="11" data-type-order="12">
<link href="link-11" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-11" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr12">High water retention after steam injection has been a well-established idiosyncrasy of the South Ratqa Field. Early production data from this pilot has shown that this characteristics is consistent across the field and is not location dependent. Figure 11 shows the favorable water cuts emerge 40-50 days after wells are put back on production. This can also be seen from a low overall total production water to steam ratio as seen in Figure 12 where the steam oil ratios (Based on 180-day production) have also been presented.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-11">
<label>Figure 11 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_11.tif" id="ImgLink-11" />
<caption>Favorable Water Cut Profiles of the Pilot Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>11</caption-order>
<caption-text>Favorable Water Cut Profiles of the Pilot Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="12" data-type-order="13">
<link href="link-12" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-12" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr13">High water retention after steam injection has been a well-established idiosyncrasy of the South Ratqa Field. Early production data from this pilot has shown that this characteristics is consistent across the field and is not location dependent. Figure 11 shows the favorable water cuts emerge 40-50 days after wells are put back on production. This can also be seen from a low overall total production water to steam ratio as seen in Figure 12 where the steam oil ratios (Based on 180-day production) have also been presented.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-12">
<label>Figure 12 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_12.tif" id="ImgLink-12" />
<caption>Steam Oil Ratio and Produced Water to Steam Ratio for the 180-day Production in the First Cycle</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>12</caption-order>
<caption-text>Steam Oil Ratio and Produced Water to Steam Ratio for the 180-day Production in the First Cycle</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="13" data-type-order="14">
<link href="link-13" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-13" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr14">H2S and sand production from various wells are closely monitored under the surveillance program. Figure 13 shows the concentration of hydrogen sulfide in the casing gas samples. The data is only available for the recent months. A huge disparity is observed in the concentrations from various wells. Although, majority of wells produce hydrogen sulfite at very low levels, few wells produce at alarming levels. PVT data does not show any significant amounts of sulfur in the fluid and as a result the high values of produced H2S are attributed to in situ generation of H2S due to thermal effect. High H2S producers are located in North-East corner of the pilot and this could be a local geochemistry phenomenon.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-13">
<label>Figure 13 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_13.tif" id="ImgLink-13" />
<caption>Concentrations of H2S in Casing Gas from Various Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>13</caption-order>
<caption-text>Concentrations of H2S in Casing Gas from Various Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="14" data-type-order="15">
<link href="link-14" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-14" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr15">Figure 14 shows the correlation coefficient for dependency of cumulative oil production to independent variables. The higher the absolute value of the coefficient, the higher the dependency of the independent variable to that parameter. For instance, the cumulative production is strongly and negatively correlated to the presence of the gas and lower reservoir pressures. Figure 15 shows the strong negative correlation between the cumulative oil production (shown in percentage of total production for each well) and the on-stream time of various wells. Figure 16 shows how all the gassy wells are producing below average.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-14">
<label>Figure 14 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_14.tif" id="ImgLink-14" />
<caption>Correlation Coefficients for Dependency of Cumulative Oil Production to Variable Parameters</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>14</caption-order>
<caption-text>Correlation Coefficients for Dependency of Cumulative Oil Production to Variable Parameters</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="15" data-type-order="16">
<link href="link-15" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-15" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr16">Figure 14 shows the correlation coefficient for dependency of cumulative oil production to independent variables. The higher the absolute value of the coefficient, the higher the dependency of the independent variable to that parameter. For instance, the cumulative production is strongly and negatively correlated to the presence of the gas and lower reservoir pressures. Figure 15 shows the strong negative correlation between the cumulative oil production (shown in percentage of total production for each well) and the on-stream time of various wells. Figure 16 shows how all the gassy wells are producing below average.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-15">
<label>Figure 15 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_15.tif" id="ImgLink-15" />
<caption>The Impact of Either Steam Quality or Sandscreen on Injectivity of Some Distinctive Wells</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>15</caption-order>
<caption-text>The Impact of Either Steam Quality or Sandscreen on Injectivity of Some Distinctive Wells</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="14" figure-order="16" data-type-order="17">
<link href="link-16" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-16" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr17">Figure 14 shows the correlation coefficient for dependency of cumulative oil production to independent variables. The higher the absolute value of the coefficient, the higher the dependency of the independent variable to that parameter. For instance, the cumulative production is strongly and negatively correlated to the presence of the gas and lower reservoir pressures. Figure 15 shows the strong negative correlation between the cumulative oil production (shown in percentage of total production for each well) and the on-stream time of various wells. Figure 16 shows how all the gassy wells are producing below average.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-16">
<label>Figure 16 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_16.tif" id="ImgLink-16" />
<caption>180-Day Relative Cumulative Production of Wells versus the Identified Gas Thickness in Well Logs</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>16</caption-order>
<caption-text>180-Day Relative Cumulative Production of Wells versus the Identified Gas Thickness in Well Logs</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="15" figure-order="17" data-type-order="18">
<link href="link-17" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-17" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr18">To understand the effect of injection volume on well performance, the wells that are highly affected by reservoir pressure (early and late wells) and gas, were removed from the analysis and a new correlation was made for the remaining 5 wells that come on stream roughly at the same time as shown in Figure 17. This Figure does not support a strong correlation between cumulative oil production and the injection volume and the final conclusion is that the slug volume at the levels injected in the pilot is not hugely influential and the production improves slightly as a result of lower injection slug.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118190437MS-Img_SPi-17">
<label>Figure 17 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118190437MS_i_17.tif" id="ImgLink-17" />
<caption>Weak Negative Correlation between Injection Slug Volume and Oil Production for the Specified Range</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>17</caption-order>
<caption-text>Weak Negative Correlation between Injection Slug Volume and Oil Production for the Specified Range</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>