<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docTables>
<docMetaData inputFile="102118187935MS.txt" extractionDate="2021-03-25T13:15:02Z">
<doi>10.2118/187935-MS</doi>
<pii>10.2118/187935-MS</pii>
<publisher>SPE_Society_of_Petroleum_Engineers</publisher>
</docMetaData>
<docFigureList>
<docFigure pdf-page="2" figure-order="1" data-type-order="1">
<link href="link-1" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-1" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr2">In this case study, a field located in Western Siberia (Figure 1) is being developed using horizontal wells (Karpov, 2016). The reservoir is the layered tight AC3 sandstone with average permeability approximately 0.1 to 1.0 mD, average net pay thickness of 5.4 m, and average depth of 1920 m. The critical risk influencing the field development is the presence of a thick (30 to 40 m) overlying aquifer AC2 located 50 to 70 meters above AC3.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-1">
<label>Figure 1 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_1.tif" id="ImgLink-1" />
<caption>Map of the field and offset well locations</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>1</caption-order>
<caption-text>Map of the field and offset well locations</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="4" figure-order="2" data-type-order="2">
<link href="link-2" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-2" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr3">Fracture geometry was also evaluated in the stimulated portion of a horizontal well B using microseismic monitoring with geophones placed in the vertical well. Microseismic recorded the hydraulic fractures breaking into the upper zones during some of the fracturing stages (2, 4 &amp; 5). These events were recorded not only in the AC2 but even in formations above AC2. Figure 2 shows the results of the microseismic monitoring where the fracturing stages are marked by different colours (points with lighter shade of the same color are events associated with mini-frac tests recorded during the respective stages). Well B was brought on production with a water cut of approximately 70%.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-2">
<label>Figure 2 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_2.tif" id="ImgLink-2" />
<caption>The results of microseismic monitoring of fracturing in horizontal well B</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>2</caption-order>
<caption-text>The results of microseismic monitoring of fracturing in horizontal well B</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="5" figure-order="3" data-type-order="3">
<link href="link-3" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-3" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr4">This higher stress contrast model was originally built using data from gamma ray, acoustic, and core analysis indicating a ratio of approximately 1.5 of the Young's Modulus of the shale to the Young's Modulus of the sandstone. Since the shale is having a higher Young's Modulus than the sands, it was assumed the shales would exhibit much higher stress than the sand in a similar order of magnitude. Under this assumed stress condition, the hydraulic fracture would have been contained within the reservoir. Figure 3 illustrates the comparison of the stress profile between the two models. As can be seen, the difference was huge and its impact on the hydraulic fracture design was extremely high.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-3">
<label>Figure 3 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_3.tif" id="ImgLink-3" />
<caption>Rock mechanical properties and the predicted minimum stress profile vs the traditional minimum stress profile for the area.</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>3</caption-order>
<caption-text>Rock mechanical properties and the predicted minimum stress profile vs the traditional minimum stress profile for the area.</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure composite="true" composite-count="2" pdf-page="6" figure-order="4" data-type-order="4">
<link href="link-4" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-4" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr5">The test can be conducted in both open holes, and in cased and perforated sections by isolating the testing interval with inflatable packers. The test provides direct measurements of formation breakdown pressure (Pb), fracture propagation and fracture reopening pressures; but most importantly it is a means for determining the fracture closure pressure (FCP), which is the best estimate of the minimum principal stress or the minimum horizontal stress (Shmin). To ensure reliable recording of this minimum stress, multiple repeat cycles are required to propagate and extend the fracture away from the influence of the near wellbore environment (Franquet, 2012; Warpinski, 1983). Fracture closure pressure is analyzed from the pressure decline after pumps-off and well shut-in. In permeable formations an injection fall-off test is performed where pressure declines quickly, allowing the fracture to close. However, in tight or non-permeable formations an injection flow-back test is necessary as the pressure decline may take considerable time and flow back is required to accelerate fracture closure rates (Figure 4).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-4">
<label>Figure 4 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_4.tif" id="ImgLink-4" />
<caption>Typical pump-in/decline microfrac test in permeable (left) and non-permeable (right) zones</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>4</caption-order>
<caption-text>Typical pump-in/decline microfrac test in permeable (left) and non-permeable (right) zones</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-4a">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_4a.tif" id="ImgLink-4a" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>left</caption-order>
<caption-text>permeable</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-4b">
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_4b.tif" id="ImgLink-4b" />
<figure-specific-caption>
<caption-order>right</caption-order>
<caption-text>non-permeable</caption-text>
</figure-specific-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="7" figure-order="5" data-type-order="5">
<link href="link-5" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-5" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr6">Assessment results suggested that the sand would have lower fracture initiation pressure compared to shale and therefore it should be easier to initiate the fractures in the producing sandstone layers. The pre-job assessment also showed a high level of confidence for the straddle packer to test and fracture the two target formations AC2 and AC3. The outcome of this pre-job assessment combined with the petrophysical evaluation led to the selection of eight primary testing intervals. In addition, back-up or secondary intervals were also selected in the event of failure to test any of the main selected testing points. Figure 5 illustrates the location of the main and back-up testing stations. Image logs were also analyzed to ensure no washouts, breakouts, or pre-existing fractures were present around the testing intervals.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-5">
<label>Figure 5 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_5.tif" id="ImgLink-5" />
<caption>Preliminary Petrophysical and fracture initiation pressure</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>5</caption-order>
<caption-text>Preliminary Petrophysical and fracture initiation pressure</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="6" data-type-order="6">
<link href="link-6" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-6" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr7">Unexpectedly high breakdown pressures were encountered in the sand bodies and no microfracturing could be achieved in some of the proposed stations. Nevertheless, direct measurements of formation breakdown pressure, fracture propagation and fracture reopening pressures were collected at alternative depth intervals in AC2 and AC3. The microfrac tests conducted in the AC3 sandstone were consistent with the stress magnitudes measured in the mini-frac tests done prior to the hydraulic fracturing treatments (Figure 3). Figure 6 and Figure 7 illustrate the results of the microfrac tests in the AC3 sand and in the shale adjacent to AC2 respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-6">
<label>Figure 6 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_6.tif" id="ImgLink-6" />
<caption>Microfrac test in Sand</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>6</caption-order>
<caption-text>Microfrac test in Sand</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="8" figure-order="7" data-type-order="7">
<link href="link-7" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-7" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr8">Unexpectedly high breakdown pressures were encountered in the sand bodies and no microfracturing could be achieved in some of the proposed stations. Nevertheless, direct measurements of formation breakdown pressure, fracture propagation and fracture reopening pressures were collected at alternative depth intervals in AC2 and AC3. The microfrac tests conducted in the AC3 sandstone were consistent with the stress magnitudes measured in the mini-frac tests done prior to the hydraulic fracturing treatments (Figure 3). Figure 6 and Figure 7 illustrate the results of the microfrac tests in the AC3 sand and in the shale adjacent to AC2 respectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-7">
<label>Figure 7 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_7.tif" id="ImgLink-7" />
<caption>Microfrac test in Shale</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>7</caption-order>
<caption-text>Microfrac test in Shale</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="10" figure-order="8" data-type-order="9">
<link href="link-8" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-8" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr9">The in-situ stress profile was revised and re-calibrated using the new data of fracture closure. For the first time, stress measurements were available for the zone between AC2 and the producing layer AC3 as well as for the lower AC3. Figure 8 shows the final calibrated stress model along with the rock mechanical properties derived from the full processing of the cross-dipole logging. An anisotropic rock model was used in the shale to estimate the elastic properties in the three directions (X, Y &amp; Z). This used the transverse shear anisotropy (DTSH) derived from the stoneley wave processing and the azimuthal anisotropy of DTSF (fast shear slowness) and DTSS (slow shear slowness).</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-8">
<label>Figure 8 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_8.tif" id="ImgLink-8" />
<caption>Re-calibrated in-situ stress profile for AC<sub>2</sub> and AC<sub>3</sub>
</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>8</caption-order>
<caption-text>Re-calibrated in-situ stress profile for AC<sub>2</sub> and AC<sub>3</sub>
</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="11" figure-order="9" data-type-order="10">
<link href="link-9" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-9" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr10">Figure 9 shows the comparison of the fracture geometry between the base and the current revised models using an averaged and simplified stress profile from the updated stress model. The base model was designed with a large amount of proppant that proved to be effective in the central part of the field with higher permeability but led to fracture migration into the AC2 layer in locations at the edges of the field. The new design involves containment of fracture height while maintaining the effective half-lengths at approximately the same values. As a result, the producing formation is developed more effectively.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-9">
<label>Figure 9 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_9.tif" id="ImgLink-9" />
<caption>Comparison of the base and the current hydraulic fracturing geometry by applying a stair-step model through averaging the stresses over specified depth intervals</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>9</caption-order>
<caption-text>Comparison of the base and the current hydraulic fracturing geometry by applying a stair-step model through averaging the stresses over specified depth intervals</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
<docFigure pdf-page="12" figure-order="10" data-type-order="11">
<link href="link-10" type="image" />
<appendix>
<linkTarget id="link-10" type="image">
<anchoringText id="Ancr11">The new parameters for hydraulic fracturing were tested on pilot wells with a 1000 m horizontal section, and they are currently on production (including Well C). To evaluate the economic effectiveness, the cumulative oil production from the "new design" and the "old design" in wells located in the same zone of the field was compared. The first five months of production showed that a change in the hydraulic fracturing approach led to substantial positive results. The average cumulative oil production in wells treated with the new fracture design has doubled compared to those wells treated with the old design (Figure 10). Another important feature is that the average water cut for Well C after hydraulic fracturing is between 5 to 10 %, which corresponds to the actual water cut expected from the producing layer.</anchoringText>
<image-wrap id="102118187935MS-Img_SPi-10">
<label>Figure 10 </label>
<imageLink type="mediaResource" href="102118187935MS_i_10.tif" id="ImgLink-10" />
<caption>Average oil production profile on wells completed with different fracturing designs</caption>
<formatted-caption>
<caption-label>Figure</caption-label>
<caption-order>10</caption-order>
<caption-text>Average oil production profile on wells completed with different fracturing designs</caption-text>
</formatted-caption>
</image-wrap>
</linkTarget>
</appendix>
</docFigure>
</docFigureList>
</docTables>